<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1992 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1992/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1992 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 06:49:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1992/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/12/12/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 06:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/12/12/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Psygnosis announced &amp;ldquo;Lemmings 2: The Tribes&amp;rdquo;. This took a slightly different twist on the original, with the goal being to re-unite twelve tribes of Lemmings, each tribe having a different theme complete with their own abilities.&#xA;An update to Sensi Software&amp;rsquo;s smash hit &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; had arrived and boasted a bevy of new and improved features, including red &amp;amp; yellow cards, the back pass rule and more competent goalies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/11/16/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 04:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/11/16/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Ocean had scored a #1 hit last Christmas with ”WWF Wrestlemania”, and hoped for a repeat in the form of ”WWF European Rampage”. While the earlier title had been panned by critics, the publisher were adamant this one would be better.&#xA;Commodore had announced the A4000 which, with a £1999 price tag, was very much targeted at the serious user. This fuelled rumours of a more affordable gaming machine and right as the mag went to press it looked like they had news&amp;hellip; though that would have to wait until next month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/9/26/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 08:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/9/26/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Team 17 were having another crack at the beat &amp;rsquo;em up genre with &amp;ldquo;Body Blows&amp;rdquo;, along with a top down racer, &amp;ldquo;Overdrive&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Rumours started to circulate that there was yet another Amiga model on the way: the A800. It would be a 32bit machine with 68030 CPU and would sit between the A600 and the A1500. Commodore&amp;rsquo;s Market Director Kelly Sumner was adamant there would be no machine called the A800, but did confirm there was another machine on the way&amp;hellip; I assume it was the A1200.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/8/7/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/8/7/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Sad news this month as one of the oldest software houses closed up shop. Palace Software had been going for almost a decade and had been behind some cracking games, including &amp;ldquo;Barbarian&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Sacred Armour of Antiriad&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Shoot&amp;rsquo;em Up Construction Kit&amp;rdquo;. The move came after months of legal wrangling, and the London office became Titus&amp;rsquo;s UK HQ. It was unclear what would happen with titles like &amp;ldquo;Hostile Breed&amp;rdquo; (unreleased, but was actually finished and reviewed two issues earlier), and &amp;ldquo;Super Barbarian&amp;rdquo; (also unreleased).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/7/30/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/7/30/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News The upcoming Christmas battle for number one looked to be between Konami’s “Batman Returns”, Acclaim’s “Alien 3” and Ocean’s latest movie license signing: “Lethal Weapon 3”.&#xA;Commodore continued their run of stupid business decision with the announcement that they were to stop selling the A500 Plus in favour of the new A600.&#xA;The ‘92 Barcelona Olympics would soon be starting and Ocean was preparing “Espagna 92” [sic] to take on US Gold’s “Megasports”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/21/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 09:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/21/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Virgin snapped up Sensi&amp;rsquo;s upcoming war game, &amp;ldquo;Cannon Fodder&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;TV show Gamesmaster was set to return for a second series and the production company were on the look out for young talent to take part.&#xA;DMI had signed a deal with German developer Prestige to bring their games to the UK. First up was &amp;ldquo;Doofus&amp;rdquo;, which would be followed by &amp;ldquo;Sword of Honour&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Catch&amp;rsquo;em&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Ocean were porting the Nintendo hit &amp;ldquo;Bart Versus the World&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/28/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 07:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/28/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News The transformation/infiltration/coup was complete and the team from ACE magazine had taken over reigns. The One for Amiga was now just &amp;ldquo;The One&amp;rdquo; as the ST mag had been rolled into ST Action. Notable changes included the scrapping of the developer profile section (which I personally liked) in favour of &amp;ldquo;special interviews&amp;rdquo; because the latter was &amp;ldquo;simply more interesting&amp;rdquo;, and more detailed, critical reviews (the previous team may have gone a little easy on games).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/25/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/25/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</guid>
      <description>News It seemed this would be the final issue for the whole editorial crew as they were being replaced by the folk from &amp;ldquo;ex-sister magazine ACE&amp;rdquo;. Such a drastic move must&amp;rsquo;ve been a bitter pill to swallow, but it did mean the return of Gary Whitta.&#xA;TV companies had begun to take an interest in video games, with Channel 4&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Gamesmaster&amp;rdquo; clocking in at around 3 million viewers during its first season.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/3/31/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 21:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/3/31/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</guid>
      <description>This month in&amp;hellip; The One for Amiga &amp;lsquo;92 News A new TV show catering for gamers had recently debuted and The One wanted to hear from readers about what they thought of it. Did Gamesmaster provide what gaming fans were looking for?&#xA;Electronic Arts were to publish &amp;ldquo;Castles&amp;rdquo;, a &amp;ldquo;SimCity&amp;rdquo; meets RPG game from Interplay.&#xA;A new book from Sigma sought to help players struggling to get to grips with adventure games.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
