<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 01:47:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review: The Bear Essentials (C64) by Pondsoft</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/14/review-the-bear-essentials-c64-by-pondsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 01:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/14/review-the-bear-essentials-c64-by-pondsoft/</guid>
      <description>When I first started to get into the resurgent C64 game scene after discovering the likes of Psytronik and Protovision, there was one game that everyone seemed to be talking about. Graham Axten’s platformer, which starred a rather charming bear, was looking great and was eagerly anticipated.
The game draws heavily from Manic Miner and Jet Set Willy, with a graphics style reminiscent of Creatures. The influence of Matthew Smith’s classic games is clear right from the start, where instead of housekeeper Maria turning Willy away to go tidy the house after a massive party, it’s Bear’s wife wanting enough apples to get the family through the winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: &#34;The Camp&#34; (C64) by Protovision</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/22/review-the-camp-c64-by-protovision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 08:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/22/review-the-camp-c64-by-protovision/</guid>
      <description>Way back in the mists of time (well, 1982) my parents took me and my sister out of school for a few months to embark on a trip around the UK, Europe and the US. For the European leg we jaunted about in a campervan, staying at campsites (and occasionally on roadsides) along the way. My memories of that time are sadly vague - my main recollection is the ridiculously rough toilet paper that one had to endure in the bathrooms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
