<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>August on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/august/</link>
    <description>Recent content in August on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 08:07:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/august/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2020/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 08:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2020/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>theone199408
News While Commodore was still without a buyer, word leaked that the company leading the pack was in fact Samsung who were looking to gain more of a foothold in the European market. It seemed everything was hanging on that deal.
Dominik Diamond was rumoured to be returning to &amp;ldquo;Gamesmaster&amp;rdquo;.
A report from Mintel showed that the UK games industry contracted by 4% last year. The market value in 1993 was £670 million compared to £700 million in 1992.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #12 August/September 1990</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this issue&amp;hellip;
The editor reflected on 2 years of Special Reserve: memberships had shot passed 25,000, with 5,500 of those also subscribing to Official Secrets (and, therefore, Confidential). While there had been the usual summer lull in game sales, they were expecting a bumper Xmas due to the Amiga&amp;rsquo;s popularity and had decided to also carry Atari Lynx, Sega Megadrive and CDTV titles.
The news included details of SSI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Secret of Silver Blades&amp;rdquo;, a bunch of upcoming flight sims, Alexey Pajitnov&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Tetris&amp;rdquo; followup &amp;ldquo;Welltris&amp;rdquo;, along with rumours of a new adventure from Level 9 (&amp;ldquo;Billy the Kid&amp;rdquo;), a game based on the book &amp;ldquo;Neuromancer&amp;rdquo;, and Sierra bringing &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Quest IV&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Colonel&amp;rsquo;s Bequest&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/8/28/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 08:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/8/28/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News A year after announcing they were leaving the Amiga behind, news arrived that Sierra On-Line were bringing &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Quest VI&amp;rdquo; to our beloved machine. The conversion was being handled by Charles Cecil&amp;rsquo;s Revolution which had created a hybrid of its &amp;ldquo;Virtual Theatre&amp;rdquo; system for the job to ensure the game felt at home on the system, rather than some shoddy PC port.
Krisalis spawned a new sub-label, Buzz, as home for its back catalogue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/8/7/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/8/7/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Sad news this month as one of the oldest software houses closed up shop. Palace Software had been going for almost a decade and had been behind some cracking games, including &amp;ldquo;Barbarian&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Sacred Armour of Antiriad&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Shoot&amp;rsquo;em Up Construction Kit&amp;rdquo;. The move came after months of legal wrangling, and the London office became Titus&amp;rsquo;s UK HQ. It was unclear what would happen with titles like &amp;ldquo;Hostile Breed&amp;rdquo; (unreleased, but was actually finished and reviewed two issues earlier), and &amp;ldquo;Super Barbarian&amp;rdquo; (also unreleased).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #6 August/September 1989</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 06:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s mag included:
A rather depressing Editorial which opened with &amp;ldquo;Boom-time for the computer games world is over, at least for the next few years.&amp;rdquo; The Japanese consoles were wiping the floor with computers - the 8bits were barely hanging on, the ST not far behind them. There looked to be some life left in the Amiga, but it was the IBM PC that stood the best chance of lasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/8/27/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 07:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/8/27/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn bid farewell as he strode off &amp;ldquo;on a secret mission&amp;rdquo;. Ciaran Brennan was to take the reins, with Julian Rignall as his assistant. Phillipa Irving&amp;rsquo;s war game section took a break as she was busy with exams. There was also a small change to the review format, with the &amp;ldquo;Value&amp;rdquo; rating being dropped.
Arnie&amp;rsquo;s latest film &amp;ldquo;Predator&amp;rdquo; had grossed $12 million at the box office in its first 3 days and Activision had signed the license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 08:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Atari unveiled their impressive handheld, the Lynx. Julian Rignall got to check it out and was gobsmacked: &amp;ldquo;Erm&amp;hellip; hmmm&amp;hellip; What can I say about the most exciting thing to happen to the games industry since the invention of the home console?&amp;rdquo;
Sinclair (aka Amstrad) were to launch a new bundle. The &amp;ldquo;Action Pack&amp;rdquo; would consist of a Spectrum +2 (£149) or +3 (£199), a Magnum light gun and 6 games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/8/20/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 06:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/8/20/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Liddon was leaving Zzap! to join Newsfield&amp;rsquo;s new software house, Thalamus, as Technical Executive. The company was headed by ex-Activision Press Officer Andrew Wright. The first game was due to be released in September on the C64 and Spectrum, with an Amstrad version following.
Gremlin were readying four new titles in time for Christmas: &amp;ldquo;Pentacle&amp;rdquo; (unreleased?), &amp;ldquo;Future Knight&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Bounder II&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Trailblazer&amp;rdquo;.
Arkana&amp;rsquo;s BBC game &amp;ldquo;Powerplay&amp;rdquo; was heading to the C64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/8/18/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 09:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/8/18/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw ex-Zzap!64 editor Julian Rignall and ex-Crash editor Steve Jarret join the C&amp;amp;VG writing staff.
With the Seoul olympic games about to start, Ocean were to release &amp;ldquo;Daley Thompson&amp;rsquo;s Olympic Challenge&amp;rdquo;. Official olympic sponsor Adidas were also sponsoring the game.
The first screenshot of Realtime Games&amp;rsquo; impressive 16bit &amp;ldquo;Carrier Command&amp;rdquo; Spectrum port appeared. The game was also to appear on the Amstrad and C64.
French software house Lankhor were working on a car racing game called &amp;ldquo;Vroom&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/8/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 05:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/8/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Perhaps the biggest news for Zzap! readers this month was that Julian Rignall had left Newsfield to take up freelancing (including for rival publisher EMAP). Gordon Houghton took over as editor, and there were quite a few changes (mainly cosmetic, but also an expanded news section for a start).
Mastertronic had a bunch of upcoming releases planned: &amp;ldquo;Rogue&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;World Darts&amp;rdquo; (may have become &amp;ldquo;180&amp;rdquo;), &amp;ldquo;Night Racer&amp;rdquo; and a re-release of Activision&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/8/25/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 08:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/8/25/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Catch 23&amp;rdquo; was a new 3D vector arcade adventure from Martech.
Epyx were continuing their &amp;ldquo;Games&amp;rdquo; series, this time focussing on events such as BMXing, skateboarding, surfing and flying disks (frisbees) in &amp;ldquo;California Games&amp;rdquo;.
Microprose were to release a new flight sim, &amp;ldquo;Project: Stealth Fighter&amp;rdquo; based on the top secret American stealth plane, and a more arcade-y combat game, &amp;ldquo;Airborne Ranger&amp;rdquo;.
Activision &amp;amp; System 3 got the game rights for Arnie&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Predator&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 03:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s nearly here&amp;rdquo;, declared C&amp;amp;VG about Mike Singleton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dark Sceptre&amp;rdquo;. The ambitious strategy/adventure (which was intended to have an optional Play By Mail service to allow players to compete with each other and Mike himself) had been in progress for a while and looked fantastic, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be until February 1988 that C&amp;amp;VG finally got to play it. From the review: &amp;ldquo;Was it worth the wait? We&amp;rsquo;ll pass on that&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (it received 8/10)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;91</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-91/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 01:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-91/</guid>
      <description>News The Bitmap Brothers announced their next game. It would be a top down arcade game with role playing elements where the player took control of one of six characters. It was very much a multiplayer game, and the AI had been designed so that they computer would fill in for any unused players. The graphical style was fresh and quite unique and the game would become known as one of the first examples of Steampunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/18/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 08:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/18/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Commodore had been reluctant to try to bring the Amiga&amp;rsquo;s price in line with the cheaper Atari ST, but this month the long rumoured £100 cut happened. The ST had stormed ahead in sales and it looked like it would be a tough battle for the Amiga, which Commodore had originally pitched as a business machine but was now accepting that it&amp;rsquo;s destiny would be games.
Sugar&amp;rsquo;s Amstrad entered into a partnership with Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s Sky satellite TV company which would see Amstrad producing and selling £199 dishes that would receive the four Sky channels once the service launched early in the following year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/13/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 08:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/13/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News US Gold had signed the licenses to a couple of Disney games, &amp;ldquo;Winnie the Pooh in the Hundred Acre Wood&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Donald Duck&amp;rsquo;s Playground&amp;rdquo;. Both were aimed at children, and both were written by Al Lowe (including the music).
Even though Ocean had been publishing Konami&amp;rsquo;s games in the US, they were strangely absent from UK shelves. This was about to change with &amp;ldquo;Hypersports&amp;rdquo;, followed by &amp;ldquo;Konami Tennis&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Yie Ar Kung-Fu&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Hyper Rally&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Golf&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Mikie&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Comic Bakery&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
