<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1995 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1995/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1995 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 07:38:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1995/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 07:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Andy Nuttall reckoned this issue was &amp;ldquo;more fruitsome and lovely than ever&amp;rdquo;.
A new contender for acquiring Commodore entered the ring: Escom, who had put in a bid for £5 million. The Commodore UK team downplayed this saying the bid was low and their own offer was still favourite. Meanwhile, Escom had bought out failed UK high street shop chain Rumbelows.
Retailer Silica were staying the course with their Amiga sales and launched a new CD32 bundle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/4/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/4/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News The One had had a bit of a facelift with the Contents page getting a re- design, along with various sections getting re-labelled.
The big news for the month was that Commodore UK had announced a new Amiga: the A1(M). The specs included &amp;ldquo;32 megabytes of RAM, a 1 gigabyte hard drive, 32-bit graphics card, 64-bit processor, 8x speed CD-ROM drive&amp;rdquo;. And of course it was The One&amp;rsquo;s April Fools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 06:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Despite some recent colossal flops at the box office (&amp;ldquo;Mario Brothers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Double Dragon&amp;rdquo;) it seemed the success of &amp;ldquo;Street Fighter&amp;rdquo; was enough for Hollywood to take another stab it with &amp;ldquo;Mortal Kombat&amp;rdquo;. The only &amp;ldquo;big names&amp;rdquo; attached to it were Christopher Lambert and Talisa Soto (a Bond girl in &amp;ldquo;Licence to Kill&amp;rdquo;). Unknown Paul Anderson was to direct. Elsewhere there were rumours of movies based on &amp;ldquo;Doom&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Myst&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/3/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/3/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Andy Nuttall officially took over the Editor role.
If you thought that the future of Commodore would be sorted out by this month, then you were sorely mistaken. The end did seem in sight (something that had been said for nearly a year), with only Commodore UK and US-based CEI remaining in the running. Meanwhile retailers were getting frustrated with the lack of new stock. With that said, apparently 82% of stores surveyed were keen to continue selling the machines (if they were provided some to sell&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/1/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/1/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Apparently the higher ups at EMAP were putting pressure on The One to cut back on pages and coverdisks, but Acting Editor Andy Nuttall and team stood firm, delivering a bumper issue. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t without its price, tho: &amp;ldquo;So, it&amp;rsquo;s taken us ages longer than normal to write, the coverdisks nearly killed us, and getting in the finished version of SWOS for review was a nightmare.&amp;rdquo;
The fate of Commodore remained up in the air, with little news to be had.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
