<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>October on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/october/</link>
    <description>Recent content in October on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 07:34:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/october/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/10/30/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 07:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/10/30/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Renegade&amp;rsquo;s release schedule was looking rather impressive with “Uridium 2” first up, followed soon after by “Turrican 3” and “Elfmania”. If that wasn’t enough, “Ruff ‘n’ Tumble”, “Sensible World of Soccer”, “Flight of the Amazon Queen” and “Z”) were all due by the end of the year. The last one - a real time strategy game from the Bitmap Brothers - was particularly interesting since it’d be years before it saw the light of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;91</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-91/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 01:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-91/</guid>
      <description>News The European Computer Entertainment show was on, then off, then back on.
Editor Ciaran Brennan pondered the dearth of releases for this time of year. Were publishers simply holding them for Christmas? Judging by the slew of previews and announcements it certainly looked like there was plenty on the way.
French developer Delphine were touting their new animation system, Cinematique. The first game to utilise it would be &amp;ldquo;Another World&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/15/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 08:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/15/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Konix Here At Last&amp;rdquo; proclaimed the headline leading off this issue. The much hyped Konix Multisystem was going to be available to buy this month at stores across the UK for around 200 quid. Not all of the eagerly anticipated peripherals would be on sale to start with - the hydraulic chair was &amp;ldquo;on the horizon&amp;rdquo; and expected to cost another 200 quid. Of course, sadly, none of this was to be&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Parallax&#34; Re-visited</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/parallax-re-visited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 07:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/parallax-re-visited/</guid>
      <description>Parallax Sensible Software/Ocean, 1986 This month in 1986 saw Sensible&amp;rsquo;s first big title reviewed in Zzap!64, scoring a very respectable 93% overall and receiving a Sizzler.
Over the past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to remember where I first saw &amp;ldquo;Parallax&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; I want to say it was at my friend Neil&amp;rsquo;s house, but did he even have a C64?? I know he had a Spectrum and later an Amiga&amp;hellip; Maybe it was someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 04:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News An article appeared in the Canberra Times in which a Mr Paul Gathercoal blathered on about the evils of games. Mr Gathercoal firmly believed games were corrupting the minds of children, driving them to lives of robberies, killing and masturbation. He claimed that playing &amp;ldquo;Franke Goes To Hollywood&amp;rdquo; would lead to &amp;ldquo;pill-popping&amp;rdquo;. What utter nonsense.
Gary Liddon had buggered off to Newsfield&amp;rsquo;s new software house, Thalamus, and a call went out to find someone to replace him at Zzap!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 07:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News Grand Slam were bringing the &amp;ldquo;Pacmania&amp;rdquo; coin-op to home computers (the Amiga, ST and Spectrum versions would be first, with C64 and Amstrad to follow next month). The software house was also working on a computer game based on board game &amp;ldquo;sensation&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Espionage&amp;rdquo;.
Software Horizons was new on the scene and would be publishing three 16bit games within the next month or so: &amp;ldquo;Veteran&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Luxor&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mafdet&amp;rdquo;.
Chris Crawford was updating his well received &amp;ldquo;Balance of Power&amp;rdquo; with some &amp;ldquo;new trouble zones of strategic importance&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/10/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 22:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/10/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Jim Synoski and Arnold Hendrick, designers of Microprose&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Project: Stealth Fighter&amp;rdquo;, were promoting the game ahead of its launch. While they admitted nothing official was known about the fighter, they felt that they had &amp;ldquo;a fair idea of what the capabilities of the plane must be&amp;rdquo;.
Incentive&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo; was shaping up well on the Speccy.
Electric Dreams had the rights to &amp;ldquo;Knightmare&amp;rdquo; - the game of the TV series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/this-month-in-zzap-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 00:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/this-month-in-zzap-87/</guid>
      <description>News The Audit Bureau of Circulations report showed that Zzap!&amp;rsquo;s readership had reached an impressive 77,483 in the first 6 months of the year.
Delta4 re-surfaced as Abstract Concepts and Fergus McNeil was busy working on a new fancy adventure system.
The next game from Stavros Fasoulas under the Thalamus label would be &amp;ldquo;Quedex&amp;rdquo;.
Features Part one of a series on the history of the shoot&amp;rsquo;em up.
Andrew Braybrook&amp;rsquo;s development diary of &amp;ldquo;Morpheus&amp;rdquo; drew to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 03:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Ariolasoft spun out two new software houses, 39 Steps to focus on adventure games and Reaktor arcade/action games. First up from 39 Steps would be &amp;ldquo;They Stole a Million&amp;rdquo; while Reaktor&amp;rsquo;s would be &amp;ldquo;Deactivators&amp;rdquo;.
Martial arts games were proving popular and Martech threw their hat in the ring with &amp;ldquo;Uchi-Mata&amp;rdquo;, a &amp;ldquo;more subtle&amp;rdquo; simulation based on Judo.
Beyond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Star Trek&amp;rdquo; was to land in time for Christmas and would feature more than 1000 stars and 256 subplots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 21:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Word on the street was that Atari was readying not one, but four new ST machines. The main one would be a &amp;ldquo;super ST&amp;rdquo; that would take on the Amiga, then there was a portable ST, a &amp;ldquo;Pocket PC&amp;rdquo; and an ST based console. Not only that, but the existing 520STFM would have its price slashed by £100 and get a software bundle valued at £440. How many of these would actually hit the selves?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 01:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News Celebrations at Crash towers as the latest circulation figures showed they had sold 101,483 copies a month on average between January and June. That number placed Crash ahead of all other computer mags.
This issue was the first to feature a cover drawn by someone other than Oliver Frey - Ian Craig was the illustrator responsible. It seemed that with the increasing array of magazines published by Newsfield, Frey had too much on his plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 23:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News After months of teasing, the new look for C&amp;amp;VG was here. It was quite a radical change and still looks pretty decent today.
The excellent &amp;ldquo;Bored of the Rings&amp;rdquo; was going to be re-launched by Silversoft and would feature new locations and graphics.
Beyond struck a deal with Mindscape that would see its games distributed in the the US. First up were &amp;ldquo;Lords of Midnight&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Shadowfire&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Quake Minus One&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
