<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amiga on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/amiga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amiga on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 07:38:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/amiga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 07:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Andy Nuttall reckoned this issue was &amp;ldquo;more fruitsome and lovely than ever&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;A new contender for acquiring Commodore entered the ring: Escom, who had put in a bid for £5 million. The Commodore UK team downplayed this saying the bid was low and their own offer was still favourite. Meanwhile, Escom had bought out failed UK high street shop chain Rumbelows.&#xA;Retailer Silica were staying the course with their Amiga sales and launched a new CD32 bundle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/4/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/4/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News The One had had a bit of a facelift with the Contents page getting a re- design, along with various sections getting re-labelled.&#xA;The big news for the month was that Commodore UK had announced a new Amiga: the A1(M). The specs included &amp;ldquo;32 megabytes of RAM, a 1 gigabyte hard drive, 32-bit graphics card, 64-bit processor, 8x speed CD-ROM drive&amp;rdquo;. And of course it was The One&amp;rsquo;s April Fools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 06:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Despite some recent colossal flops at the box office (&amp;ldquo;Mario Brothers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Double Dragon&amp;rdquo;) it seemed the success of &amp;ldquo;Street Fighter&amp;rdquo; was enough for Hollywood to take another stab it with &amp;ldquo;Mortal Kombat&amp;rdquo;. The only &amp;ldquo;big names&amp;rdquo; attached to it were Christopher Lambert and Talisa Soto (a Bond girl in &amp;ldquo;Licence to Kill&amp;rdquo;). Unknown Paul Anderson was to direct. Elsewhere there were rumours of movies based on &amp;ldquo;Doom&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Myst&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/3/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/3/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Andy Nuttall officially took over the Editor role.&#xA;If you thought that the future of Commodore would be sorted out by this month, then you were sorely mistaken. The end did seem in sight (something that had been said for nearly a year), with only Commodore UK and US-based CEI remaining in the running. Meanwhile retailers were getting frustrated with the lack of new stock. With that said, apparently 82% of stores surveyed were keen to continue selling the machines (if they were provided some to sell&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/1/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/1/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Apparently the higher ups at EMAP were putting pressure on The One to cut back on pages and coverdisks, but Acting Editor Andy Nuttall and team stood firm, delivering a bumper issue. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t without its price, tho: &amp;ldquo;So, it&amp;rsquo;s taken us ages longer than normal to write, the coverdisks nearly killed us, and getting in the finished version of SWOS for review was a nightmare.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The fate of Commodore remained up in the air, with little news to be had.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/12/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/12/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News While there was still no news on the fate of Commodore, the UK office was busy preparing for the World of Commodore show, which was to take place at the Wembley Exhibition Centre, December 9th through 11th. It was to be a “buying show” where the primary goal was for attendees to do a bit of shopping, but The One wondered if there’d be any Commodore kit left to purchase by then.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/11/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/11/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Simon Byron announced he was stepping down to work at a chip shop on the outskirts of Bognor: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that the life of a simple chippy is preferable to slogging my guts out on Britain&amp;rsquo;s least popular Amiga games magazine.&amp;rdquo; Andy Nuttall would be filling in as Acting Editor.&#xA;Frustrating times for Amiga journos and fans alike as there was still no news from Commodore on the future of the company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/9/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/9/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News After reporting that the saga of Commodore&amp;rsquo;s fate would be resolved &amp;ldquo;any day now&amp;rdquo; for the past few months, The One decided to quit guessing the timeline. In the latest twist, word arrived Commodore UK (lead by David Pleasance and Colin Proudfoot) were now the favourites with their proposal of a Management Buy Out, with Samsung apparently still keen. At the US head office Mehdi Ali was officially out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 08:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>theone199408&#xA;News While Commodore was still without a buyer, word leaked that the company leading the pack was in fact Samsung who were looking to gain more of a foothold in the European market. It seemed everything was hanging on that deal.&#xA;Dominik Diamond was rumoured to be returning to &amp;ldquo;Gamesmaster&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;A report from Mintel showed that the UK games industry contracted by 4% last year. The market value in 1993 was £670 million compared to £700 million in 1992.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/7/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/7/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News The fate of Commodore UK was close to becoming a bit clearer with an announcement regarding a new owner was due &amp;ldquo;any day now&amp;rdquo;. The &amp;ldquo;most solid&amp;rdquo; information pointed to a &amp;ldquo;Far-Eastern&amp;rdquo; company, with Acer, Samsung and Goldstar all rumoured to be in the running. While the UK office had continued trading, they weren&amp;rsquo;t receiving any new units to sell which meant they had to make do with whatever stock they had in their warehouses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/6/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/6/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News News broke as the mag went to press that Commodore worldwide had basically filed for administration in the Bahamas, where the company was registered. Just what this meant was unclear, but things did not look good. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly surprising considering the losses the company had posted over the last couple of years, though Commodore UK had performed well. While this move was obviously concerning, The One were confident that the continued popularity of the Amiga would mean a positive outcome one way or another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 22:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Andy Nuttall (aka “Nutts”) joined the mag as Deputy Editor after having done five months hard time at ST Format.&#xA;Third time’s the charm - or so Commodore hoped with its third CD32 bundle since launch. The Voyage pack included “Microcosm” and “The Chaos Engine”, plus four games from the two existing bundles while stocks lasted, all for £299.99.&#xA;Codemasters were bringing “Captain Dynamo” and the “Dizzy CD Collection” to the CD32.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/4/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/4/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Contrary to last month’s news, while ex-The One editor David Upchurch had been assigned to a new mag, it was to EMAP’s latest launch, PC Games, and not a reboot of Sinclair User&amp;hellip; which made a little more sense.&#xA;Ocean struck a deal with Virgin to release twelve of its games on Hit Squad, their budget label. The lineup included “Cannon Fodder”, “Dune”, “Dune 2”, “Jimmy White’s Whirlwind Snooker”, “Archer Maclean’s Pool”, “Realms”, “Legend of Kyrandia”, “Supremacy”, “KGB”, “Reach for the Skies”, “Shuttle” and “Lure of the Temptress”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 05:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>theone199403&#xA;News This was to be David Upchurch&amp;rsquo;s last issue as Editor as off to head up EMAP&amp;rsquo;s relaunch of&amp;hellip; Sinclair User. Apparently the Speccy had been seeing a resurgence, though I find that a little hard to believe. At any rate, Simon Byron was to take over the helm.&#xA;Team 17 were embracing the CD32 starting with &amp;ldquo;Ultimate Body Blows&amp;rdquo;, a revamped version of their beat&amp;rsquo;em up featuring new AGA backdrops, digitised speech and a digital CD soundtrack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/2/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 06:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/2/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Editor David Upchurch saw a bright 1994 ahead for the Amiga.&#xA;Word on the street was that Commodore UK were close to striking a deal with LucasArts that would see them bring their PC hits &amp;ldquo;Rebel Assault&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Day of the Tentacle&amp;rdquo; to the CD32. (It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen)&#xA;While England had suffered the shame of failing to qualify for the upcoming World Cup, Virgin were keen to join with Adidas to sponsor a new initiative to promote youth footballing skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 08:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Late breaking news was that Maxis were porting &amp;ldquo;Sim City 2000&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga. The PC original was impressive, but would it survive the translation?&#xA;It looked like &amp;ldquo;The Second Samurai&amp;rdquo; would be Vivid Image Design&amp;rsquo;s last title for a little while as they were going all in on CD gaming. Mev Dinc and his team were taking the interesting approach of insisting that all design and illustration work be finished before a single line of code was written.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/10/30/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 07:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/10/30/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Renegade&amp;rsquo;s release schedule was looking rather impressive with “Uridium 2” first up, followed soon after by “Turrican 3” and “Elfmania”. If that wasn’t enough, “Ruff ‘n’ Tumble”, “Sensible World of Soccer”, “Flight of the Amazon Queen” and “Z”) were all due by the end of the year. The last one - a real time strategy game from the Bitmap Brothers - was particularly interesting since it’d be years before it saw the light of day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/6/23/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 05:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/6/23/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The Amiga had a strong showing at this year&amp;rsquo;s Golden Joysticks awards. Team 17 and Sensible Software won Software House of the Year and Computer Game of the Year respectively, with Jon Hare giving a &amp;ldquo;stirring speech warning against the dangers of complacency.&amp;rdquo; The Amiga related winners were:&#xA;Software House of the Year: Team 17 Computer Game of the Year: &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; Sensible Software Best Licensed Computer Game: &amp;ldquo;Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis&amp;rdquo; LucasArts Programming Team of the Year: LucasArts Best Computer Simulation: &amp;ldquo;Formula One Grand Prix&amp;rdquo; Geoff Crammond/Microprose Team 17 announced two new titles, both racing games: &amp;ldquo;Overdrive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;F1 Challenge&amp;rdquo; (the latter would be renamed to &amp;ldquo;F17 Challenge&amp;rdquo; after some legal issues).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/3/18/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 07:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/3/18/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Comic artist Dave Gibbons (of &amp;ldquo;Watchmen&amp;rdquo; fame) had been collaborating with Charles Cecil and Revolution Software on the cyberpunk point-and-click adventure &amp;ldquo;Beneath a Steel Sky&amp;rdquo;. It transpired that his involvement came about after he contacted The One to complain they&amp;rsquo;d forgotten to credit him for &amp;ldquo;Watchmen&amp;rdquo;. The mag decided to lend him an Amiga and a copy of &amp;ldquo;Deluxe Paint&amp;rdquo; for a followup article, which sparked his interest in computer art and lead to an introduction to Cecil.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/2/27/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 07:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/2/27/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Under the headline &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3 Shocker!&amp;rdquo; came the news that Dino Dini had parted ways with Anco and signed with Virgin to develop a &amp;ldquo;world-beating follow-up to &amp;lsquo;Kick Off 2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;, with the working title &amp;ldquo;Goal!&amp;rdquo;. The move cast doubts on whether there would be an official &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3&amp;rdquo;, though co-designer Steve Screech remained at Anco.&#xA;From the ashes of the hyped &amp;ldquo;Apocalypse&amp;rdquo;, Jason Perkins and Robin Levy were continuing their partnership on a new game from Renegade, &amp;ldquo;Ruff n&amp;rsquo; Tumble&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/1/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 06:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/1/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Digital Image Design had two new titles on the way. The first up was a &amp;ldquo;pseudo-sequel&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Epic&amp;rdquo; - called &amp;ldquo;Odyssey&amp;rdquo; - set 90 years further in the future and would feature more of an open world feel. Sadly it looks like it was never released.. The second was another sequel, jet fighter sim &amp;ldquo;TFX Inferno&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Relative newcomer Miracle Games were rather bullish about their upcoming platformer, &amp;ldquo;Miracle Bat&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/12/12/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 06:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/12/12/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Psygnosis announced &amp;ldquo;Lemmings 2: The Tribes&amp;rdquo;. This took a slightly different twist on the original, with the goal being to re-unite twelve tribes of Lemmings, each tribe having a different theme complete with their own abilities.&#xA;An update to Sensi Software&amp;rsquo;s smash hit &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; had arrived and boasted a bevy of new and improved features, including red &amp;amp; yellow cards, the back pass rule and more competent goalies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/11/16/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 04:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/11/16/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Ocean had scored a #1 hit last Christmas with ”WWF Wrestlemania”, and hoped for a repeat in the form of ”WWF European Rampage”. While the earlier title had been panned by critics, the publisher were adamant this one would be better.&#xA;Commodore had announced the A4000 which, with a £1999 price tag, was very much targeted at the serious user. This fuelled rumours of a more affordable gaming machine and right as the mag went to press it looked like they had news&amp;hellip; though that would have to wait until next month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/18/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 06:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/18/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News After months of mystery, Dino Dini&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3&amp;rdquo; was finally unveiled. Unlike the second instalment which was effectively tweaks and improvements to the original&amp;rsquo;s codebase, this one was re-coded from the ground up. Would it be able to take back the crown from &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; ?&#xA;Speaking of which, the Sensi lads hadn&amp;rsquo;t been resting on their laurels and &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer v1.1&amp;rdquo; was due out next month. Player and club data had been updated for the new season, and there were other welcome changes such as re-written goalie behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/9/26/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 08:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/9/26/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Team 17 were having another crack at the beat &amp;rsquo;em up genre with &amp;ldquo;Body Blows&amp;rdquo;, along with a top down racer, &amp;ldquo;Overdrive&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Rumours started to circulate that there was yet another Amiga model on the way: the A800. It would be a 32bit machine with 68030 CPU and would sit between the A600 and the A1500. Commodore&amp;rsquo;s Market Director Kelly Sumner was adamant there would be no machine called the A800, but did confirm there was another machine on the way&amp;hellip; I assume it was the A1200.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/8/7/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/8/7/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Sad news this month as one of the oldest software houses closed up shop. Palace Software had been going for almost a decade and had been behind some cracking games, including &amp;ldquo;Barbarian&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Sacred Armour of Antiriad&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Shoot&amp;rsquo;em Up Construction Kit&amp;rdquo;. The move came after months of legal wrangling, and the London office became Titus&amp;rsquo;s UK HQ. It was unclear what would happen with titles like &amp;ldquo;Hostile Breed&amp;rdquo; (unreleased, but was actually finished and reviewed two issues earlier), and &amp;ldquo;Super Barbarian&amp;rdquo; (also unreleased).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/7/30/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/7/30/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News The upcoming Christmas battle for number one looked to be between Konami’s “Batman Returns”, Acclaim’s “Alien 3” and Ocean’s latest movie license signing: “Lethal Weapon 3”.&#xA;Commodore continued their run of stupid business decision with the announcement that they were to stop selling the A500 Plus in favour of the new A600.&#xA;The ‘92 Barcelona Olympics would soon be starting and Ocean was preparing “Espagna 92” [sic] to take on US Gold’s “Megasports”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/21/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 09:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/21/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Virgin snapped up Sensi&amp;rsquo;s upcoming war game, &amp;ldquo;Cannon Fodder&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;TV show Gamesmaster was set to return for a second series and the production company were on the look out for young talent to take part.&#xA;DMI had signed a deal with German developer Prestige to bring their games to the UK. First up was &amp;ldquo;Doofus&amp;rdquo;, which would be followed by &amp;ldquo;Sword of Honour&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Catch&amp;rsquo;em&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Ocean were porting the Nintendo hit &amp;ldquo;Bart Versus the World&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/28/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 07:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/28/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News The transformation/infiltration/coup was complete and the team from ACE magazine had taken over reigns. The One for Amiga was now just &amp;ldquo;The One&amp;rdquo; as the ST mag had been rolled into ST Action. Notable changes included the scrapping of the developer profile section (which I personally liked) in favour of &amp;ldquo;special interviews&amp;rdquo; because the latter was &amp;ldquo;simply more interesting&amp;rdquo;, and more detailed, critical reviews (the previous team may have gone a little easy on games).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/25/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/25/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</guid>
      <description>News It seemed this would be the final issue for the whole editorial crew as they were being replaced by the folk from &amp;ldquo;ex-sister magazine ACE&amp;rdquo;. Such a drastic move must&amp;rsquo;ve been a bitter pill to swallow, but it did mean the return of Gary Whitta.&#xA;TV companies had begun to take an interest in video games, with Channel 4&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Gamesmaster&amp;rdquo; clocking in at around 3 million viewers during its first season.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amiga 3000&#43; Board on eBay</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/7/amiga-3000-board-on-ebay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 04:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/7/amiga-3000-board-on-ebay/</guid>
      <description>Well, this is rather fascinating: an Amiga 3000+ prototype board was sold on eBay by none other than Dave Haynie. It fetched a decent $2,155 USD and included a couple of his notebooks from the period when he was working on it.&#xA;As if the fact that such a board still exists isn&amp;rsquo;t interesting enough, he penned a long description of the board and what was going on at Commodore at the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Kickstarters</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 23:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a good time to be a retro gaming fan recently with several promising Kickstarters. Of course I dawdled too long on writing about them, so some have already finished, but they&amp;rsquo;re still worth keeping an eye on.&#xA;Reformation 2 from Matt Gray The first Reformation took a little longer to ship than originally expected, but it was well worth the wait. 5 CDs of excellent remakes of some of the best tunes to grace the C64 (and therefore, games in general).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December Games Revisited</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/31/december-games-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 04:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/31/december-games-revisited/</guid>
      <description>One of these days I’ll get my act together and not wait until the dying hours of the month (and even year in this case) to write these things… With that said, I did manage to have a decent play on a bunch of the biggest December games from 1986 and 1988.&#xA;”The Sentinel”, Geoff Crammond/Firebird, 1986&#xA;Reviewed Zzap!64 December 1986.&#xA;I recall playing this quite a bit on the C64.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November Games Revisited</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/30/november-games-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 07:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/30/november-games-revisited/</guid>
      <description>I had hoped to have a number of opportunities to spend some quality time playing these games (and more) this month, but one of the downsides of travelling so much for business is that such occasions are rare. Very rare in the case of this month: I managed a pathetic few hours last Sunday.&#xA;At any rate&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief look back at a few games that hit the shelves in November many years ago to rave reviews.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms To Billions: The Amiga Years</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 03:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</guid>
      <description>The good folk behind the absolutely brilliant &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms to Billions&amp;rdquo; documentary have announced their new project: a 90 minute film on the Amiga. This time rather than focussing on the British contribution to the industry, they&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking to prominent Amiga developers, musicians, demo sceners and so on from around the world.&#xA;Given my love for the Amiga - a machine that was so beautifully and elegantly architected and years ahead of its time - I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely delighted they&amp;rsquo;ve chosen it as the subject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Commodore Amiga: a visual Commpendium&#34; Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 01:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Following on from his beautiful C64 book, Sam Dyer is running a Kickstarter campaign to give the same loving treatment to the Amiga. He has an impressive list of prominent Amiga folk lined up as contributors and - quite rightly - plans to include a section on the demo scene, which played a huge role in making the machine so amazing. The campaign smashed through the initial goal within a short time but there are still some rather tasty looking stretch goals that would be great to hit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Chaos Engine remake announced</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/18/the-chaos-engine-remake-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 01:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/18/the-chaos-engine-remake-announced/</guid>
      <description>Rather exciting news: a remake of the excellent Amiga game The Chaos Engine has been announced for PS, Mac and Linux. This game has always struck me as an obvious candidate for an update, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to hear it&amp;rsquo;s finally happening. Development duties are being handled by Abstraction Games who most recently ported Hotline Miami to the PS3 an Vita. Fingers crossed it&amp;rsquo;ll have been worth the wait.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensible World of Soccer (XBLA)</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/14/sensible-world-of-soccer-xbla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/14/sensible-world-of-soccer-xbla/</guid>
      <description>When I finally got around to picking up a 360 a couple of years ago, the first thing I did when I set it up was download Sensible World Of Soccer (SWOS). Forget Halo, or Gears of War, or Mass Effect; SWOS was what I cared about. The Amiga version is the game I routinely tell people is &amp;ldquo;the best game ever made&amp;rdquo; and I played it everyday for years during the 90s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archipelagos (iOS)</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/2/20/archipelagos-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 07:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/2/20/archipelagos-ios/</guid>
      <description>Archipelagos appeared on the Amiga back in 1989 and is a first person realtime puzzle/strategy game. I certainly remember playing it, but I also remember not really knowing what I was doing. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat reminiscent of The Sentinel (surely a remake of that must be on the cards?), and features 9999 procedurally generated levels.&#xA;The original scored well in magazines of the day (Zzap! gave it 90%) and the remake is a decent job, though it feels a little rough and finicky - it seems to be a pretty straightforward port of the modern desktop version and the touch controls could use some love.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
