<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>May on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/may/</link>
    <description>Recent content in May on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 07:38:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/may/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 07:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Andy Nuttall reckoned this issue was &amp;ldquo;more fruitsome and lovely than ever&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;A new contender for acquiring Commodore entered the ring: Escom, who had put in a bid for £5 million. The Commodore UK team downplayed this saying the bid was low and their own offer was still favourite. Meanwhile, Escom had bought out failed UK high street shop chain Rumbelows.&#xA;Retailer Silica were staying the course with their Amiga sales and launched a new CD32 bundle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/4/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/4/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News The One had had a bit of a facelift with the Contents page getting a re- design, along with various sections getting re-labelled.&#xA;The big news for the month was that Commodore UK had announced a new Amiga: the A1(M). The specs included &amp;ldquo;32 megabytes of RAM, a 1 gigabyte hard drive, 32-bit graphics card, 64-bit processor, 8x speed CD-ROM drive&amp;rdquo;. And of course it was The One&amp;rsquo;s April Fools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 22:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Andy Nuttall (aka “Nutts”) joined the mag as Deputy Editor after having done five months hard time at ST Format.&#xA;Third time’s the charm - or so Commodore hoped with its third CD32 bundle since launch. The Voyage pack included “Microcosm” and “The Chaos Engine”, plus four games from the two existing bundles while stocks lasted, all for £299.99.&#xA;Codemasters were bringing “Captain Dynamo” and the “Dizzy CD Collection” to the CD32.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/28/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 07:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/28/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News The transformation/infiltration/coup was complete and the team from ACE magazine had taken over reigns. The One for Amiga was now just &amp;ldquo;The One&amp;rdquo; as the ST mag had been rolled into ST Action. Notable changes included the scrapping of the developer profile section (which I personally liked) in favour of &amp;ldquo;special interviews&amp;rdquo; because the latter was &amp;ldquo;simply more interesting&amp;rdquo;, and more detailed, critical reviews (the previous team may have gone a little easy on games).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #4 April/May 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</guid>
      <description>This issue came hot on the heels of British Telecom&amp;rsquo;s decision to bail out of the games industry. They were looking to sell off the Rainbird, Firebird and Silverbird labels as one lot, while winding Telecomsoft down. The official reason given was that games were no longer in line with the goals of BT, and the asking price was rumoured to be around £5 million. The editorial questioned the motives, highlighting a series of recent misteps resulting in significant financial losses, which included the purchase of Beyond Software (closed down soon after due to poor performance), and the US based Firebird Licensees Inc which lasted less than a year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/15/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/15/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Thanks to a tweet from Julian Rignall I finally noticed that the ships getting blown up by Zzap!64 on the cover represented Commodore User &amp;amp; C&amp;amp;VG. Cheeky.&#xA;The reason for such a cover? Sales had climbed to 67,728 per month and showed no signs of letting up. The mag would be undergoing a few changes - they looked to be broadening the scope of what they were covering, including “unusual, but relevant” features.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/24/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/24/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>[Oh dear, I got confused and thought this was the April issue.. turns out my April issue appears to be missing - no doubt the fault of one of my High School friends back in the day]&#xA;News Rignall and Glancey took on Domark’s Mark Strachan and Andy Blazdell in three rounds of Tengen’s &amp;ldquo;Vindicators&amp;rdquo; arcade machine. The C&amp;amp;VG lads won two out of three and claimed the Tengen Trophy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/31/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 08:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/31/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News A rather triumphant Zzap! boasted about the latest ABC figures which showed it was the &amp;ldquo;leading magazine in the field&amp;rdquo;. Sister publication Crash did even better, not only beating rival Sinclair User but also C&amp;amp;VG, which meant it was the best selling computer title of any kind in the UK.&#xA;In the same editorial, Roger Kean lamented the recent trend of game releases being pushed back. The common excuse for delays seemed to be &amp;ldquo;programming complexity&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 08:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News Stephen Crow&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Starquake&amp;rdquo; was heading to the ST and Amstrad PC thanks to Mandarin Software.&#xA;Hewson were to re-release several classic titles by Gargoyle Games. &amp;ldquo;Dun Darach&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Marsport&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Tir Na Nog&amp;rdquo; would available for a mere £1.99.&#xA;C&amp;amp;VG apologised for incorrectly stating the price of &amp;ldquo;IO&amp;rdquo; for the C64 last month.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Stir Crazy&amp;rdquo; from Infogrames starred a &amp;ldquo;crazy criminal character&amp;rdquo; attempting to escape prison.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Batman: The Killing Joke&amp;rdquo; by Alan Moore and Brian Bolland was proving quite a hit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This (er, last) month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/1/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 07:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/1/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>I managed to miss May by one day - mea culpa.&#xA;News Julian Rignall defended the status of the C64 in light of the recently arrived 16bit machines, citing the strength of recent release compared to rather disappointing 16bit titles: &amp;ldquo;To me, the Commodore 64 is leading the way when it comes to new ideas - Driller, the up-and-coming Echelon, Apollo 18, Nebulus, Soko Ban and Deflektor are recent examples that inject new life and innovation into the computer game format.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/5/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 04:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/5/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Simon Price, who had previously worked on &amp;ldquo;Redhawk&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kwah!&amp;rdquo;, was developing &amp;ldquo;Wiz&amp;rdquo; for Melbourne House.&#xA;Danish software house Kele Line had two new C64 releases this month, &amp;ldquo;Thunder Force&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Unitrax&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;The 4th Dimension&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Vikings&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Pirates of the Ocean&amp;rdquo; were to follow. Seems that only &amp;ldquo;Thunder Force&amp;rdquo; (published by Hewson) and &amp;ldquo;Vikings&amp;rdquo; made it out.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Mystery of Arkham Manor&amp;rdquo; would see the player take on the role of a journo investigating a - as the title suggests - mysterious murder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/25/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 01:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/25/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Tony Crowther moved back Alligata, the company he started out with. He had briefly run his own software house called Wizard Developments.&#xA;After finding success with Delta4&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bored of the Rings&amp;rdquo; CRL had signed up the new St Brides spoof &amp;ldquo;The Very Big Cave Adventure&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Little of the much hyped &amp;ldquo;Nexus&amp;rdquo; had been heard over the previous few months, but now it had resurfaced with news that Beyond would no longer be the publisher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/4/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/4/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News More changes at Crash towers this month with three new staff members: Ian Phillipson, Gareth Adams and, perhaps most notably, Ciaran Brennan.&#xA;Mastertronic was branching out into the video and music markets by launching the Master Vision and Master Sound labels.&#xA;The Tau Ceti system was to once again be the setting for a new game from CRL called &amp;ldquo;Traxxion&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Piracy was rife in the USSR with the &amp;ldquo;Raid Over Moscow&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Rambo&amp;rdquo; proving particularly popular.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 09:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News The first ever British entertainment software conference took place, with representatives from Britain&amp;rsquo;s top software houses and distributors in attendance. A gala awards dinner was held which handed out awards based on Crash and Zzap!64 reader awards. Best Spectrum game went to &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo; from Incentive, with &amp;ldquo;California Games&amp;rdquo; from Epyx/US Gold winning best C64 game. Ocean won best software house for readers of both magazines.&#xA;Games Workshop opened a new retail outlet on Oxford Street and a queue of &amp;ldquo;well over&amp;rdquo; 1000 people showed up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 03:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News Huge news arrived just hours before this issue went to press - Amstrad had bought Sinclair for meagre £5 million. What would this mean for Sinclair products? The QL and microdrive would be likely casualties, but it sounded like Amstrad had promising plans for the Spectrum. Overall it was taken as a positive happening, though the alternative would&amp;rsquo;ve been receivership for Sinclair. Sir Clive himself was to return to research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/12/this-month-in-cvg-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/12/this-month-in-cvg-/</guid>
      <description>News Not games related as such, but May saw the launch of C&amp;amp;VG&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bring Back the Doctor&amp;rdquo; campaign after the BBC announced Doctor Who was to end. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the BBC had specified when this was to happen, as it would last another 4 years.&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;Designer of the Month&amp;rdquo; was Stephen Redman, a 21 year old uni student who released the somewhat controversial (how innocent we all were) game &amp;ldquo;A Day in the Life&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
