<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remake on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/remake/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Remake on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 06:02:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/remake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The return of Magnetic Scrolls? (Sort of)</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/18/the-return-of-magnetic-scrolls-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 06:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/18/the-return-of-magnetic-scrolls-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>Well, this is very interesting indeed. Hugh Steers - a founding member of Magnetic Scrolls - has formed Strand Games along with Stefan Meier (from if-legends.org). Their first release is a a remaster of the classic adventure &amp;ldquo;The Pawn&amp;rdquo;, available for Mac, Win and Linux. Not only that, but they have the support of other Magnetic Scrolls alumni, including Anita Sinclair and Ken Gordon.
I stumbled across their site somewhat randomly - I&amp;rsquo;m a bit surprised it hasn&amp;rsquo;t received more coverage in the retro gaming scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midwinter Remake</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/1/10/midwinter-remake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 21:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/1/10/midwinter-remake/</guid>
      <description>Chris Wild, who was behind the excellent iOS remake of &amp;ldquo;Lords of Midnight&amp;rdquo;, has announced that his company is now taking on a brand new version of another Mike Singleton classic: &amp;ldquo;Midwinter&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Midwinter&amp;rdquo; received considerable critical claim but slipped by unnoticed by many (including myself). A sprawling open world game originally released on the Amiga in 1989, &amp;ldquo;Midwinter&amp;rdquo; was an early, influential example of sandbox gameplay.
The game is currently in pre-production, with a Kickstarter campaign expected to start in the next few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chaos Engine remake announced</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/18/the-chaos-engine-remake-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 01:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/18/the-chaos-engine-remake-announced/</guid>
      <description>Rather exciting news: a remake of the excellent Amiga game The Chaos Engine has been announced for PS, Mac and Linux. This game has always struck me as an obvious candidate for an update, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to hear it&amp;rsquo;s finally happening. Development duties are being handled by Abstraction Games who most recently ported Hotline Miami to the PS3 an Vita. Fingers crossed it&amp;rsquo;ll have been worth the wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archipelagos (iOS)</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/2/20/archipelagos-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 07:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/2/20/archipelagos-ios/</guid>
      <description>Archipelagos appeared on the Amiga back in 1989 and is a first person realtime puzzle/strategy game. I certainly remember playing it, but I also remember not really knowing what I was doing. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat reminiscent of The Sentinel (surely a remake of that must be on the cards?), and features 9999 procedurally generated levels.
The original scored well in magazines of the day (Zzap! gave it 90%) and the remake is a decent job, though it feels a little rough and finicky - it seems to be a pretty straightforward port of the modern desktop version and the touch controls could use some love.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
