<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TheGamesMachine on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/thegamesmachine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TheGamesMachine on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 23:56:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/thegamesmachine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/22/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 23:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/22/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News Word leaked out that Epyx was working on a new console. David Morse (CEO of Epyx, and one of the original Amiga hardware designers) was involved on what was rumoured to be a new handheld. This, of course, would become the Atari Lynx.
Megadrives and NES consoles started appearing in arcades in the UK where players could purchase a set amount of play time with a range of games available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 05:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News Atari Games (not to be confused with hardware manufacturer, Atari) sued Nintendo for $100 million over the inability to publish games for the NES without going through the Japanese company. Nintendo seemed unphased by the move, saying that they had never lost a lawsuit.
Confusion reigned over the specifics for the Konix Slipstream. TGM attempted to clear things up by confirming that it would retail at £150 (or slightly higher), have a set of peripherals (hydraulic chair, light gun, 3D helmet), some of which would be included with the console (not the chair!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw a new &amp;ldquo;bigger and brighter&amp;rdquo; look for TGM.
Excitement was growing for the impending release of the Konix Slipstream megaconsole. Costing a mere £149 it was due to go on sale in Autumn and would be able to read software from standard 3&amp;quot; disks as well as cartridges. Disks were looking like the preferred format due to being much cheaper to produce - customers could look forward to paying only 15 quid for games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/22/this-month-in-tgm-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 22:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/22/this-month-in-tgm-88/</guid>
      <description>News The console wars were heating up as rumours surfaced that Nintendo and Sega were working on 16bit machines. Neither the NES or Master System had managed to gain much of a foothold in the UK - both machines selling around 45,000 units each - but the tide did seem to be turning. Code Masters were rather bullish about the console market, with Operations Manager Bruce Everiss being particularly enthusiastic about the Konix Slipstream: &amp;ldquo;I think Konix has the potential to be another Amstrad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News After months of speculation, Amstrad finally revealed their 16bit Sinclair. It was not, as many thought, a games console, but a rather unimpressive PC. The reception was luke warm at best: &amp;ldquo;is Amstrad&amp;rsquo;s Sinclair a powerless business computer or a games machine that&amp;rsquo;s unsuitable for games?&amp;rdquo;
Meanwhile, excitement was riding high for the Konix console. The release date was to be January 28th and would include a bunch of add ons, including the hydraulic chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 21:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Word on the street was that Atari was readying not one, but four new ST machines. The main one would be a &amp;ldquo;super ST&amp;rdquo; that would take on the Amiga, then there was a portable ST, a &amp;ldquo;Pocket PC&amp;rdquo; and an ST based console. Not only that, but the existing 520STFM would have its price slashed by £100 and get a software bundle valued at £440. How many of these would actually hit the selves?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-the-games-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 04:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-the-games-machine/</guid>
      <description>News Atari appeared to be winning the battle of the 16bits. A combination of a very generous software bundle, price drop and big ad campaign saw sales of the ST see a rise even during the usual summer slump. Meanwhile, the Amiga was still having problems with reliability - some shops putting returns as high as 25%. Software sales were reportedly 70/30 in favour of the ST.
A small South Wales company called Miles Gordon Technology (MGT) was about to release a Spectrum &amp;ldquo;super clone&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/18/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 08:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/18/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Commodore had been reluctant to try to bring the Amiga&amp;rsquo;s price in line with the cheaper Atari ST, but this month the long rumoured £100 cut happened. The ST had stormed ahead in sales and it looked like it would be a tough battle for the Amiga, which Commodore had originally pitched as a business machine but was now accepting that it&amp;rsquo;s destiny would be games.
Sugar&amp;rsquo;s Amstrad entered into a partnership with Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s Sky satellite TV company which would see Amstrad producing and selling £199 dishes that would receive the four Sky channels once the service launched early in the following year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/7/19/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 21:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/7/19/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Not a game as such, but the latest book from William Gibson, &amp;ldquo;Mona Lisa Overdrive&amp;rdquo;, was about to hit the shelves. To mark the occasion, the Cyberpunk theme would be visited several times in this issue.
What was billed &amp;ldquo;the first mass-market desktop-publishing (DTP) packag&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; was launched by mouse manufacturer AMS for PC-XT and AT compatibles. It featured a mouse, a handheld scanner and software - all for only £447.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 05:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Computers and Art&amp;rdquo; was a new travelling exhibition that had just opened at the IBM Gallery of Science and Art in NYC. It was an attempt to bring &amp;ldquo;computer art&amp;rdquo; into the mainstream - not just graphics, but works using fabric etc. Elsewhere, Carnegie Mellon began a course on writing &amp;ldquo;interactive fiction.&amp;rdquo; CRL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Wolfman&amp;rdquo; was in the news for failing to be slapped with a British Board of Censors rating certificate, unlike their previous adventures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 09:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News The first ever British entertainment software conference took place, with representatives from Britain&amp;rsquo;s top software houses and distributors in attendance. A gala awards dinner was held which handed out awards based on Crash and Zzap!64 reader awards. Best Spectrum game went to &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo; from Incentive, with &amp;ldquo;California Games&amp;rdquo; from Epyx/US Gold winning best C64 game. Ocean won best software house for readers of both magazines.
Games Workshop opened a new retail outlet on Oxford Street and a queue of &amp;ldquo;well over&amp;rdquo; 1000 people showed up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 19:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Rare had been inundated with calls from developers wanting in on the Nintendo market and the Z80 arcade board that they (Rare) were working on. This all follows on from a pretty amazing interview with Rare in the previous issue of TGM - amazing because it was the first (and perhaps only?) proper interview conducted with the Stamper brothers. Everyone had been wondering what happened to Ultimate Play The Game (arguably the finest developer of the 8bit years), and now we all knew.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
