<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1986 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1986/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1986 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 04:12:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1986/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>December Games Revisited</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/31/december-games-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 04:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/31/december-games-revisited/</guid>
      <description>One of these days I’ll get my act together and not wait until the dying hours of the month (and even year in this case) to write these things… With that said, I did manage to have a decent play on a bunch of the biggest December games from 1986 and 1988.
”The Sentinel”, Geoff Crammond/Firebird, 1986
Reviewed Zzap!64 December 1986.
I recall playing this quite a bit on the C64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 04:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News More changes were afoot, with Strategy Front writer Sean Masterson moving on and the start of a make over that would take effect during the next few months.
Last month Zzap! teased readers by asking them to check out a screenshot of the hotly anticipated arcade conversion of &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; and then failed to print it. To make up for the error they provided not one but four shots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Games Revisited</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/30/november-games-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 07:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/30/november-games-revisited/</guid>
      <description>I had hoped to have a number of opportunities to spend some quality time playing these games (and more) this month, but one of the downsides of travelling so much for business is that such occasions are rare. Very rare in the case of this month: I managed a pathetic few hours last Sunday.
At any rate&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief look back at a few games that hit the shelves in November many years ago to rave reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 08:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Gary Penn trumpeted the success of Zzap!, saying that it had become the &amp;ldquo;biggest selling Commodore magazine in the civilised World.&amp;rdquo; The healthy sales meant more advertisers, which meant more content - this month the mag hit 148 pages.
A Commodore show took place in Manchester. Commodore did have a stand (which apparently bore a resemblance to Parisian public toilets), where they were showing off was the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Parallax&#34; Re-visited</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/parallax-re-visited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 07:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/parallax-re-visited/</guid>
      <description>Parallax Sensible Software/Ocean, 1986 This month in 1986 saw Sensible&amp;rsquo;s first big title reviewed in Zzap!64, scoring a very respectable 93% overall and receiving a Sizzler.
Over the past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to remember where I first saw &amp;ldquo;Parallax&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; I want to say it was at my friend Neil&amp;rsquo;s house, but did he even have a C64?? I know he had a Spectrum and later an Amiga&amp;hellip; Maybe it was someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 04:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News An article appeared in the Canberra Times in which a Mr Paul Gathercoal blathered on about the evils of games. Mr Gathercoal firmly believed games were corrupting the minds of children, driving them to lives of robberies, killing and masturbation. He claimed that playing &amp;ldquo;Franke Goes To Hollywood&amp;rdquo; would lead to &amp;ldquo;pill-popping&amp;rdquo;. What utter nonsense.
Gary Liddon had buggered off to Newsfield&amp;rsquo;s new software house, Thalamus, and a call went out to find someone to replace him at Zzap!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 09:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News More staffing changes at the magazine this month. Roger Kean was moving over to a new Newsfield mag called L.M., with Gary Penn stepping in to the Editor role. There were three new faces with Richard &amp;ldquo;Dick&amp;rdquo; Eddy, Jonathan Rignall (Julian&amp;rsquo;s younger brother) and Massimo Valducci starting.
Beyond announced the upcoming release of not one but two Denton Design games: &amp;ldquo;Dante’s Inferno&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Infodroid&amp;rdquo;.
Meanwhile, Beyond had managed to secure the first ever Star Trek license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/8/20/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 06:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/8/20/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Liddon was leaving Zzap! to join Newsfield&amp;rsquo;s new software house, Thalamus, as Technical Executive. The company was headed by ex-Activision Press Officer Andrew Wright. The first game was due to be released in September on the C64 and Spectrum, with an Amstrad version following.
Gremlin were readying four new titles in time for Christmas: &amp;ldquo;Pentacle&amp;rdquo; (unreleased?), &amp;ldquo;Future Knight&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Bounder II&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Trailblazer&amp;rdquo;.
Arkana&amp;rsquo;s BBC game &amp;ldquo;Powerplay&amp;rdquo; was heading to the C64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/7/14/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/7/14/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News The Commodore Show in London was the biggest dedicated C64 event of the year. Zzap!&amp;rsquo;s own booth proved very popular - especially when games programmers dropped by to show off their latest wares (often yet to be signed to a publisher). So why weren&amp;rsquo;t the crowds impressed with the show? It seemed software houses were very thin on the ground&amp;hellip;
Tony Takoushi was at the show touting a new gizmo called &amp;ldquo;Speedos&amp;rdquo; which was a mod for 1541 floppy drives enabling much faster load times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 08:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Antony Jacobson wrote a withering attack on Zzap! and Crash in Computer Trade Weekly. It really was oddly vitriolic and included such gems as: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; a certain kind of magazine should only be handled with rubber gloves and antiseptic fire tongs. No-one forces them to publish contagious rubbish but magazines that do so are not simply to be described as boring, but debasing the values of their readership&amp;hellip; and polluting the social and commercial environment in which we live and work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/31/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 08:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/31/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News A rather triumphant Zzap! boasted about the latest ABC figures which showed it was the &amp;ldquo;leading magazine in the field&amp;rdquo;. Sister publication Crash did even better, not only beating rival Sinclair User but also C&amp;amp;VG, which meant it was the best selling computer title of any kind in the UK.
In the same editorial, Roger Kean lamented the recent trend of game releases being pushed back. The common excuse for delays seemed to be &amp;ldquo;programming complexity&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 01:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Roger Kean pondered whether the games industry &amp;ldquo;coming of age&amp;rdquo; after 5-ish years with the conglomeration of software houses and the emergence of a small number of dominating companies was a good thing. On the one hand it did mean developers were able to focus more on creating games rather than managing the marketing and distribution, but on the other the desire to get as many games on the shelves as possible was putting a real strain on quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 06:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Commodore announced they were closing their Corby factory and ceasing the manufacture of the 64 in Britain. Was this a sign of bigger troubles? The price of the C64 remained higher than that of competitors, and rather than address this, Commodore had introduced the C16 - but what did this actually solve?
English Software were finally about to release &amp;ldquo;Elektra Glide&amp;rdquo; on the C64 - some months after the original Atari version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News This month&amp;rsquo;s editorial warned readers to expect some divisive reviews. Not divisive in that reviewers were unable to agree, but in the sense that they had some truly great games, some utterly awful, and few in between. So some &amp;ldquo;savage criticism&amp;rdquo; was in store.
One amusing aspect of the editorial is that Roger Kean seemed quite bothered by the fact that a reader had written in to complain about Kean&amp;rsquo;s assertion that the C64&amp;rsquo;s xmas release schedule was &amp;ldquo;disappointing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 02:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Probe Software was porting two arcade games, &amp;ldquo;Quartet&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Enduro Racer&amp;rdquo; to home computers for Activision.
&amp;ldquo;Tracker&amp;rdquo; from Rainbird promised tactical battles against an &amp;ldquo;artificially intelligent enemy&amp;rdquo; which would involve strategy and fast 3D arcade sections.
Beyond continued to promote their much hyped &amp;ldquo;Star Trek&amp;rdquo; game, which would never see a release. They also revealed &amp;ldquo;Infodroid&amp;rdquo; - a new game from Denton Designs.
After Ocean&amp;rsquo;s exceptionally disappointing &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo; a few months earlier, Activision owned the US rights to the cartoon and David Crane had been working on an entirely different &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo; game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 23:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw C&amp;amp;VG turn 5 years old and to celebrate they had a bunch of special features, including a Spectrum listing by Steve Turner&amp;rsquo;s dad.
Microsphere revealed their next game would be &amp;ldquo;Contact Sam Cruise&amp;rdquo;, which was inspired by classic private eye movies. There was also a hint that there might be something for fans of &amp;ldquo;Skool Daze&amp;rdquo; at Christmas.
Arioalasoft got the licenses for two Hanna-Barbera cartoons: &amp;ldquo;The Centurions&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Challenge of the Gobots&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 03:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Ariolasoft spun out two new software houses, 39 Steps to focus on adventure games and Reaktor arcade/action games. First up from 39 Steps would be &amp;ldquo;They Stole a Million&amp;rdquo; while Reaktor&amp;rsquo;s would be &amp;ldquo;Deactivators&amp;rdquo;.
Martial arts games were proving popular and Martech threw their hat in the ring with &amp;ldquo;Uchi-Mata&amp;rdquo;, a &amp;ldquo;more subtle&amp;rdquo; simulation based on Judo.
Beyond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Star Trek&amp;rdquo; was to land in time for Christmas and would feature more than 1000 stars and 256 subplots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 01:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Peter Jones and Trevor Lever (the blokes behind &amp;ldquo;Terrormolinos&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hampstead&amp;rdquo;) were back with a new two part adventure &amp;ldquo;Dodgy Geezers&amp;rdquo;.
US Gold had a strong upcoming lineup with &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Masters of the Universe&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Infiltrator&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Cycle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Championship Wrestling&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Movie Monster&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;World Games&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Xevious&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Express Raider&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Break Thru&amp;rdquo;. Phew.
Lucasfilm and Activision picked up the game rights for &amp;ldquo;Labyrinth&amp;rdquo;. The movie had been received well in the US and was due to hit the UK around Christmas</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 03:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s nearly here&amp;rdquo;, declared C&amp;amp;VG about Mike Singleton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dark Sceptre&amp;rdquo;. The ambitious strategy/adventure (which was intended to have an optional Play By Mail service to allow players to compete with each other and Mike himself) had been in progress for a while and looked fantastic, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be until February 1988 that C&amp;amp;VG finally got to play it. From the review: &amp;ldquo;Was it worth the wait? We&amp;rsquo;ll pass on that&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (it received 8/10)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/7/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 04:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/7/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Leading this month&amp;rsquo;s news was US Gold&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;World Cup Carnival&amp;rdquo;, the official World Cup &amp;lsquo;86 game. A team of programmers had been working on it for 6 months and US Gold boldly claimed that it would &amp;ldquo;reach new standards in football simulation&amp;rdquo;. Sadly it would turn out to be one of the most infamously terrible games of the time, and was just a repackaging of an older title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 03:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Activision announced &amp;ldquo;Murder on the Missippi[sic]&amp;rdquo;, which was being written by Adam Bellin. Rather oddly C&amp;amp;VG described Bellin as &amp;ldquo;part of the team who produced the controversial &amp;lsquo;Ghostbusters&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;. I have no idea what the controversy was.
&amp;ldquo;Dr Blitzen and the Islands of Arcanum&amp;rdquo; would be the followup to the popular &amp;ldquo;Dynamite Dan&amp;rdquo;.
Alligata released &amp;ldquo;Who Dares Wins II&amp;rdquo;.
Colin McLinton won Firebird&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Elite&amp;rdquo; competition. There were 11 finalists, all of which had achieved Elite status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/25/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 01:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/25/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Tony Crowther moved back Alligata, the company he started out with. He had briefly run his own software house called Wizard Developments.
After finding success with Delta4&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bored of the Rings&amp;rdquo; CRL had signed up the new St Brides spoof &amp;ldquo;The Very Big Cave Adventure&amp;rdquo;.
Little of the much hyped &amp;ldquo;Nexus&amp;rdquo; had been heard over the previous few months, but now it had resurfaced with news that Beyond would no longer be the publisher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 23:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News The UK release of &amp;ldquo;Questprobe 3&amp;rdquo; (aka &amp;ldquo;The Fantastic Four&amp;rdquo;) had suffered more delays. There had been hopes it&amp;rsquo;d be out for Christmas, but it looks like licensing issues had pushed it back.
Rhino announced &amp;ldquo;Ark Pandora&amp;rdquo; for the C64.
PSS had released two new wargames: &amp;ldquo;Falklands 82&amp;rdquo; for the Spectrum and &amp;ldquo;Theatre of Europe&amp;rdquo; for the Amstrad.
Global Software announced a game based on &amp;ldquo;the Worst Vegetable Movie of All Time&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The Attack of the Killer Tomatoes&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 06:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News The biggest news by far this month was that US Gold had merged with Ultimate Play The Game, and that US Gold would now handle all international manufacturing, promotion, marketing and sales of Ultimate games. Ultimate said that they were going to concentrate on making games and planned to release six new titles during 1986. What wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear was just how involved the Stamper brothers were to be, but it would turn out that they already had their eyes on the new Japanese consoles and the formation of a certain company called Rare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/9/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 01:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/9/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Andrew Braybrook revealed his new game, &amp;ldquo;Uridium&amp;rdquo;. It promised &amp;ldquo;super- fast scrolling and authentically addictive action&amp;rdquo; and would certainly end up delivering.
Infocom slashed the prices on several of their games for a Christmas promotion. &amp;ldquo;Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide To The Galaxy&amp;rdquo; would drop to £24.95, while others would be between £14 and £22.
Two schoolboys raised £80 for famine relief in Ethiopia by playing games for 24 hours. The games included &amp;ldquo;Castle Quest&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alien 8&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Revs&amp;rdquo;, all on their BBC which apparently &amp;ldquo;did get a bit hot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/5/mun4x70unjj1dh0jl2mlo3doj77olx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/5/mun4x70unjj1dh0jl2mlo3doj77olx/</guid>
      <description>News Dave Perry and Nick Jones had nearly wrapped up the latest Wally game for MikroGen - &amp;ldquo;Three Weeks in Paradise&amp;rdquo;.
Domark released a screenshot of their rather controversial &amp;ldquo;Friday the 13th&amp;rdquo;. The game certainly got the attention of the press but - unsurprisingly - for all the wrong reasons, as it turned out to be rubbish. (&amp;ldquo;Oh dear, oh dear&amp;rdquo; lamented Crash in their review).
A BBC conversion of Imagine&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Arcadia&amp;rdquo; called &amp;ldquo;Wet Zone&amp;rdquo; was to be distributed on the Micronet 800 dialup service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/15/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 22:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/15/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News A Crash contingent went down to London for the 20th ZX Microfair. While the event was usually held in the &amp;ldquo;cavernous&amp;rdquo; Royal Horticultural Hall, a booking mixup meant this one had to move to &amp;ldquo;several rooms and various floors&amp;rdquo; at Central Hall in Westminster. There were very few new products to talk about, the only ones receiving a mention being &amp;ldquo;The Professional Adventure Writing System&amp;rdquo;, a new disk interface from Rockfort called &amp;ldquo;The Disciple&amp;rdquo; and Romantic Robot&amp;rsquo;s video digitiser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News The Crash staff, along with all the other Newsfield folk, went down to London for the launch party of their new magazine, LM. The venue was the Camden Palace and plenty of gaming bigwigs were in attendance. Sadly the magazine failed to gain much traction, folding after only a handful of issues.
The release of Amstrad&amp;rsquo;s Spectrum +2 had many scratching their heads. Despite the official release having taken place in September, people were unable to find any in shops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 01:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News Celebrations at Crash towers as the latest circulation figures showed they had sold 101,483 copies a month on average between January and June. That number placed Crash ahead of all other computer mags.
This issue was the first to feature a cover drawn by someone other than Oliver Frey - Ian Craig was the illustrator responsible. It seemed that with the increasing array of magazines published by Newsfield, Frey had too much on his plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/29/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 01:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/29/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News The Personal Computer World Show was about to happen and publishers were busy announcing/teasing their upcoming games. Full details of what was on display would be in next month&amp;rsquo;s issue, but there was a boatload of previews to do.
Not one but two winners had been chosen for the Genesis competition Crash launched a few months earlier. The first was a shoot em up called &amp;ldquo;Kat Trap&amp;rdquo; by John Eggleton that would hopefully be out by Christmas, while the second - &amp;ldquo;The Sewer&amp;rdquo; by Martin Lee - was planned for Spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-crash-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 05:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-crash-88/</guid>
      <description>News On the back of the news that the price of the Spectrum 128K had dropped following the acquisition by Amstrad, rumours started to circulate that a 256K &amp;ldquo;games machine&amp;rdquo; was in the pipeline. According to the rumours the machine would be Spectrum based but would use credit card sized &amp;ldquo;cartridges&amp;rdquo;. Reactions were mixed - while this would drastically reduce piracy, software houses feared Amstrad having control over what games would be released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 03:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News Huge news arrived just hours before this issue went to press - Amstrad had bought Sinclair for meagre £5 million. What would this mean for Sinclair products? The QL and microdrive would be likely casualties, but it sounded like Amstrad had promising plans for the Spectrum. Overall it was taken as a positive happening, though the alternative would&amp;rsquo;ve been receivership for Sinclair. Sir Clive himself was to return to research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/21/this-month-in-crash-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 22:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/21/this-month-in-crash-85/</guid>
      <description>Compared to the previous few months, there seemed like a relative dearth of good games released for the Spectrum. Crash pondered whether this had anything to do with the recent release of the Spectrum 128K. Game compilations (often tied to a charity) were coming out at a ridiculous rate - would this result in the cost of games for the consumer (typically kids) going down? or will the revenue developers see take a big hit as people choose cheap compilations over &amp;ldquo;single&amp;rdquo; release games?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
