<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kickstarter on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/categories/kickstarter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kickstarter on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 22:37:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/categories/kickstarter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zzap!64 Annual 2019 Kickstarter launched</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/29/zzap64-annual-2019-kickstarter-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 22:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/29/zzap64-annual-2019-kickstarter-launched/</guid>
      <description>The folks behind last year&amp;rsquo;s rather excellent Crash Annual are back. Chris Wilkins, Roger Kean and Oli Frey have teamed up once again, this time to resurrect Crash&amp;rsquo;s sister mag, Zzap!64, for an annual due out towards the end of the year.&#xA;I must admit I didn&amp;rsquo;t read the Kickstarter pitch or even watch the video before backing it as there was no question in my mind, so it was only through seeing people discussing it online that I realised that the likes of Mel Croucher, Julian Rignall and Robin Hogg were also involved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectrum Addict: Load &#34;FILM 2&#34; Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/spectrum-addict-load-film-2-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 04:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/spectrum-addict-load-film-2-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>The Kickstarter for a follow up to the &amp;ldquo;Memoirs of a Spectrum Addict&amp;rdquo; documentary, &amp;ldquo;Load &amp;lsquo;FILM 2&amp;rsquo; has entered its final week. The line up of Speccy developers is impressive, including the likes of my old boss Jon Ritman and Bo Jangeborg. As someone who was obsessed by Delta4&amp;rsquo;s adventure games back in the day, I&amp;rsquo;m particularly pleased to see Fergus McNeil in there as well.&#xA;These documentaries are clearly a labour of love for Andy and I strongly believe that we need to be capturing the stories of these pioneers, so I really hope this funds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunter&#39;s Moon Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/28/hunters-moon-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 21:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/28/hunters-moon-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>The legendary C64 software house Thalamus is back! Created in 1986 by mag publisher Newsfield, it quickly grew a reputation for quality titles. The connection with Zzap!64 probably didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt either.&#xA;News broke a couple of months ago that the label was being reborn as Thalamus Digital, and that we could look forward to some of those classic games making a come back - including the possibility of a new installment of Creatures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Hubbard Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/18/project-hubbard-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 07:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/18/project-hubbard-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to overstate the impact Rob Hubbard had on the UK games scene during the 80s. He was a prolific musician who turned out some incredible tunes. Seeing &amp;ldquo;Commando&amp;rdquo; at my mate&amp;rsquo;s place one afternoon after school helped convince me I needed a C64. I remember going back to his house, tape recorder in hand, to record the music to listen to on repeat (especially that lovely game over tune).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crash Annual 2018 Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/24/crash-annual-2018-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 02:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/24/crash-annual-2018-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>The Kickstarter for the 99th issue of Crash magazine has gone live. Roger Kean is back on editing duties, and Oli Frey will be creating the cover and art - we&amp;rsquo;ll even see the return of the Jetman comic strip. The line up of other contributors is also looking rather impressive.&#xA;Crash holds a special place in my heart - it was my main go to mag back in the day (before, I admit, I jumped ship to the C64&amp;hellip;), and I still have all the well worn issues I used to pore over each month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Kickstarters</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 23:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a good time to be a retro gaming fan recently with several promising Kickstarters. Of course I dawdled too long on writing about them, so some have already finished, but they&amp;rsquo;re still worth keeping an eye on.&#xA;Reformation 2 from Matt Gray The first Reformation took a little longer to ship than originally expected, but it was well worth the wait. 5 CDs of excellent remakes of some of the best tunes to grace the C64 (and therefore, games in general).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZX Spectrum Next Kickstarter Launched!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/23/zx-spectrum-next-kickstarter-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 04:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/23/zx-spectrum-next-kickstarter-launched/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s even designed by the original&amp;rsquo;s designer, Rick Dickinson!&#xA;After months of anticipation, the ZX Spectrum Next Kickstarter campaign has been launched. I was fortunate to see a prototype in action at the Revival Solstice event last July when Henrique gave a talk on the project and was very impressed. After some high profile crowdfunded retro gaming failures over the last couple of years it&amp;rsquo;s easy to be sceptical, but these guys are not only doing everything right, but all indications are that their hearts are in the right place too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms To Billions: The Amiga Years</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 03:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</guid>
      <description>The good folk behind the absolutely brilliant &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms to Billions&amp;rdquo; documentary have announced their new project: a 90 minute film on the Amiga. This time rather than focussing on the British contribution to the industry, they&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking to prominent Amiga developers, musicians, demo sceners and so on from around the world.&#xA;Given my love for the Amiga - a machine that was so beautifully and elegantly architected and years ahead of its time - I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely delighted they&amp;rsquo;ve chosen it as the subject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Commodore Amiga: a visual Commpendium&#34; Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 01:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Following on from his beautiful C64 book, Sam Dyer is running a Kickstarter campaign to give the same loving treatment to the Amiga. He has an impressive list of prominent Amiga folk lined up as contributors and - quite rightly - plans to include a section on the demo scene, which played a huge role in making the machine so amazing. The campaign smashed through the initial goal within a short time but there are still some rather tasty looking stretch goals that would be great to hit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chaos Reborn Kickstarter Launched</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/chaos-reborn-kickstarter-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 06:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/chaos-reborn-kickstarter-launched/</guid>
      <description>After about a year of building a prototype and refining the systems, Julian Gollop has launched a Kickstarter for &amp;ldquo;Chaos Reborn&amp;rdquo;. Gollop has created many brilliant games over the years - &amp;ldquo;Rebelstar&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Laser Squad&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;X-Com&amp;rdquo; to name a few - and now he&amp;rsquo;s returning to one of his first, [&amp;ldquo;Chaos&amp;rdquo;][131]. It will be a turn based affair, set in a fantasy realm with magic and unique creatures, and will feature a variety of multiplayer modes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter for a Bluetooth Speccy</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/22/kickstarter-for-a-bluetooth-speccy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 22:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/22/kickstarter-for-a-bluetooth-speccy/</guid>
      <description>This draft Kickstarter campaign for a Bluetooth ZX Spectrum could be interesting. My old 48K only has a partially function keyboard (I really should get around to getting a new keyboard membrane for it), and Elite&amp;rsquo;s emulation on iOS is generally pretty good so this could be a good way to get a more authentic Speccy experience. I certainly hope that it will be useable as a standard Bluetooth keyboard so other emulators (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contradiction Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/8/contradiction-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 21:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/8/contradiction-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Tim Follin (one of the great composers from the 8/16 bit years) has launched a rather interesting looking Kickstarter campaign for an &amp;ldquo;interactive murder mystery movie&amp;rdquo; called &amp;ldquo;Contradiction&amp;rdquo;. While the game looks to be similar to traditional FMV games, the way the player interacts with it promises to be far more fluid. Murder mysteries are bizarrely under-represented in games and it&amp;rsquo;s a genre that I love dearly, so it&amp;rsquo;s great to see someone taking this on and adding their own twist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slightly Magic Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/slightly-magic-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/slightly-magic-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Colin Jones is probably best known for his excellent rock star management simulation, &amp;ldquo;Rock Star Ate My Hamster&amp;rdquo;, which featured many thinly veiled (rather biting) pop culture references. &amp;ldquo;Slightly Magic&amp;rdquo; was a later creation of his which was always intended to be part of a trilogy of games, but sadly the latter two chapters were never released. Colin is now hoping to resurrect Slightly, starting with an updated version of &amp;ldquo;Slightly Magic&amp;rdquo; followed by two new games to complete the series.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter for a book by Andrew Hewson</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/kickstarter-for-a-book-by-andrew-hewson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 21:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/kickstarter-for-a-book-by-andrew-hewson/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Hewson is running a Kickstarter for a new book detailing his experiences and insights from a long career in videogame development. I&amp;rsquo;m not terribly keen on the title of the book (&amp;ldquo;Hints &amp;amp; Tips for Videogame Pioneers&amp;rdquo;) as it sounds a bit like those &amp;ldquo;Learn how to program C++ in 24 hours!&amp;rdquo; books, but I would love to read his accounts of what was one my favourite software houses of the 80s/90s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deus Ex Machina 2 Kickstarter!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/16/deus-ex-machina-2-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 04:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/16/deus-ex-machina-2-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>As I previously mentioned , a sequel the the amazing &amp;ldquo;Deus Ex Machina&amp;rdquo; is in the works. Well, Mel is now looking for backers to help fund the final stages of production. I&amp;rsquo;m still unsure of just how the game will turn out (the original was more about the experience as a whole, rather than they gameplay itself), but it cannot be overstated how important the original and Mel himself was to the early game scene.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
