<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Developers on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/categories/developers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Developers on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:49:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikekeith.github.io/categories/developers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>St. Bride&#39;s Article</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/7/29/st-brides-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/7/29/st-brides-article/</guid>
      <description>This is a great piece on the mysterious text adventure creators, St Bride&amp;rsquo;s; an edited version of which appeared in GamesTM mag.
I&amp;rsquo;d written about them previously, but this article does a far better job at uncovering their somewhat bizarre story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The return of Magnetic Scrolls? (Sort of)</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/18/the-return-of-magnetic-scrolls-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 06:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/18/the-return-of-magnetic-scrolls-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>Well, this is very interesting indeed. Hugh Steers - a founding member of Magnetic Scrolls - has formed Strand Games along with Stefan Meier (from if-legends.org). Their first release is a a remaster of the classic adventure &amp;ldquo;The Pawn&amp;rdquo;, available for Mac, Win and Linux. Not only that, but they have the support of other Magnetic Scrolls alumni, including Anita Sinclair and Ken Gordon.
I stumbled across their site somewhat randomly - I&amp;rsquo;m a bit surprised it hasn&amp;rsquo;t received more coverage in the retro gaming scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rogue Squadron in Retro Gamer</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/18/rogue-squadron-in-retro-gamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 05:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/18/rogue-squadron-in-retro-gamer/</guid>
      <description>Issue 168 of Retro Gamer (May-ish 2017 - my copy didn&amp;rsquo;t arrive until a week or so into June) has a great article on the &amp;ldquo;Rogue Squadron&amp;rdquo; series of games, complete with a few ramblings from myself. The other people interviewed were my old Factor 5 colleagues Julian Eggebrecht, Jamie Uhrmacher and Chris Crawford, plus Ryan Kaufman who was a level designer at Lucasarts.
I joined Factor 5 soon after &amp;ldquo;Rogue Squadron&amp;rdquo; had been released, and my first game there would be the sadly underrated and somewhat unknown &amp;ldquo;Battle for Naboo&amp;rdquo; - the fact that it was an Episode 1 game right after Star Wars fans worldwide had been punched in the guts by that terrible movie didn&amp;rsquo;t help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blitz Games closes down</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/9/15/blitz-games-closes-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 05:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/9/15/blitz-games-closes-down/</guid>
      <description>Well, this is sad. Blitz Games has closed down after 23 years. The Oliver Twins have been prominent members of the UK games industry since they shot to fame in the 80s for their much loved Dizzy series of games. I&amp;rsquo;ve never met them myself, but everyone I know that has has nothing but glowing things to say about them - they&amp;rsquo;ve been an immense help to many UK developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Woakes interviewed?!</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/5/19/paul-woakes-interviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 21:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/5/19/paul-woakes-interviewed/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the people behind the &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms To Billions&amp;rdquo; doco tweeted something very intriguing indeed:
Latest interview just shot! With the sword of Damocles over our heads we needed a Mercenary to bail us out! What an Encounter that was!
— FrmBedrooms2Billions (@FromBedrooms) May 17, 2013
This is obviously a reference to Novagen, but could this actually mean they interviewed Paul Woakes? As far as I&amp;rsquo;m aware, this would be a first if true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return of the PiMan?</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/5/5/return-of-the-piman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 20:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/5/5/return-of-the-piman/</guid>
      <description>I have no idea how this managed to escape my attention for so long, but it appears Mel Croucher has relaunched Automata. According to the site, not only is Deus Ex Machina 2 on the way, but also remakes of PiMania and even Thanatos. The latter is interesting seeing as I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure Croucher had nothing to do with the original.
The original Deus Ex Machina was quite easily one of the most incredible game experiences I had during that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St Brides</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/4/23/st-brides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 04:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/4/23/st-brides/</guid>
      <description>St Brides were easily one of those most intriguing software houses of the 80s. For a start they produced some great adventures games - &amp;ldquo;The Very Big Cave Adventure&amp;rdquo; was my first exposure to them, which I remember fondly. Their games were known for being well written with a keen sense of humour. Then there was the fact that they appeared to be a company consisting entirely of women (quite unique in the industry), as they were generally referred to as &amp;ldquo;the sisters&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;the ladies&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;the belles&amp;rdquo;/etc of St Brides (to what extent this was actually the case, I&amp;rsquo;m unsure).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
