<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>November on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/november/</link>
    <description>Recent content in November on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:28:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/november/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/11/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/11/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Simon Byron announced he was stepping down to work at a chip shop on the outskirts of Bognor: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that the life of a simple chippy is preferable to slogging my guts out on Britain&amp;rsquo;s least popular Amiga games magazine.&amp;rdquo; Andy Nuttall would be filling in as Acting Editor.
Frustrating times for Amiga journos and fans alike as there was still no news from Commodore on the future of the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/11/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 03:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/11/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The CD32 launch hadn&amp;rsquo;t exactly gotten off to a great start, with sales looking rather lacklustre. To try to turn things around Commodore kicked off a marketing push starting with a big presence at the Live &amp;lsquo;93 exhibition and an upcoming TV advert. Satellite stations would be targeted first before switching to ITV and C4 over the Christmas period. Apparently Live &amp;lsquo;93 was such a big hit that Commodore had already booked its presence at next year&amp;rsquo;s event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/11/16/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 04:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/11/16/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Ocean had scored a #1 hit last Christmas with ”WWF Wrestlemania”, and hoped for a repeat in the form of ”WWF European Rampage”. While the earlier title had been panned by critics, the publisher were adamant this one would be better.
Commodore had announced the A4000 which, with a £1999 price tag, was very much targeted at the serious user. This fuelled rumours of a more affordable gaming machine and right as the mag went to press it looked like they had news&amp;hellip; though that would have to wait until next month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/11/16/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 07:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/11/16/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News A new computer was about to be unleashed on Europe which boasted specs that certainly beat the 8bits, but also - apparently - rivaled the Amiga and ST. While that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem terribly exciting, it did have one interesting feature: the ability to run most Speccy games. The SAM Coupe was due to launch in the UK on November 20th.
With Christmas around the corner, Hewson were to release a couple of compilations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Games Revisited</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/30/november-games-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 07:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/30/november-games-revisited/</guid>
      <description>I had hoped to have a number of opportunities to spend some quality time playing these games (and more) this month, but one of the downsides of travelling so much for business is that such occasions are rare. Very rare in the case of this month: I managed a pathetic few hours last Sunday.
At any rate&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief look back at a few games that hit the shelves in November many years ago to rave reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 08:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Gary Penn trumpeted the success of Zzap!, saying that it had become the &amp;ldquo;biggest selling Commodore magazine in the civilised World.&amp;rdquo; The healthy sales meant more advertisers, which meant more content - this month the mag hit 148 pages.
A Commodore show took place in Manchester. Commodore did have a stand (which apparently bore a resemblance to Parisian public toilets), where they were showing off was the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 08:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News It was Superman vs Batman as to who would have the better game. Tynesoft delivering the former, while Ocean took on the latter. Early indications were that Batman had the edge.
Loricel&amp;rsquo;s next attempt to crack the UK would come in the form of Porsche racing game &amp;ldquo;944 Turbo Cup&amp;rdquo;. Driver Rene Metge (&amp;ldquo;who?&amp;rdquo; asked C&amp;amp;VG) provided the endorsement and the software house hoped to include a model car in the box, but apparently British retailers weren&amp;rsquo;t so keen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/11/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 07:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/11/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Microprose&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;F-15 Strike Eagle&amp;rdquo; was about to land on the ST. The ST would also get a port of Mirrorsoft&amp;rsquo;s flightsim featuring a somewhat older aircraft, &amp;ldquo;Spitfire 40&amp;rdquo;.
Viz were working on &amp;ldquo;Werewolves of London&amp;rdquo;.
For the first time since being bought out by Mastertronic, Melbourne House announced its upcoming titles: &amp;ldquo;Roadwars&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rockford&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pulse Warrior&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Street Hassle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Metropolis&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kelly X&amp;rdquo; (I was unable to find any sign that the latter two were released, at least not under those names).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News This issue came complete with a pair of red/blue 3D glasses and to use when reading the &amp;ldquo;3D Tips Supplement&amp;rdquo;.
Incentive Software&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Graphic Adventure Creator Plus&amp;rdquo; was due in the coming month. This new version would allow games to use a disc-access system - similar to Infocom&amp;rsquo;s games - which would allow much bigger adventures. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure if this was actually released.
Level 9 unveiled their latest adventure, &amp;ldquo;Gnome Ranger&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 23:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw C&amp;amp;VG turn 5 years old and to celebrate they had a bunch of special features, including a Spectrum listing by Steve Turner&amp;rsquo;s dad.
Microsphere revealed their next game would be &amp;ldquo;Contact Sam Cruise&amp;rdquo;, which was inspired by classic private eye movies. There was also a hint that there might be something for fans of &amp;ldquo;Skool Daze&amp;rdquo; at Christmas.
Arioalasoft got the licenses for two Hanna-Barbera cartoons: &amp;ldquo;The Centurions&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Challenge of the Gobots&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Elite announced &amp;ldquo;Scooby-Doo in the Castle Mystery&amp;rdquo;, teasing gamers with a couple of amazing looking screens. It promised to provide cartoon like quality graphics but the game then promptly disappeared, only to resurface some time later as a very good, but very different game developed for Elite by Gargoyle Games.
Christian Urqhart (programmer behind games like &amp;ldquo;Daley Thompson&amp;rsquo;s Decathlon&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hunchback&amp;rdquo;) had left Ocean and formed his own company, Alphabatim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News The Crash staff, along with all the other Newsfield folk, went down to London for the launch party of their new magazine, LM. The venue was the Camden Palace and plenty of gaming bigwigs were in attendance. Sadly the magazine failed to gain much traction, folding after only a handful of issues.
The release of Amstrad&amp;rsquo;s Spectrum +2 had many scratching their heads. Despite the official release having taken place in September, people were unable to find any in shops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News After months of speculation, Amstrad finally revealed their 16bit Sinclair. It was not, as many thought, a games console, but a rather unimpressive PC. The reception was luke warm at best: &amp;ldquo;is Amstrad&amp;rsquo;s Sinclair a powerless business computer or a games machine that&amp;rsquo;s unsuitable for games?&amp;rdquo;
Meanwhile, excitement was riding high for the Konix console. The release date was to be January 28th and would include a bunch of add ons, including the hydraulic chair.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
