<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>February on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/february/</link>
    <description>Recent content in February on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/february/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/3/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/3/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Andy Nuttall officially took over the Editor role.
If you thought that the future of Commodore would be sorted out by this month, then you were sorely mistaken. The end did seem in sight (something that had been said for nearly a year), with only Commodore UK and US-based CEI remaining in the running. Meanwhile retailers were getting frustrated with the lack of new stock. With that said, apparently 82% of stores surveyed were keen to continue selling the machines (if they were provided some to sell&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/2/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 06:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/2/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Editor David Upchurch saw a bright 1994 ahead for the Amiga.
Word on the street was that Commodore UK were close to striking a deal with LucasArts that would see them bring their PC hits &amp;ldquo;Rebel Assault&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Day of the Tentacle&amp;rdquo; to the CD32. (It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen)
While England had suffered the shame of failing to qualify for the upcoming World Cup, Virgin were keen to join with Adidas to sponsor a new initiative to promote youth footballing skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/2/27/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 07:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/2/27/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Under the headline &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3 Shocker!&amp;rdquo; came the news that Dino Dini had parted ways with Anco and signed with Virgin to develop a &amp;ldquo;world-beating follow-up to &amp;lsquo;Kick Off 2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;, with the working title &amp;ldquo;Goal!&amp;rdquo;. The move cast doubts on whether there would be an official &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3&amp;rdquo;, though co-designer Steve Screech remained at Anco.
From the ashes of the hyped &amp;ldquo;Apocalypse&amp;rdquo;, Jason Perkins and Robin Levy were continuing their partnership on a new game from Renegade, &amp;ldquo;Ruff n&amp;rsquo; Tumble&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;90</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/2/8/this-month-in-cvg-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 07:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/2/8/this-month-in-cvg-90/</guid>
      <description>News Code Masters unveiled their fancy new CD compilations for the Spectrum and C64. The package included a computer interface to connect your regular CD player and the CD-ROM containing 30 Code Masters games. The Spectrum version was able to load games in under a minute, while the C64 utilised the stereo audio signal to encode a timing track enabling even quicker load times. C&amp;amp;VG marvelled at the possibilities: &amp;ldquo;Imagine a game with minutes of digitised speech or amazing digitised graphics!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 06:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn responded to grumblings from readers about the Christmas issue. The main complaints were around the lack of reviews and the price. The former issue was hardly the magazine’s fault as publisher’s were taking any morsel of time they could get in order to get games on the shelves for the Christmas shoppers.
Electric Dreams/Activision had a whopping dozen licensed arcade conversions heading to the C64. They included: &amp;ldquo;Tempest” (unreleased?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/23/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 08:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/23/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Death Stalks the Night&amp;rdquo; was an upcoming arcade adventure from Ubi Soft where the player assumed the role as Count Dracula to take on “the usual Van Helsings”.
New software house EAS announced a space trading game called &amp;ldquo;STAG&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST.
Mr Chip’s &amp;ldquo;Wrangler&amp;rdquo;would see the player take control over Clint Eastwood (yes, apparently) and his ‘droid in what looked like a puzzle game.
Budget label Alternative were moving into the 16bits with Don Priestly’s &amp;ldquo;Mad Flunky”, a follow-up to his Spectrum game &amp;ldquo;Flunky”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News This month&amp;rsquo;s editorial warned readers to expect some divisive reviews. Not divisive in that reviewers were unable to agree, but in the sense that they had some truly great games, some utterly awful, and few in between. So some &amp;ldquo;savage criticism&amp;rdquo; was in store.
One amusing aspect of the editorial is that Roger Kean seemed quite bothered by the fact that a reader had written in to complain about Kean&amp;rsquo;s assertion that the C64&amp;rsquo;s xmas release schedule was &amp;ldquo;disappointing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 23:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw Eugene Lacey take over as editor. Lacey came from editing Commodore User, and had been a C&amp;amp;VG staff writer sometime earlier.
Go!&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bedlam&amp;rdquo; promised arcade action featuring up to 18 aliens at any one time.
Sega&amp;rsquo;s Master System recently launched in the UK and now a slew of titles were heading its way. These included: &amp;ldquo;Kung-Kid&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Fantasy Zone II&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;After Burner&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Global Defense&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Zaxxon 3D&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alien Syndrome&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rescue &amp;amp; Mission&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Zillion II: The Tri Formation&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alex Kidd: The Lost Stars&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Boys Monster Land&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Cube Zone&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Maze Hunter 3D&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 02:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News This issue would see the introduction of a new (potentially controversial) regular section: a roundup of Amiga games.
GO!, a sublabel of US Gold, won the rights to release conversions of 10 of Capcom&amp;rsquo;s upcoming arcade machines.
Mastertronic signed a deal with Japanese arcade company Technos for the rights to all current and future releases. First up would be &amp;ldquo;Double Dragon&amp;rdquo;.
Features Julian Rignall and Steve Jarratt visited Britsh Airways&amp;rsquo; Flight Crew Training Centre to check out the state of the art in flight simulators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/14/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 21:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/14/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News The Robot Society of America was offering newly signed up members the chance to win an &amp;ldquo;experimental sound-activated robot&amp;rdquo; kit. Membership was $50 per year.
Bug Byte was to release old Virgin games under its budget label. &amp;ldquo;Strangeloop&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Falcon Patrol II&amp;rdquo; were among the first batch.
Also getting in on the budget action was newcomer Alternative Software with releases such as &amp;ldquo;Howzat&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Henry&amp;rsquo;s Hoard&amp;rdquo;. Not exactly the most thrilling line up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 05:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News Atari Games (not to be confused with hardware manufacturer, Atari) sued Nintendo for $100 million over the inability to publish games for the NES without going through the Japanese company. Nintendo seemed unphased by the move, saying that they had never lost a lawsuit.
Confusion reigned over the specifics for the Konix Slipstream. TGM attempted to clear things up by confirming that it would retail at £150 (or slightly higher), have a set of peripherals (hydraulic chair, light gun, 3D helmet), some of which would be included with the console (not the chair!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 05:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Graeme Kidd lamented the glut of poor games with big movie, TV and arcade licenses attached. Were game developers spending too much time and money on the licenses while neglecting the actual games? And was this just a temporary phase or would it become a trend?
Crash made some changes to their review system: reviews would now be signed, and the rated categories were massaged (Getting Started and Use Of Computer were replaced by Presentation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/9/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 01:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/9/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Andrew Braybrook revealed his new game, &amp;ldquo;Uridium&amp;rdquo;. It promised &amp;ldquo;super- fast scrolling and authentically addictive action&amp;rdquo; and would certainly end up delivering.
Infocom slashed the prices on several of their games for a Christmas promotion. &amp;ldquo;Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide To The Galaxy&amp;rdquo; would drop to £24.95, while others would be between £14 and £22.
Two schoolboys raised £80 for famine relief in Ethiopia by playing games for 24 hours. The games included &amp;ldquo;Castle Quest&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alien 8&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Revs&amp;rdquo;, all on their BBC which apparently &amp;ldquo;did get a bit hot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
