<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1993 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/1993/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1993 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 07:27:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/1993/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/12/17/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 07:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/12/17/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Editor David Upchurch had “deserted” the mag for a couple of months which left Simon Byron in charge.
The CD32 received some encouraging news as high street retailer Menzies announced they would be stocking it in time for Christmas.
After some months of silence (on the Amiga at any rate), Thalamus was about to release “S.U.B.” (unreleased). The One wondered what had happened to “Arsenal” - rumour was the programmer had gone missing&amp;hellip; It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see the light of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/11/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 03:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/11/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The CD32 launch hadn&amp;rsquo;t exactly gotten off to a great start, with sales looking rather lacklustre. To try to turn things around Commodore kicked off a marketing push starting with a big presence at the Live &amp;lsquo;93 exhibition and an upcoming TV advert. Satellite stations would be targeted first before switching to ITV and C4 over the Christmas period. Apparently Live &amp;lsquo;93 was such a big hit that Commodore had already booked its presence at next year&amp;rsquo;s event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/10/30/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 07:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/10/30/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Renegade&amp;rsquo;s release schedule was looking rather impressive with “Uridium 2” first up, followed soon after by “Turrican 3” and “Elfmania”. If that wasn’t enough, “Ruff ‘n’ Tumble”, “Sensible World of Soccer”, “Flight of the Amazon Queen” and “Z”) were all due by the end of the year. The last one - a real time strategy game from the Bitmap Brothers - was particularly interesting since it’d be years before it saw the light of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/9/29/zlkv83ofoauysfxxv490x1maf0etuj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 06:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/9/29/zlkv83ofoauysfxxv490x1maf0etuj/</guid>
      <description>News In an effort to draw some attention away from the other popular gaming mascots, Mindscape decided to enter &amp;ldquo;Alfred the Chicken&amp;rdquo; in the Christchurch by-election. Alfred managed to bring in 18 votes - two ahead of the Rainbow Alliance Party. The resulting media &amp;ldquo;circus&amp;rdquo; was certainly worth the 500 quid it cost them.
Europress teased some screen shots of racing sim &amp;ldquo;Rally&amp;rdquo;, though they were from the PC version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/8/28/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 08:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/8/28/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News A year after announcing they were leaving the Amiga behind, news arrived that Sierra On-Line were bringing &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Quest VI&amp;rdquo; to our beloved machine. The conversion was being handled by Charles Cecil&amp;rsquo;s Revolution which had created a hybrid of its &amp;ldquo;Virtual Theatre&amp;rdquo; system for the job to ensure the game felt at home on the system, rather than some shoddy PC port.
Krisalis spawned a new sub-label, Buzz, as home for its back catalogue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/7/31/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 07:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/7/31/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The first images of the fighters in Team 17&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Body Blows 2&amp;rdquo; surfaced.
Domark snapped up the rights to the F1 championship, with the appropriately named &amp;ldquo;F1&amp;rdquo; being the first title out the door.
The infamous &amp;ldquo;Night Trap&amp;rdquo; had resulted in politicians &amp;amp; law makers wanting to create a new mandatory classification scheme for games.
After Ocean signed a large deal with them, Digital Image Design revealed two upcoming games: &amp;ldquo;TFX&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Inferno: The Odyssey Continues&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/6/23/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 05:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/6/23/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The Amiga had a strong showing at this year&amp;rsquo;s Golden Joysticks awards. Team 17 and Sensible Software won Software House of the Year and Computer Game of the Year respectively, with Jon Hare giving a &amp;ldquo;stirring speech warning against the dangers of complacency.&amp;rdquo; The Amiga related winners were:
Software House of the Year: Team 17 Computer Game of the Year: &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; Sensible Software Best Licensed Computer Game: &amp;ldquo;Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis&amp;rdquo; LucasArts Programming Team of the Year: LucasArts Best Computer Simulation: &amp;ldquo;Formula One Grand Prix&amp;rdquo; Geoff Crammond/Microprose Team 17 announced two new titles, both racing games: &amp;ldquo;Overdrive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;F1 Challenge&amp;rdquo; (the latter would be renamed to &amp;ldquo;F17 Challenge&amp;rdquo; after some legal issues).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/4/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/4/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News I&amp;rsquo;m guessing this was an April Fools joke, but the lead news story concerned PC game &amp;ldquo;X-Wing&amp;rdquo; appearing &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; the Amiga&amp;hellip; as in, it was a photo of an &amp;ldquo;X-Wing&amp;rdquo; box sitting on an Amiga&amp;hellip;
Mindscape revealed that their upcoming Gameboy platformer &amp;ldquo;Alfred Chicken&amp;rdquo; would be getting an Amiga release.
Ocean reckoned that the somewhat crowded car racer genre was in need of something with a bit more realism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/3/18/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 07:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/3/18/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Comic artist Dave Gibbons (of &amp;ldquo;Watchmen&amp;rdquo; fame) had been collaborating with Charles Cecil and Revolution Software on the cyberpunk point-and-click adventure &amp;ldquo;Beneath a Steel Sky&amp;rdquo;. It transpired that his involvement came about after he contacted The One to complain they&amp;rsquo;d forgotten to credit him for &amp;ldquo;Watchmen&amp;rdquo;. The mag decided to lend him an Amiga and a copy of &amp;ldquo;Deluxe Paint&amp;rdquo; for a followup article, which sparked his interest in computer art and lead to an introduction to Cecil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/2/27/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 07:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/2/27/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Under the headline &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3 Shocker!&amp;rdquo; came the news that Dino Dini had parted ways with Anco and signed with Virgin to develop a &amp;ldquo;world-beating follow-up to &amp;lsquo;Kick Off 2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;, with the working title &amp;ldquo;Goal!&amp;rdquo;. The move cast doubts on whether there would be an official &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3&amp;rdquo;, though co-designer Steve Screech remained at Anco.
From the ashes of the hyped &amp;ldquo;Apocalypse&amp;rdquo;, Jason Perkins and Robin Levy were continuing their partnership on a new game from Renegade, &amp;ldquo;Ruff n&amp;rsquo; Tumble&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/1/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 06:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/1/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Digital Image Design had two new titles on the way. The first up was a &amp;ldquo;pseudo-sequel&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Epic&amp;rdquo; - called &amp;ldquo;Odyssey&amp;rdquo; - set 90 years further in the future and would feature more of an open world feel. Sadly it looks like it was never released.. The second was another sequel, jet fighter sim &amp;ldquo;TFX Inferno&amp;rdquo;.
Relative newcomer Miracle Games were rather bullish about their upcoming platformer, &amp;ldquo;Miracle Bat&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
