<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zzap64 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/zzap64/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zzap64 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 22:37:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/zzap64/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zzap!64 Annual 2019 Kickstarter launched</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/4/29/zzap64-annual-2019-kickstarter-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 22:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/4/29/zzap64-annual-2019-kickstarter-launched/</guid>
      <description>The folks behind last year&amp;rsquo;s rather excellent Crash Annual are back. Chris Wilkins, Roger Kean and Oli Frey have teamed up once again, this time to resurrect Crash&amp;rsquo;s sister mag, Zzap!64, for an annual due out towards the end of the year.
I must admit I didn&amp;rsquo;t read the Kickstarter pitch or even watch the video before backing it as there was no question in my mind, so it was only through seeing people discussing it online that I realised that the likes of Mel Croucher, Julian Rignall and Robin Hogg were also involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/8/27/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 07:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/8/27/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn bid farewell as he strode off &amp;ldquo;on a secret mission&amp;rdquo;. Ciaran Brennan was to take the reins, with Julian Rignall as his assistant. Phillipa Irving&amp;rsquo;s war game section took a break as she was busy with exams. There was also a small change to the review format, with the &amp;ldquo;Value&amp;rdquo; rating being dropped.
Arnie&amp;rsquo;s latest film &amp;ldquo;Predator&amp;rdquo; had grossed $12 million at the box office in its first 3 days and Activision had signed the license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/7/16/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 06:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/7/16/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Software Projects announced that they were reducing their prices to £5.95 in the run up to Christmas. Others were expected to follow suit, though that did seem somewhat unlikely as that’s a steep drop down from £9.95. Gary Penn pondered how lower prices might affect the quality of games - lower budgets for development? less licensed tie-ins? (The latter was considered a good thing)
Ciaran Brennan was promoted to Assistant Editor, and Gary Liddon was due to make his return next month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 08:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Firebird closed a deal with Activision/Electric Dreams which would see the budget publisher re-releasing a slew of older titles from the US for £1.99 each.
No changes at Zzap! this month, though Julian Rignall got engaged to Glenys Powell, the “ever-effervescent” Editorial Assistant.
Zzap! launched in Italy. Note the lack of “64” - Speccy, Atari, MSX and C16 gamers would all be catered for.
The Sensi Software lads were wrapping up their next game: the awesome &amp;ldquo;Wizball”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/5/15/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/5/15/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Thanks to a tweet from Julian Rignall I finally noticed that the ships getting blown up by Zzap!64 on the cover represented Commodore User &amp;amp; C&amp;amp;VG. Cheeky.
The reason for such a cover? Sales had climbed to 67,728 per month and showed no signs of letting up. The mag would be undergoing a few changes - they looked to be broadening the scope of what they were covering, including “unusual, but relevant” features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 07:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News A couple of new arrivals at Zzap! this month, with Steve Jarratt swapping industrial chemistry for games journalism and Philipa Irving who, er, swapped Crash for its Newsfield sibling.
Ariolasoft’s Starlight label had three games on the way. &amp;ldquo;Dogfight 2187&amp;rdquo; promised 3D wireframe shoot ‘em up action with a vertically split screen giving two views of the action. The other two games were &amp;ldquo;Deathscape&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Greyfell”. Meanwhile Tony Crowther had teamed up with Keith Blake and Ross Goodley to develop ”Challenge of the Gobots” based on the popular kids cartoon, which would be published by Ariolasoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/3/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 07:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/3/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn wrote a long editorial on a matter that had been on a lot of people’s minds: had quality and innovation taken a dive as software houses relied more and more on coin-op, TV and film licenses? The market seemed to be full of these unimaginative and often shoddy tie ins which, aside from the attached IP, only had good presentation going for them. Developers were feeling the pinch as well: publishers would “guarantee 100,000” copies sold, giving them an excuse to lower royalties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/2/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 06:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/2/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn responded to grumblings from readers about the Christmas issue. The main complaints were around the lack of reviews and the price. The former issue was hardly the magazine’s fault as publisher’s were taking any morsel of time they could get in order to get games on the shelves for the Christmas shoppers.
Electric Dreams/Activision had a whopping dozen licensed arcade conversions heading to the C64. They included: &amp;ldquo;Tempest” (unreleased?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/1/25/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 08:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/1/25/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Gary Penn lamented the fact that for the first time there had not been a single Sizzler or Gold Medal awarded in an issue. Well, that’s not entirely true as &amp;ldquo;The Bard’s Tale&amp;rdquo; picked up a very respectable Sizzler, though apparently it didn’t count as it was “a role playing game”. It seemed that software houses were spending as much time as possible before Christmas to polish up their hopeful hits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 04:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News More changes were afoot, with Strategy Front writer Sean Masterson moving on and the start of a make over that would take effect during the next few months.
Last month Zzap! teased readers by asking them to check out a screenshot of the hotly anticipated arcade conversion of &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; and then failed to print it. To make up for the error they provided not one but four shots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/11/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 08:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/11/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Gary Penn trumpeted the success of Zzap!, saying that it had become the &amp;ldquo;biggest selling Commodore magazine in the civilised World.&amp;rdquo; The healthy sales meant more advertisers, which meant more content - this month the mag hit 148 pages.
A Commodore show took place in Manchester. Commodore did have a stand (which apparently bore a resemblance to Parisian public toilets), where they were showing off was the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Parallax&#34; Re-visited</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/10/24/parallax-re-visited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 07:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/10/24/parallax-re-visited/</guid>
      <description>Parallax Sensible Software/Ocean, 1986 This month in 1986 saw Sensible&amp;rsquo;s first big title reviewed in Zzap!64, scoring a very respectable 93% overall and receiving a Sizzler.
Over the past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to remember where I first saw &amp;ldquo;Parallax&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; I want to say it was at my friend Neil&amp;rsquo;s house, but did he even have a C64?? I know he had a Spectrum and later an Amiga&amp;hellip; Maybe it was someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/10/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 04:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/10/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News An article appeared in the Canberra Times in which a Mr Paul Gathercoal blathered on about the evils of games. Mr Gathercoal firmly believed games were corrupting the minds of children, driving them to lives of robberies, killing and masturbation. He claimed that playing &amp;ldquo;Franke Goes To Hollywood&amp;rdquo; would lead to &amp;ldquo;pill-popping&amp;rdquo;. What utter nonsense.
Gary Liddon had buggered off to Newsfield&amp;rsquo;s new software house, Thalamus, and a call went out to find someone to replace him at Zzap!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 09:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News More staffing changes at the magazine this month. Roger Kean was moving over to a new Newsfield mag called L.M., with Gary Penn stepping in to the Editor role. There were three new faces with Richard &amp;ldquo;Dick&amp;rdquo; Eddy, Jonathan Rignall (Julian&amp;rsquo;s younger brother) and Massimo Valducci starting.
Beyond announced the upcoming release of not one but two Denton Design games: &amp;ldquo;Dante’s Inferno&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Infodroid&amp;rdquo;.
Meanwhile, Beyond had managed to secure the first ever Star Trek license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/8/20/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 06:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/8/20/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Liddon was leaving Zzap! to join Newsfield&amp;rsquo;s new software house, Thalamus, as Technical Executive. The company was headed by ex-Activision Press Officer Andrew Wright. The first game was due to be released in September on the C64 and Spectrum, with an Amstrad version following.
Gremlin were readying four new titles in time for Christmas: &amp;ldquo;Pentacle&amp;rdquo; (unreleased?), &amp;ldquo;Future Knight&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Bounder II&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Trailblazer&amp;rdquo;.
Arkana&amp;rsquo;s BBC game &amp;ldquo;Powerplay&amp;rdquo; was heading to the C64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/7/14/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/7/14/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News The Commodore Show in London was the biggest dedicated C64 event of the year. Zzap!&amp;rsquo;s own booth proved very popular - especially when games programmers dropped by to show off their latest wares (often yet to be signed to a publisher). So why weren&amp;rsquo;t the crowds impressed with the show? It seemed software houses were very thin on the ground&amp;hellip;
Tony Takoushi was at the show touting a new gizmo called &amp;ldquo;Speedos&amp;rdquo; which was a mod for 1541 floppy drives enabling much faster load times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/6/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 08:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/6/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Antony Jacobson wrote a withering attack on Zzap! and Crash in Computer Trade Weekly. It really was oddly vitriolic and included such gems as: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; a certain kind of magazine should only be handled with rubber gloves and antiseptic fire tongs. No-one forces them to publish contagious rubbish but magazines that do so are not simply to be described as boring, but debasing the values of their readership&amp;hellip; and polluting the social and commercial environment in which we live and work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/5/31/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 08:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/5/31/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News A rather triumphant Zzap! boasted about the latest ABC figures which showed it was the &amp;ldquo;leading magazine in the field&amp;rdquo;. Sister publication Crash did even better, not only beating rival Sinclair User but also C&amp;amp;VG, which meant it was the best selling computer title of any kind in the UK.
In the same editorial, Roger Kean lamented the recent trend of game releases being pushed back. The common excuse for delays seemed to be &amp;ldquo;programming complexity&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 01:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Roger Kean pondered whether the games industry &amp;ldquo;coming of age&amp;rdquo; after 5-ish years with the conglomeration of software houses and the emergence of a small number of dominating companies was a good thing. On the one hand it did mean developers were able to focus more on creating games rather than managing the marketing and distribution, but on the other the desire to get as many games on the shelves as possible was putting a real strain on quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 06:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Commodore announced they were closing their Corby factory and ceasing the manufacture of the 64 in Britain. Was this a sign of bigger troubles? The price of the C64 remained higher than that of competitors, and rather than address this, Commodore had introduced the C16 - but what did this actually solve?
English Software were finally about to release &amp;ldquo;Elektra Glide&amp;rdquo; on the C64 - some months after the original Atari version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/2/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/2/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News This month&amp;rsquo;s editorial warned readers to expect some divisive reviews. Not divisive in that reviewers were unable to agree, but in the sense that they had some truly great games, some utterly awful, and few in between. So some &amp;ldquo;savage criticism&amp;rdquo; was in store.
One amusing aspect of the editorial is that Roger Kean seemed quite bothered by the fact that a reader had written in to complain about Kean&amp;rsquo;s assertion that the C64&amp;rsquo;s xmas release schedule was &amp;ldquo;disappointing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/8/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 05:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/8/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Perhaps the biggest news for Zzap! readers this month was that Julian Rignall had left Newsfield to take up freelancing (including for rival publisher EMAP). Gordon Houghton took over as editor, and there were quite a few changes (mainly cosmetic, but also an expanded news section for a start).
Mastertronic had a bunch of upcoming releases planned: &amp;ldquo;Rogue&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;World Darts&amp;rdquo; (may have become &amp;ldquo;180&amp;rdquo;), &amp;ldquo;Night Racer&amp;rdquo; and a re-release of Activision&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/7/27/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 07:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/7/27/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Mastertronic was to release a followup to &amp;ldquo;Kane&amp;rdquo;, unsurprisingly called &amp;ldquo;Kane II&amp;rdquo;.
Up until this point Microprose&amp;rsquo;s games had been distributed in the UK by US Gold, but now they were going to handle it all themselves. This would allow them to use much fancier packaging, for starters.
Tynesoft and Virgin were both readying new compilations.
Elite started a new budget label, Encore, which would see their back catalogue classics re-released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 07:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News The &amp;ldquo;silly season&amp;rdquo; was upon us with new releases rather sparse as programmers/software houses focussed their sights on Christmas.
Kevin Toms was putting the finishing touches on the long awaited &amp;ldquo;Football Manager II&amp;rdquo;.
Domark were producing &amp;ldquo;Live and Let Die&amp;rdquo;, a game based on Roger Moore&amp;rsquo;s first Bond film.
&amp;ldquo;Barbarian II&amp;rdquo; was due for release in August and promised a &amp;ldquo;multiload extravaganza&amp;rdquo; with a large, mappable area.
In last month&amp;rsquo;s review of &amp;ldquo;Stealth Mission&amp;rdquo;, Zzap!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This (er, last) month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/6/1/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 07:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/6/1/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>I managed to miss May by one day - mea culpa.
News Julian Rignall defended the status of the C64 in light of the recently arrived 16bit machines, citing the strength of recent release compared to rather disappointing 16bit titles: &amp;ldquo;To me, the Commodore 64 is leading the way when it comes to new ideas - Driller, the up-and-coming Echelon, Apollo 18, Nebulus, Soko Ban and Deflektor are recent examples that inject new life and innovation into the computer game format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/4/15/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 06:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/4/15/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Gordon Leslie Houghton was the newest person to join the Zzap!64 writing team.
Hard to know whether Zzap! fell for an April fools, or were behind it themselves, but they carried a news story about a Norwegian firm creating a C64 add-on that would turn the humble 64 into an Amiga. The &amp;ldquo;Amulator&amp;rdquo; was being made by Blue Tec and would cost around £280.
Features Martin Walker had just finished off &amp;ldquo;Hunter&amp;rsquo;s Moon&amp;rdquo; and had embarked on a new dev diary for his next (yet to be decided) game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/3/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 06:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/3/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News A fresh faced 18yr old Paul Glancey joined the Zzap!64 team.
Features Julian Rignall and Steve Jarratt popped along to the 44th Amusement Trade Exhibition International to check out the latest arcade machines.
Sci-fi films and TV had taken a stab at many predictions of the future of computers over the previous 35 years, and Zzap!64 cast a critical eye over them.
Zzap!64 visited the offices of Digital Pictures to drool over their high power CG machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/2/22/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 02:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/2/22/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News This issue would see the introduction of a new (potentially controversial) regular section: a roundup of Amiga games.
GO!, a sublabel of US Gold, won the rights to release conversions of 10 of Capcom&amp;rsquo;s upcoming arcade machines.
Mastertronic signed a deal with Japanese arcade company Technos for the rights to all current and future releases. First up would be &amp;ldquo;Double Dragon&amp;rdquo;.
Features Julian Rignall and Steve Jarratt visited Britsh Airways&amp;rsquo; Flight Crew Training Centre to check out the state of the art in flight simulators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Rather oddly there was no news section, despite it being a bumper issue. Perhaps this was a change of direction now that Julian Rignall was editor?
Features Jon Hare provided a run down of how to use SEUCK.
A bunch of joysticks were reviewed. The Competition Pro 5000 came out on top.
The Harlequin looked back on what was a bit of a lacklustre year for adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 03:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Ciaran Brennan had only just taken over the helm at ZZap! but he was already moving onto pastures new. This ushered in Julian Rignall as editor.
US Gold acquired the rights to the &amp;ldquo;Rolling Thunder&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Roadblasters&amp;rdquo; coin ops. Meanwhile, the publisher dropped the price of all of their C64 disk games from £14.99 to £11.99 (thanks to economies of scale).
Telecomsoft scored a bit of a coup, signing Graftgold away from Hewson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News This issue came complete with a pair of red/blue 3D glasses and to use when reading the &amp;ldquo;3D Tips Supplement&amp;rdquo;.
Incentive Software&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Graphic Adventure Creator Plus&amp;rdquo; was due in the coming month. This new version would allow games to use a disc-access system - similar to Infocom&amp;rsquo;s games - which would allow much bigger adventures. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure if this was actually released.
Level 9 unveiled their latest adventure, &amp;ldquo;Gnome Ranger&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/10/19/this-month-in-zzap-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 00:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/10/19/this-month-in-zzap-87/</guid>
      <description>News The Audit Bureau of Circulations report showed that Zzap!&amp;rsquo;s readership had reached an impressive 77,483 in the first 6 months of the year.
Delta4 re-surfaced as Abstract Concepts and Fergus McNeil was busy working on a new fancy adventure system.
The next game from Stavros Fasoulas under the Thalamus label would be &amp;ldquo;Quedex&amp;rdquo;.
Features Part one of a series on the history of the shoot&amp;rsquo;em up.
Andrew Braybrook&amp;rsquo;s development diary of &amp;ldquo;Morpheus&amp;rdquo; drew to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 02:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Sensible Software signed to Outlaw, Palace Software&amp;rsquo;s new label. The first game the sensi chaps would deliver was &amp;ldquo;Shoot&amp;rsquo;em Up Construction Kit&amp;rdquo; (or SEUCK as it came to be known as).
A game based on Jeffrey Archer&amp;rsquo;s first novel, &amp;ldquo;Not a Penny More, Not a Penny Less&amp;rdquo; was in the works. Meanwhile, Archer had been busy in a highly publicised court case and had just been acquitted.
There was a &amp;ldquo;Ten Things You Never Knew About Mark Cale&amp;rdquo; section (head of System 3).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
