<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1994 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1994/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1994 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1994/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/12/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/12/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News While there was still no news on the fate of Commodore, the UK office was busy preparing for the World of Commodore show, which was to take place at the Wembley Exhibition Centre, December 9th through 11th. It was to be a “buying show” where the primary goal was for attendees to do a bit of shopping, but The One wondered if there’d be any Commodore kit left to purchase by then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/11/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/11/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Simon Byron announced he was stepping down to work at a chip shop on the outskirts of Bognor: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that the life of a simple chippy is preferable to slogging my guts out on Britain&amp;rsquo;s least popular Amiga games magazine.&amp;rdquo; Andy Nuttall would be filling in as Acting Editor.
Frustrating times for Amiga journos and fans alike as there was still no news from Commodore on the future of the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/9/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/9/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News After reporting that the saga of Commodore&amp;rsquo;s fate would be resolved &amp;ldquo;any day now&amp;rdquo; for the past few months, The One decided to quit guessing the timeline. In the latest twist, word arrived Commodore UK (lead by David Pleasance and Colin Proudfoot) were now the favourites with their proposal of a Management Buy Out, with Samsung apparently still keen. At the US head office Mehdi Ali was officially out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 08:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>theone199408
News While Commodore was still without a buyer, word leaked that the company leading the pack was in fact Samsung who were looking to gain more of a foothold in the European market. It seemed everything was hanging on that deal.
Dominik Diamond was rumoured to be returning to &amp;ldquo;Gamesmaster&amp;rdquo;.
A report from Mintel showed that the UK games industry contracted by 4% last year. The market value in 1993 was £670 million compared to £700 million in 1992.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/7/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/7/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News The fate of Commodore UK was close to becoming a bit clearer with an announcement regarding a new owner was due &amp;ldquo;any day now&amp;rdquo;. The &amp;ldquo;most solid&amp;rdquo; information pointed to a &amp;ldquo;Far-Eastern&amp;rdquo; company, with Acer, Samsung and Goldstar all rumoured to be in the running. While the UK office had continued trading, they weren&amp;rsquo;t receiving any new units to sell which meant they had to make do with whatever stock they had in their warehouses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/6/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/6/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News News broke as the mag went to press that Commodore worldwide had basically filed for administration in the Bahamas, where the company was registered. Just what this meant was unclear, but things did not look good. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly surprising considering the losses the company had posted over the last couple of years, though Commodore UK had performed well. While this move was obviously concerning, The One were confident that the continued popularity of the Amiga would mean a positive outcome one way or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 22:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Andy Nuttall (aka “Nutts”) joined the mag as Deputy Editor after having done five months hard time at ST Format.
Third time’s the charm - or so Commodore hoped with its third CD32 bundle since launch. The Voyage pack included “Microcosm” and “The Chaos Engine”, plus four games from the two existing bundles while stocks lasted, all for £299.99.
Codemasters were bringing “Captain Dynamo” and the “Dizzy CD Collection” to the CD32.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/4/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/4/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Contrary to last month’s news, while ex-The One editor David Upchurch had been assigned to a new mag, it was to EMAP’s latest launch, PC Games, and not a reboot of Sinclair User&amp;hellip; which made a little more sense.
Ocean struck a deal with Virgin to release twelve of its games on Hit Squad, their budget label. The lineup included “Cannon Fodder”, “Dune”, “Dune 2”, “Jimmy White’s Whirlwind Snooker”, “Archer Maclean’s Pool”, “Realms”, “Legend of Kyrandia”, “Supremacy”, “KGB”, “Reach for the Skies”, “Shuttle” and “Lure of the Temptress”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 05:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>theone199403
News This was to be David Upchurch&amp;rsquo;s last issue as Editor as off to head up EMAP&amp;rsquo;s relaunch of&amp;hellip; Sinclair User. Apparently the Speccy had been seeing a resurgence, though I find that a little hard to believe. At any rate, Simon Byron was to take over the helm.
Team 17 were embracing the CD32 starting with &amp;ldquo;Ultimate Body Blows&amp;rdquo;, a revamped version of their beat&amp;rsquo;em up featuring new AGA backdrops, digitised speech and a digital CD soundtrack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/2/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 06:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/2/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Editor David Upchurch saw a bright 1994 ahead for the Amiga.
Word on the street was that Commodore UK were close to striking a deal with LucasArts that would see them bring their PC hits &amp;ldquo;Rebel Assault&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Day of the Tentacle&amp;rdquo; to the CD32. (It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen)
While England had suffered the shame of failing to qualify for the upcoming World Cup, Virgin were keen to join with Adidas to sponsor a new initiative to promote youth footballing skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 08:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Late breaking news was that Maxis were porting &amp;ldquo;Sim City 2000&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga. The PC original was impressive, but would it survive the translation?
It looked like &amp;ldquo;The Second Samurai&amp;rdquo; would be Vivid Image Design&amp;rsquo;s last title for a little while as they were going all in on CD gaming. Mev Dinc and his team were taking the interesting approach of insisting that all design and illustration work be finished before a single line of code was written.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
