<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adventure on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/adventure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adventure on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:35:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/adventure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #12 August/September 1990</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this issue&amp;hellip;
The editor reflected on 2 years of Special Reserve: memberships had shot passed 25,000, with 5,500 of those also subscribing to Official Secrets (and, therefore, Confidential). While there had been the usual summer lull in game sales, they were expecting a bumper Xmas due to the Amiga&amp;rsquo;s popularity and had decided to also carry Atari Lynx, Sega Megadrive and CDTV titles.
The news included details of SSI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Secret of Silver Blades&amp;rdquo;, a bunch of upcoming flight sims, Alexey Pajitnov&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Tetris&amp;rdquo; followup &amp;ldquo;Welltris&amp;rdquo;, along with rumours of a new adventure from Level 9 (&amp;ldquo;Billy the Kid&amp;rdquo;), a game based on the book &amp;ldquo;Neuromancer&amp;rdquo;, and Sierra bringing &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Quest IV&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Colonel&amp;rsquo;s Bequest&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Bride&#39;s Article</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/7/29/st-brides-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/7/29/st-brides-article/</guid>
      <description>This is a great piece on the mysterious text adventure creators, St Bride&amp;rsquo;s; an edited version of which appeared in GamesTM mag.
I&amp;rsquo;d written about them previously, but this article does a far better job at uncovering their somewhat bizarre story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #10 April/May 1990</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/23/confidential-magazine-10-aprilmay-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 05:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/23/confidential-magazine-10-aprilmay-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s issue&amp;hellip;
The subject on the editor&amp;rsquo;s mind was, perhaps unexpectedly for an adventure gaming mag, taxation as he had a good rant about how much money from each game the club sold went to the HMRC.
Games making the news this month included several horror games (&amp;ldquo;Elvira&amp;rdquo;, [&amp;ldquo;Demon&amp;rsquo;s Tomb - The Awakening&amp;rdquo;][4403], [&amp;ldquo;Mystery of the Mummy&amp;rdquo;][4404]), the next title from The Bitmaps in the form of [&amp;ldquo;Cadaver&amp;rdquo;][4405], and some new games from Origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #9 February/March 1990</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/13/confidential-magazine-9-februarymarch-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 23:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/13/confidential-magazine-9-februarymarch-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s editorial, The Boss Upstairs reflected on the success of the Special Reserve and Official Secrets clubs. The team had grown to 30 to cope with the increased orders, with some 200 being processed every day. The future looked bright.
Elsewhere in the mag:
A lengthy interview with Anita Sinclair of Magnetic Scrolls. The newest Special Reserve/Official Secrets team members were introduced. A back to basics primer on how to tackle adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #8 December &#39;88/January &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</guid>
      <description>As we bid goodbye to the 80s, the Editor pondered what lay ahead in the coming decade. After the world had lived in fear of nuclear annihalation for so many years, the arrival of the likes of Gorbachev meant we could now focus on the &amp;ldquo;prospect of irreversible doom&amp;rdquo; thanks to global warming. Technology would, of course, play a significant role in what was to come: &amp;ldquo;Our ability to manipulate information and communicate the results to the whole World within seconds, could lead us into chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #7 October/November 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/6/confidential-magazine-7-octobernovember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 08:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/6/confidential-magazine-7-octobernovember-1989/</guid>
      <description>While they didn&amp;rsquo;t reveal actual subscription figures, the situation sounded a bit grim - the membership fee was to increase and there was a plea for readers to spread the word.
Meanwhile the helpline seemed to have switched to be a largely answering machine based service, and there was a request for solutions to a bunch of big recent adventures.
In this issue:
The news included details of several upcoming adventures from Electronic Arts and Gary Gygax consulting for Infogrames on &amp;ldquo;Drakkhen&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Point-and-Click Adventure Games pre-orders are live!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/4/the-art-of-point-and-click-adventure-games-pre-orders-are-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/4/the-art-of-point-and-click-adventure-games-pre-orders-are-live/</guid>
      <description>There is a slight irony around my love of point &amp;amp; click adventures over the last few years. Back in the 8 and 16 bit days I would often pour my disdain on these games while proclaiming the superiority of the good old text adventure. I was willing to accept the static images that accompanied games like &amp;ldquo;The Guild of Thieves&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;The Boggit&amp;rdquo;, but controlling a pixeled character and clicking on things with a limited set of verbs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Guild of Thieves Remastered&#34; is out!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/guild-of-thieves-remastered-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 22:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/guild-of-thieves-remastered-is-out/</guid>
      <description>I guess this is a sign of how recent life has been all-consumed by work, but I only just noticed that Strand Games have released the second of their Magnetic Scrolls remasters, &amp;ldquo;The Guild of Thieves&amp;rdquo;.
There are few games which I remember as fondly as this, not just because it is a brilliant adventure (which it certainly is), but because it was the game - and only game - I ordered alongside my beloved Amiga 500.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thimbleweed Park Day!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/19/happy-thimbleweed-park-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 07:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/19/happy-thimbleweed-park-day/</guid>
      <description>The iPad has become my preferred platform for playing adventure games, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to this one. I backed the Kickstarter almost three years ago and it&amp;rsquo;s been a treat to see it take shape - the dev blog posts and podcasts were worth it alone.
As luck would have it, my next overseas business trip is coming up in a few days which I hope will provide ample of opportunity to dive into it proper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #4 April/May 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</guid>
      <description>This issue came hot on the heels of British Telecom&amp;rsquo;s decision to bail out of the games industry. They were looking to sell off the Rainbird, Firebird and Silverbird labels as one lot, while winding Telecomsoft down. The official reason given was that games were no longer in line with the goals of BT, and the asking price was rumoured to be around £5 million. The editorial questioned the motives, highlighting a series of recent misteps resulting in significant financial losses, which included the purchase of Beyond Software (closed down soon after due to poor performance), and the US based Firebird Licensees Inc which lasted less than a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official Magnetic Scrolls Solution Books</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/official-magnetic-scrolls-solution-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 06:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/official-magnetic-scrolls-solution-books/</guid>
      <description>While digging through some boxes of old Stuff from the attic I came across a couple of solution books for the adventure games &amp;ldquo;Corruption&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Fish!&amp;rdquo; by Magnetic Scrolls. I got these directly from Magnetic Scrolls, and they&amp;rsquo;re far superior to regular old walkthroughs as they include location maps, hints for specific situations along with the step by step solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Throttle Remastered arrives on iOS</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/20/full-throttle-remastered-arrives-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 09:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/20/full-throttle-remastered-arrives-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>Finally! I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this one for a while: &amp;ldquo;Full Throttle Remastered&amp;rdquo; has been released for iOS. The iPad has become my adventure gaming device of choice (aside from 8bit text adventures, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out a solution for that), so it&amp;rsquo;s great to see another LucasArts classic on the platform.
Not only that, but to coincide with the release Double Fine have slashed the prices of &amp;ldquo;Grim Fandango Remastered&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Day of the Tentacle Remastered&amp;rdquo; - both highly recommended and absolute bargains at this price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #1 Sept/Oct 1988</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/8/confidential-magazine-1-septoct-1988/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 06:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/8/confidential-magazine-1-septoct-1988/</guid>
      <description>Back in 1987 I ordered a copy of the classic adventure &amp;ldquo;Guild of Thieves&amp;rdquo; along with my Amiga 500. Included in the game&amp;rsquo;s package was a copy of &amp;ldquo;What Burglar?&amp;rdquo; magazine, and an advert for a mysterious &amp;ldquo;Confidential&amp;rdquo; club. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s how I remember it - looking through the box now I don&amp;rsquo;t see such an advert in there, though there is an offer to write in to Magnetic Scrolls to receive some swag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: &#34;The Camp&#34; (C64) by Protovision</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/22/review-the-camp-c64-by-protovision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 08:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/22/review-the-camp-c64-by-protovision/</guid>
      <description>Way back in the mists of time (well, 1982) my parents took me and my sister out of school for a few months to embark on a trip around the UK, Europe and the US. For the European leg we jaunted about in a campervan, staying at campsites (and occasionally on roadsides) along the way. My memories of that time are sadly vague - my main recollection is the ridiculously rough toilet paper that one had to endure in the bathrooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The return of Magnetic Scrolls? (Sort of)</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/18/the-return-of-magnetic-scrolls-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 06:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/18/the-return-of-magnetic-scrolls-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>Well, this is very interesting indeed. Hugh Steers - a founding member of Magnetic Scrolls - has formed Strand Games along with Stefan Meier (from if-legends.org). Their first release is a a remaster of the classic adventure &amp;ldquo;The Pawn&amp;rdquo;, available for Mac, Win and Linux. Not only that, but they have the support of other Magnetic Scrolls alumni, including Anita Sinclair and Ken Gordon.
I stumbled across their site somewhat randomly - I&amp;rsquo;m a bit surprised it hasn&amp;rsquo;t received more coverage in the retro gaming scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Kickstarters</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 23:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a good time to be a retro gaming fan recently with several promising Kickstarters. Of course I dawdled too long on writing about them, so some have already finished, but they&amp;rsquo;re still worth keeping an eye on.
Reformation 2 from Matt Gray The first Reformation took a little longer to ship than originally expected, but it was well worth the wait. 5 CDs of excellent remakes of some of the best tunes to grace the C64 (and therefore, games in general).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken Age Part 1</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/broken-age-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 23:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/broken-age-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The Double Fine Adventure Kickstarter was one of those few moments where you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re actually seeing a seismic shift in the industry. I jumped in within hours of the campaign going live - as a huge fan of adventure games, particularly those from Lucasfilm/Lucas Arts, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to think twice. It&amp;rsquo;s been a really fascinating ride since then - the behind the scenes videos are the best accounts of game development ever committed to film, and I almost don&amp;rsquo;t want them to finish the game as that will mean the end of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St Brides</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/23/st-brides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 04:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/23/st-brides/</guid>
      <description>St Brides were easily one of those most intriguing software houses of the 80s. For a start they produced some great adventures games - &amp;ldquo;The Very Big Cave Adventure&amp;rdquo; was my first exposure to them, which I remember fondly. Their games were known for being well written with a keen sense of humour. Then there was the fact that they appeared to be a company consisting entirely of women (quite unique in the industry), as they were generally referred to as &amp;ldquo;the sisters&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;the ladies&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;the belles&amp;rdquo;/etc of St Brides (to what extent this was actually the case, I&amp;rsquo;m unsure).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
