<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>September on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/september/</link>
    <description>Recent content in September on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:39:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/september/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/9/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/9/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News After reporting that the saga of Commodore&amp;rsquo;s fate would be resolved &amp;ldquo;any day now&amp;rdquo; for the past few months, The One decided to quit guessing the timeline. In the latest twist, word arrived Commodore UK (lead by David Pleasance and Colin Proudfoot) were now the favourites with their proposal of a Management Buy Out, with Samsung apparently still keen. At the US head office Mehdi Ali was officially out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #12 August/September 1990</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this issue&amp;hellip;
The editor reflected on 2 years of Special Reserve: memberships had shot passed 25,000, with 5,500 of those also subscribing to Official Secrets (and, therefore, Confidential). While there had been the usual summer lull in game sales, they were expecting a bumper Xmas due to the Amiga&amp;rsquo;s popularity and had decided to also carry Atari Lynx, Sega Megadrive and CDTV titles.
The news included details of SSI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Secret of Silver Blades&amp;rdquo;, a bunch of upcoming flight sims, Alexey Pajitnov&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Tetris&amp;rdquo; followup &amp;ldquo;Welltris&amp;rdquo;, along with rumours of a new adventure from Level 9 (&amp;ldquo;Billy the Kid&amp;rdquo;), a game based on the book &amp;ldquo;Neuromancer&amp;rdquo;, and Sierra bringing &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Quest IV&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Colonel&amp;rsquo;s Bequest&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/9/29/zlkv83ofoauysfxxv490x1maf0etuj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 06:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/9/29/zlkv83ofoauysfxxv490x1maf0etuj/</guid>
      <description>News In an effort to draw some attention away from the other popular gaming mascots, Mindscape decided to enter &amp;ldquo;Alfred the Chicken&amp;rdquo; in the Christchurch by-election. Alfred managed to bring in 18 votes - two ahead of the Rainbow Alliance Party. The resulting media &amp;ldquo;circus&amp;rdquo; was certainly worth the 500 quid it cost them.
Europress teased some screen shots of racing sim &amp;ldquo;Rally&amp;rdquo;, though they were from the PC version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/9/26/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 08:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/9/26/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Team 17 were having another crack at the beat &amp;rsquo;em up genre with &amp;ldquo;Body Blows&amp;rdquo;, along with a top down racer, &amp;ldquo;Overdrive&amp;rdquo;.
Rumours started to circulate that there was yet another Amiga model on the way: the A800. It would be a 32bit machine with 68030 CPU and would sit between the A600 and the A1500. Commodore&amp;rsquo;s Market Director Kelly Sumner was adamant there would be no machine called the A800, but did confirm there was another machine on the way&amp;hellip; I assume it was the A1200.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #6 August/September 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 06:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s mag included:
A rather depressing Editorial which opened with &amp;ldquo;Boom-time for the computer games world is over, at least for the next few years.&amp;rdquo; The Japanese consoles were wiping the floor with computers - the 8bits were barely hanging on, the ST not far behind them. There looked to be some life left in the Amiga, but it was the IBM PC that stood the best chance of lasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/5/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 07:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/5/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Two years after it launched in the US, Atari were bringing the 7800 ProSystem to the UK. On paper the specs weren&amp;rsquo;t up to much when compared to Nintendo and Sega&amp;rsquo;s offerings, but at £69.95 it looked decent value for money. Stateside the 7800 was the number 2 selling console ahead of the Master System.
Spectravideo&amp;rsquo;s popular range of Quickshot joysticks (the Quickshot II Turbo was my personal fave back in the day) was being joined by their new Wizmaster gamepad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 09:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News More staffing changes at the magazine this month. Roger Kean was moving over to a new Newsfield mag called L.M., with Gary Penn stepping in to the Editor role. There were three new faces with Richard &amp;ldquo;Dick&amp;rdquo; Eddy, Jonathan Rignall (Julian&amp;rsquo;s younger brother) and Massimo Valducci starting.
Beyond announced the upcoming release of not one but two Denton Design games: &amp;ldquo;Dante’s Inferno&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Infodroid&amp;rdquo;.
Meanwhile, Beyond had managed to secure the first ever Star Trek license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 07:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News For the first time, major games were being released on the 16bits before the 8bits. C&amp;amp;VG reassured its readers that almost all the games would make their way to the C64/Spectrum/Amstrad, and that the magazine would continue to cover those machines.
The Bitmap Brothers were following up their well received 16bit shoot&amp;rsquo;em up &amp;ldquo;Xenon&amp;rdquo; with a new futuristic sports game, &amp;ldquo;Speedball&amp;rdquo;.
Mirrorsoft had created a new label, Imageworks, which would be their flagship for most of its new games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/9/13/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 06:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/9/13/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Digital Integration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bobsleigh&amp;rdquo; was a departure from their usual flight sims and would centre around the winter event.
Incentive teased their impressive new Freescape engine with a couple of screenshots of the upcoming &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo;.
English Software were working on a Rambo-esque game: &amp;ldquo;Captain Courageous&amp;rdquo;.
Atari dropped the price of the 520STFM to £299.99. They were also planning to re-launch the 130XE and position it as &amp;ldquo;the ultimate teaching computer&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 02:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Sensible Software signed to Outlaw, Palace Software&amp;rsquo;s new label. The first game the sensi chaps would deliver was &amp;ldquo;Shoot&amp;rsquo;em Up Construction Kit&amp;rdquo; (or SEUCK as it came to be known as).
A game based on Jeffrey Archer&amp;rsquo;s first novel, &amp;ldquo;Not a Penny More, Not a Penny Less&amp;rdquo; was in the works. Meanwhile, Archer had been busy in a highly publicised court case and had just been acquitted.
There was a &amp;ldquo;Ten Things You Never Knew About Mark Cale&amp;rdquo; section (head of System 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 01:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Peter Jones and Trevor Lever (the blokes behind &amp;ldquo;Terrormolinos&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hampstead&amp;rdquo;) were back with a new two part adventure &amp;ldquo;Dodgy Geezers&amp;rdquo;.
US Gold had a strong upcoming lineup with &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Masters of the Universe&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Infiltrator&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Cycle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Championship Wrestling&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Movie Monster&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;World Games&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Xevious&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Express Raider&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Break Thru&amp;rdquo;. Phew.
Lucasfilm and Activision picked up the game rights for &amp;ldquo;Labyrinth&amp;rdquo;. The movie had been received well in the US and was due to hit the UK around Christmas</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/29/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 01:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/29/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News The Personal Computer World Show was about to happen and publishers were busy announcing/teasing their upcoming games. Full details of what was on display would be in next month&amp;rsquo;s issue, but there was a boatload of previews to do.
Not one but two winners had been chosen for the Genesis competition Crash launched a few months earlier. The first was a shoot em up called &amp;ldquo;Kat Trap&amp;rdquo; by John Eggleton that would hopefully be out by Christmas, while the second - &amp;ldquo;The Sewer&amp;rdquo; by Martin Lee - was planned for Spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-the-games-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 04:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-the-games-machine/</guid>
      <description>News Atari appeared to be winning the battle of the 16bits. A combination of a very generous software bundle, price drop and big ad campaign saw sales of the ST see a rise even during the usual summer slump. Meanwhile, the Amiga was still having problems with reliability - some shops putting returns as high as 25%. Software sales were reportedly 70/30 in favour of the ST.
A small South Wales company called Miles Gordon Technology (MGT) was about to release a Spectrum &amp;ldquo;super clone&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 04:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News The Golden Sundial of Pi prize from &amp;ldquo;Pimania&amp;rdquo; was finally found! The winners - Sue Cooper and Lizi Newman - solved the puzzle by being at Hindover Hill in Sussex on July 22nd. The competition had begun on the release of &amp;ldquo;Pimania&amp;rdquo; in 1982.
British Telecom were about to open up public access to M.U.D. (multi-user dungeon), which had previously just been available to students and staff at Essex University.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
