<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentaries on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/documentaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentaries on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 04:45:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/documentaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spectrum Addict: Load &#34;FILM 2&#34; Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/spectrum-addict-load-film-2-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 04:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/spectrum-addict-load-film-2-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>The Kickstarter for a follow up to the &amp;ldquo;Memoirs of a Spectrum Addict&amp;rdquo; documentary, &amp;ldquo;Load &amp;lsquo;FILM 2&amp;rsquo; has entered its final week. The line up of Speccy developers is impressive, including the likes of my old boss Jon Ritman and Bo Jangeborg. As someone who was obsessed by Delta4&amp;rsquo;s adventure games back in the day, I&amp;rsquo;m particularly pleased to see Fergus McNeil in there as well.&#xA;These documentaries are clearly a labour of love for Andy and I strongly believe that we need to be capturing the stories of these pioneers, so I really hope this funds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Kickstarters</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 23:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a good time to be a retro gaming fan recently with several promising Kickstarters. Of course I dawdled too long on writing about them, so some have already finished, but they&amp;rsquo;re still worth keeping an eye on.&#xA;Reformation 2 from Matt Gray The first Reformation took a little longer to ship than originally expected, but it was well worth the wait. 5 CDs of excellent remakes of some of the best tunes to grace the C64 (and therefore, games in general).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms To Billions: The Amiga Years</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 03:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</guid>
      <description>The good folk behind the absolutely brilliant &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms to Billions&amp;rdquo; documentary have announced their new project: a 90 minute film on the Amiga. This time rather than focussing on the British contribution to the industry, they&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking to prominent Amiga developers, musicians, demo sceners and so on from around the world.&#xA;Given my love for the Amiga - a machine that was so beautifully and elegantly architected and years ahead of its time - I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely delighted they&amp;rsquo;ve chosen it as the subject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms To Billions</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 04:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</guid>
      <description>A little over 2 years ago I stumbled across an Indiegogo campaign that was raising funds for a documentary on the birth of the UK games industry. They already had an impressive list of interviewees lined up and the clips they&amp;rsquo;d released were very promising. It was clear that the producers had a deep respect for the subject and the people they were recording, and that they weren&amp;rsquo;t setting out to create some cheesey fluff piece (unlike certain other productions).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
