<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1989 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1989/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1989 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1989/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #8 December &#39;88/January &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</guid>
      <description>As we bid goodbye to the 80s, the Editor pondered what lay ahead in the coming decade. After the world had lived in fear of nuclear annihalation for so many years, the arrival of the likes of Gorbachev meant we could now focus on the &amp;ldquo;prospect of irreversible doom&amp;rdquo; thanks to global warming. Technology would, of course, play a significant role in what was to come: &amp;ldquo;Our ability to manipulate information and communicate the results to the whole World within seconds, could lead us into chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #6 August/September 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 06:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s mag included:
A rather depressing Editorial which opened with &amp;ldquo;Boom-time for the computer games world is over, at least for the next few years.&amp;rdquo; The Japanese consoles were wiping the floor with computers - the 8bits were barely hanging on, the ST not far behind them. There looked to be some life left in the Amiga, but it was the IBM PC that stood the best chance of lasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #5 June/July 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 22:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</guid>
      <description>In this issue you can find:
A bit of a rant by the Ed on the &amp;ldquo;joys&amp;rdquo; of running a software mail order service and dealing with clueless, impatient and down right rude customers calling up. A report from the first European Computer Trade Show, which sounded like a right disappointment: &amp;ldquo;Where were the First Ever Showings? The Exclusive Demos? The Sneako Previews? Well, they certainly weren&amp;rsquo;t present on the day I visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 07:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Hot off the presses from Japan was news of the PC Engine Super Grafx which looked to build on the already impressive original. New custom chips meant it could chuck around 128 sprites (up from 64) and the cartridges saw a decent boost in size. Perhaps the most intriguing aspect was the Power Console add on which the console slotted into and featured a full on steering yoke, a gear stick/throttle, LCD clock/timer, LED radar display, numeric keypad and a bunch of buttons and knobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/11/16/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 07:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/11/16/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News A new computer was about to be unleashed on Europe which boasted specs that certainly beat the 8bits, but also - apparently - rivaled the Amiga and ST. While that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem terribly exciting, it did have one interesting feature: the ability to run most Speccy games. The SAM Coupe was due to launch in the UK on November 20th.
With Christmas around the corner, Hewson were to release a couple of compilations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/15/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 08:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/15/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Konix Here At Last&amp;rdquo; proclaimed the headline leading off this issue. The much hyped Konix Multisystem was going to be available to buy this month at stores across the UK for around 200 quid. Not all of the eagerly anticipated peripherals would be on sale to start with - the hydraulic chair was &amp;ldquo;on the horizon&amp;rdquo; and expected to cost another 200 quid. Of course, sadly, none of this was to be&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #4 April/May 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</guid>
      <description>This issue came hot on the heels of British Telecom&amp;rsquo;s decision to bail out of the games industry. They were looking to sell off the Rainbird, Firebird and Silverbird labels as one lot, while winding Telecomsoft down. The official reason given was that games were no longer in line with the goals of BT, and the asking price was rumoured to be around £5 million. The editorial questioned the motives, highlighting a series of recent misteps resulting in significant financial losses, which included the purchase of Beyond Software (closed down soon after due to poor performance), and the US based Firebird Licensees Inc which lasted less than a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/5/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 07:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/5/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Two years after it launched in the US, Atari were bringing the 7800 ProSystem to the UK. On paper the specs weren&amp;rsquo;t up to much when compared to Nintendo and Sega&amp;rsquo;s offerings, but at £69.95 it looked decent value for money. Stateside the 7800 was the number 2 selling console ahead of the Master System.
Spectravideo&amp;rsquo;s popular range of Quickshot joysticks (the Quickshot II Turbo was my personal fave back in the day) was being joined by their new Wizmaster gamepad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #2 Dec 1988/Jan 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 08:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</guid>
      <description>Postal strikes had caused delays to the first issue, and - whether it was due to this or some other reason - November came and went without the second issue. Going forward they would be sticking to the every-other-month schedule.
Contents:
Interview with Philippe Ulrich, head of the EXXOS group at French software house ERE Informatique which had recently released the rather original and intriguing &amp;ldquo;Captain Blood&amp;rdquo;. A somewhat tongue in cheek guide to playing adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 08:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Atari unveiled their impressive handheld, the Lynx. Julian Rignall got to check it out and was gobsmacked: &amp;ldquo;Erm&amp;hellip; hmmm&amp;hellip; What can I say about the most exciting thing to happen to the games industry since the invention of the home console?&amp;rdquo;
Sinclair (aka Amstrad) were to launch a new bundle. The &amp;ldquo;Action Pack&amp;rdquo; would consist of a Spectrum +2 (£149) or +3 (£199), a Magnum light gun and 6 games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/4/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 08:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/4/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News The industry was abuzz with talk of Nintendo’s Game Boy. The handheld had seen a very successful launch in Japan with over 500,000 units being sold (300,000 of which were on the first day), and now the question was when would it reach the UK. Nintendo were unable to give any dates, but confirmed they had plans…
The FIST telephone game was getting a sequel (I have no idea what this was).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 08:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw C&amp;amp;VG getting a revamp based on reader feedback. Coin ops and consoles would get more pages, the adventure section got a make over, there was more space dedicated to previews and overall there would be a lot more colour. The announcement of these changes referenced the fact that some features were dropped, but they didn’t actually specify which. Somewhat worryingly, there were no adventure game reviews - just some tips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/24/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/24/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>[Oh dear, I got confused and thought this was the April issue.. turns out my April issue appears to be missing - no doubt the fault of one of my High School friends back in the day]
News Rignall and Glancey took on Domark’s Mark Strachan and Andy Blazdell in three rounds of Tengen’s &amp;ldquo;Vindicators&amp;rdquo; arcade machine. The C&amp;amp;VG lads won two out of three and claimed the Tengen Trophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/20/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 08:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/20/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Michael Jackson’s “Moonwalker” movie had only just come out and US Gold had already snaffled the game license.
Titus announced their futuristic deadly sport game &amp;ldquo;Titan”.
The Vocalizer 1000 was a music gadget where the user would hum/whistle/sing a tune at it and it would detect the varying pitches and allow playback of the tune using a selection of 28 instruments.
Gary Liddon was teaming up with renowned game artist Paul Docherty to develop &amp;ldquo;Tyger Tyger&amp;rdquo; for Mastertronic’s Ricochet label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/23/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 08:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/23/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Death Stalks the Night&amp;rdquo; was an upcoming arcade adventure from Ubi Soft where the player assumed the role as Count Dracula to take on “the usual Van Helsings”.
New software house EAS announced a space trading game called &amp;ldquo;STAG&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST.
Mr Chip’s &amp;ldquo;Wrangler&amp;rdquo;would see the player take control over Clint Eastwood (yes, apparently) and his ‘droid in what looked like a puzzle game.
Budget label Alternative were moving into the 16bits with Don Priestly’s &amp;ldquo;Mad Flunky”, a follow-up to his Spectrum game &amp;ldquo;Flunky”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/11/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 08:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/11/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News C&amp;amp;VG were giving away a Body Rap toy which would be strapped to your body and emit audio (bass, drum, snare, cymbal etc) when hit. They described it as a “neat little gizmo” but I can’t imagine it being anything other than dreadful.
The Amiga, ST and Amstrad versions of Titus’ car racing game &amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars II&amp;rdquo; were on the shelves, with the C64 due this month.
German software house Rainbow Arts were to release &amp;ldquo;Spherical”, a Gauntlet-style game, and &amp;ldquo;The Game&amp;rdquo; which promised to be a “space battle spectacular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/22/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 23:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/22/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News Word leaked out that Epyx was working on a new console. David Morse (CEO of Epyx, and one of the original Amiga hardware designers) was involved on what was rumoured to be a new handheld. This, of course, would become the Atari Lynx.
Megadrives and NES consoles started appearing in arcades in the UK where players could purchase a set amount of play time with a range of games available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 05:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News Atari Games (not to be confused with hardware manufacturer, Atari) sued Nintendo for $100 million over the inability to publish games for the NES without going through the Japanese company. Nintendo seemed unphased by the move, saying that they had never lost a lawsuit.
Confusion reigned over the specifics for the Konix Slipstream. TGM attempted to clear things up by confirming that it would retail at £150 (or slightly higher), have a set of peripherals (hydraulic chair, light gun, 3D helmet), some of which would be included with the console (not the chair!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw a new &amp;ldquo;bigger and brighter&amp;rdquo; look for TGM.
Excitement was growing for the impending release of the Konix Slipstream megaconsole. Costing a mere £149 it was due to go on sale in Autumn and would be able to read software from standard 3&amp;quot; disks as well as cartridges. Disks were looking like the preferred format due to being much cheaper to produce - customers could look forward to paying only 15 quid for games.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
