<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentaries on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/categories/documentaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentaries on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 03:09:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/categories/documentaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms To Billions: The Amiga Years</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 03:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</guid>
      <description>The good folk behind the absolutely brilliant &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms to Billions&amp;rdquo; documentary have announced their new project: a 90 minute film on the Amiga. This time rather than focussing on the British contribution to the industry, they&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking to prominent Amiga developers, musicians, demo sceners and so on from around the world.&#xA;Given my love for the Amiga - a machine that was so beautifully and elegantly architected and years ahead of its time - I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely delighted they&amp;rsquo;ve chosen it as the subject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms To Billions</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 04:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</guid>
      <description>A little over 2 years ago I stumbled across an Indiegogo campaign that was raising funds for a documentary on the birth of the UK games industry. They already had an impressive list of interviewees lined up and the clips they&amp;rsquo;d released were very promising. It was clear that the producers had a deep respect for the subject and the people they were recording, and that they weren&amp;rsquo;t setting out to create some cheesey fluff piece (unlike certain other productions).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms to Billions</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/3/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 19:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/3/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</guid>
      <description>After a successful round of crowdfunding last year, the people behind the &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms to Billions&amp;rdquo; documentary and conducting a new Kickstarter campaign in order to cover the myriad of costs involved in finishing and polishing the film. With the passing of Mike Singleton, it&amp;rsquo;s become clear that we need to record the histories of the people involved in the UK games industry during the 80s. The interviews they&amp;rsquo;ve managed to snag are extremely impressive - so many of my heroes are in there.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
