<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>January on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/january/</link>
    <description>Recent content in January on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:44:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/january/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/1/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/1/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Apparently the higher ups at EMAP were putting pressure on The One to cut back on pages and coverdisks, but Acting Editor Andy Nuttall and team stood firm, delivering a bumper issue. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t without its price, tho: &amp;ldquo;So, it&amp;rsquo;s taken us ages longer than normal to write, the coverdisks nearly killed us, and getting in the finished version of SWOS for review was a nightmare.&amp;rdquo;
The fate of Commodore remained up in the air, with little news to be had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 08:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Late breaking news was that Maxis were porting &amp;ldquo;Sim City 2000&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga. The PC original was impressive, but would it survive the translation?
It looked like &amp;ldquo;The Second Samurai&amp;rdquo; would be Vivid Image Design&amp;rsquo;s last title for a little while as they were going all in on CD gaming. Mev Dinc and his team were taking the interesting approach of insisting that all design and illustration work be finished before a single line of code was written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/1/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 06:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/1/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Digital Image Design had two new titles on the way. The first up was a &amp;ldquo;pseudo-sequel&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Epic&amp;rdquo; - called &amp;ldquo;Odyssey&amp;rdquo; - set 90 years further in the future and would feature more of an open world feel. Sadly it looks like it was never released.. The second was another sequel, jet fighter sim &amp;ldquo;TFX Inferno&amp;rdquo;.
Relative newcomer Miracle Games were rather bullish about their upcoming platformer, &amp;ldquo;Miracle Bat&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #8 December &#39;88/January &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</guid>
      <description>As we bid goodbye to the 80s, the Editor pondered what lay ahead in the coming decade. After the world had lived in fear of nuclear annihalation for so many years, the arrival of the likes of Gorbachev meant we could now focus on the &amp;ldquo;prospect of irreversible doom&amp;rdquo; thanks to global warming. Technology would, of course, play a significant role in what was to come: &amp;ldquo;Our ability to manipulate information and communicate the results to the whole World within seconds, could lead us into chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #2 Dec 1988/Jan 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 08:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</guid>
      <description>Postal strikes had caused delays to the first issue, and - whether it was due to this or some other reason - November came and went without the second issue. Going forward they would be sticking to the every-other-month schedule.
Contents:
Interview with Philippe Ulrich, head of the EXXOS group at French software house ERE Informatique which had recently released the rather original and intriguing &amp;ldquo;Captain Blood&amp;rdquo;. A somewhat tongue in cheek guide to playing adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/25/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 08:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/25/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Gary Penn lamented the fact that for the first time there had not been a single Sizzler or Gold Medal awarded in an issue. Well, that’s not entirely true as &amp;ldquo;The Bard’s Tale&amp;rdquo; picked up a very respectable Sizzler, though apparently it didn’t count as it was “a role playing game”. It seemed that software houses were spending as much time as possible before Christmas to polish up their hopeful hits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/11/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 08:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/11/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News C&amp;amp;VG were giving away a Body Rap toy which would be strapped to your body and emit audio (bass, drum, snare, cymbal etc) when hit. They described it as a “neat little gizmo” but I can’t imagine it being anything other than dreadful.
The Amiga, ST and Amstrad versions of Titus’ car racing game &amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars II&amp;rdquo; were on the shelves, with the C64 due this month.
German software house Rainbow Arts were to release &amp;ldquo;Spherical”, a Gauntlet-style game, and &amp;ldquo;The Game&amp;rdquo; which promised to be a “space battle spectacular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/1/10/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 05:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/1/10/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This issue came with an audio cassette featuring music from 720º and Out Run.
Electric Dreams&amp;rsquo; Spectrum port of &amp;ldquo;Super Hang-On&amp;rdquo; narrowly missed the review window for the month, but a tasty screenshot of it was included instead. C&amp;amp;VG assured readers it was &amp;ldquo;simply brilliant&amp;rdquo;.
The Edge was bringing comic cat &amp;ldquo;Garfield&amp;rdquo; to home computers.
&amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars&amp;rdquo; was a rather promising looking 16bit racing game from Titus.
&amp;ldquo;Robocop&amp;rdquo; had taken US movie goers by storm and was due to hit UK screens early in the New Year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Rather oddly there was no news section, despite it being a bumper issue. Perhaps this was a change of direction now that Julian Rignall was editor?
Features Jon Hare provided a run down of how to use SEUCK.
A bunch of joysticks were reviewed. The Competition Pro 5000 came out on top.
The Harlequin looked back on what was a bit of a lacklustre year for adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 20:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Ocean was to bring &amp;ldquo;Donkey Kong&amp;rdquo; to the C64, Spectrum and Amstrad.
&amp;ldquo;Blood n&amp;rsquo; Guts&amp;rdquo; was heading to the C64 and was described by publisher American Action as &amp;ldquo;an ancient barbarian decathlon with all the violence and brutality you&amp;rsquo;ve ever dreamed about in a computer game&amp;rdquo;. Oo-kay.
Atari&amp;rsquo;s 7800 was about to hit the shelves retailing for around £70, with games costing £10-15.
Bo Jangeborg was busy finishing &amp;ldquo;Fairlight II&amp;rdquo;, which was to be double the size and feature a greater variety of graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw a new &amp;ldquo;bigger and brighter&amp;rdquo; look for TGM.
Excitement was growing for the impending release of the Konix Slipstream megaconsole. Costing a mere £149 it was due to go on sale in Autumn and would be able to read software from standard 3&amp;quot; disks as well as cartridges. Disks were looking like the preferred format due to being much cheaper to produce - customers could look forward to paying only 15 quid for games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/12/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 01:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/12/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News With the news that Ultimate had morphed into Rare and committed exclusively to consoles - due to hit the UK in the coming months - and the arrival of powerful 16bit machines, Graeme Kidd tried allay the fears of readers about the future of the Speccy. A swath of top quality games had come out for the Spectrum in the last few months of 1986 and Graeme reckoned all those talented programmers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to suddenly jump ship to the new platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/5/mun4x70unjj1dh0jl2mlo3doj77olx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/5/mun4x70unjj1dh0jl2mlo3doj77olx/</guid>
      <description>News Dave Perry and Nick Jones had nearly wrapped up the latest Wally game for MikroGen - &amp;ldquo;Three Weeks in Paradise&amp;rdquo;.
Domark released a screenshot of their rather controversial &amp;ldquo;Friday the 13th&amp;rdquo;. The game certainly got the attention of the press but - unsurprisingly - for all the wrong reasons, as it turned out to be rubbish. (&amp;ldquo;Oh dear, oh dear&amp;rdquo; lamented Crash in their review).
A BBC conversion of Imagine&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Arcadia&amp;rdquo; called &amp;ldquo;Wet Zone&amp;rdquo; was to be distributed on the Micronet 800 dialup service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
