<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Confidential on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/confidential/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Confidential on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:35:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/confidential/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #12 August/September 1990</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this issue&amp;hellip;
The editor reflected on 2 years of Special Reserve: memberships had shot passed 25,000, with 5,500 of those also subscribing to Official Secrets (and, therefore, Confidential). While there had been the usual summer lull in game sales, they were expecting a bumper Xmas due to the Amiga&amp;rsquo;s popularity and had decided to also carry Atari Lynx, Sega Megadrive and CDTV titles.
The news included details of SSI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Secret of Silver Blades&amp;rdquo;, a bunch of upcoming flight sims, Alexey Pajitnov&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Tetris&amp;rdquo; followup &amp;ldquo;Welltris&amp;rdquo;, along with rumours of a new adventure from Level 9 (&amp;ldquo;Billy the Kid&amp;rdquo;), a game based on the book &amp;ldquo;Neuromancer&amp;rdquo;, and Sierra bringing &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Quest IV&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Colonel&amp;rsquo;s Bequest&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #10 April/May 1990</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/23/confidential-magazine-10-aprilmay-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 05:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/23/confidential-magazine-10-aprilmay-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s issue&amp;hellip;
The subject on the editor&amp;rsquo;s mind was, perhaps unexpectedly for an adventure gaming mag, taxation as he had a good rant about how much money from each game the club sold went to the HMRC.
Games making the news this month included several horror games (&amp;ldquo;Elvira&amp;rdquo;, [&amp;ldquo;Demon&amp;rsquo;s Tomb - The Awakening&amp;rdquo;][4403], [&amp;ldquo;Mystery of the Mummy&amp;rdquo;][4404]), the next title from The Bitmaps in the form of [&amp;ldquo;Cadaver&amp;rdquo;][4405], and some new games from Origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #9 February/March 1990</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/13/confidential-magazine-9-februarymarch-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 23:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/13/confidential-magazine-9-februarymarch-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s editorial, The Boss Upstairs reflected on the success of the Special Reserve and Official Secrets clubs. The team had grown to 30 to cope with the increased orders, with some 200 being processed every day. The future looked bright.
Elsewhere in the mag:
A lengthy interview with Anita Sinclair of Magnetic Scrolls. The newest Special Reserve/Official Secrets team members were introduced. A back to basics primer on how to tackle adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #8 December &#39;88/January &#39;89</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</guid>
      <description>As we bid goodbye to the 80s, the Editor pondered what lay ahead in the coming decade. After the world had lived in fear of nuclear annihalation for so many years, the arrival of the likes of Gorbachev meant we could now focus on the &amp;ldquo;prospect of irreversible doom&amp;rdquo; thanks to global warming. Technology would, of course, play a significant role in what was to come: &amp;ldquo;Our ability to manipulate information and communicate the results to the whole World within seconds, could lead us into chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #7 October/November 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/6/confidential-magazine-7-octobernovember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 08:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/6/confidential-magazine-7-octobernovember-1989/</guid>
      <description>While they didn&amp;rsquo;t reveal actual subscription figures, the situation sounded a bit grim - the membership fee was to increase and there was a plea for readers to spread the word.
Meanwhile the helpline seemed to have switched to be a largely answering machine based service, and there was a request for solutions to a bunch of big recent adventures.
In this issue:
The news included details of several upcoming adventures from Electronic Arts and Gary Gygax consulting for Infogrames on &amp;ldquo;Drakkhen&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #6 August/September 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 06:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s mag included:
A rather depressing Editorial which opened with &amp;ldquo;Boom-time for the computer games world is over, at least for the next few years.&amp;rdquo; The Japanese consoles were wiping the floor with computers - the 8bits were barely hanging on, the ST not far behind them. There looked to be some life left in the Amiga, but it was the IBM PC that stood the best chance of lasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #5 June/July 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 22:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</guid>
      <description>In this issue you can find:
A bit of a rant by the Ed on the &amp;ldquo;joys&amp;rdquo; of running a software mail order service and dealing with clueless, impatient and down right rude customers calling up. A report from the first European Computer Trade Show, which sounded like a right disappointment: &amp;ldquo;Where were the First Ever Showings? The Exclusive Demos? The Sneako Previews? Well, they certainly weren&amp;rsquo;t present on the day I visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #4 April/May 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</guid>
      <description>This issue came hot on the heels of British Telecom&amp;rsquo;s decision to bail out of the games industry. They were looking to sell off the Rainbird, Firebird and Silverbird labels as one lot, while winding Telecomsoft down. The official reason given was that games were no longer in line with the goals of BT, and the asking price was rumoured to be around £5 million. The editorial questioned the motives, highlighting a series of recent misteps resulting in significant financial losses, which included the purchase of Beyond Software (closed down soon after due to poor performance), and the US based Firebird Licensees Inc which lasted less than a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #2 Dec 1988/Jan 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 08:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</guid>
      <description>Postal strikes had caused delays to the first issue, and - whether it was due to this or some other reason - November came and went without the second issue. Going forward they would be sticking to the every-other-month schedule.
Contents:
Interview with Philippe Ulrich, head of the EXXOS group at French software house ERE Informatique which had recently released the rather original and intriguing &amp;ldquo;Captain Blood&amp;rdquo;. A somewhat tongue in cheek guide to playing adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #1 Sept/Oct 1988</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/8/confidential-magazine-1-septoct-1988/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 06:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/8/confidential-magazine-1-septoct-1988/</guid>
      <description>Back in 1987 I ordered a copy of the classic adventure &amp;ldquo;Guild of Thieves&amp;rdquo; along with my Amiga 500. Included in the game&amp;rsquo;s package was a copy of &amp;ldquo;What Burglar?&amp;rdquo; magazine, and an advert for a mysterious &amp;ldquo;Confidential&amp;rdquo; club. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s how I remember it - looking through the box now I don&amp;rsquo;t see such an advert in there, though there is an offer to write in to Magnetic Scrolls to receive some swag.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
