<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>June on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/june/</link>
    <description>Recent content in June on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:02:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/june/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/6/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/6/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News News broke as the mag went to press that Commodore worldwide had basically filed for administration in the Bahamas, where the company was registered. Just what this meant was unclear, but things did not look good. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly surprising considering the losses the company had posted over the last couple of years, though Commodore UK had performed well. While this move was obviously concerning, The One were confident that the continued popularity of the Amiga would mean a positive outcome one way or another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/6/23/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 05:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/6/23/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The Amiga had a strong showing at this year&amp;rsquo;s Golden Joysticks awards. Team 17 and Sensible Software won Software House of the Year and Computer Game of the Year respectively, with Jon Hare giving a &amp;ldquo;stirring speech warning against the dangers of complacency.&amp;rdquo; The Amiga related winners were:&#xA;Software House of the Year: Team 17 Computer Game of the Year: &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; Sensible Software Best Licensed Computer Game: &amp;ldquo;Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis&amp;rdquo; LucasArts Programming Team of the Year: LucasArts Best Computer Simulation: &amp;ldquo;Formula One Grand Prix&amp;rdquo; Geoff Crammond/Microprose Team 17 announced two new titles, both racing games: &amp;ldquo;Overdrive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;F1 Challenge&amp;rdquo; (the latter would be renamed to &amp;ldquo;F17 Challenge&amp;rdquo; after some legal issues).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/21/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 09:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/21/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Virgin snapped up Sensi&amp;rsquo;s upcoming war game, &amp;ldquo;Cannon Fodder&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;TV show Gamesmaster was set to return for a second series and the production company were on the look out for young talent to take part.&#xA;DMI had signed a deal with German developer Prestige to bring their games to the UK. First up was &amp;ldquo;Doofus&amp;rdquo;, which would be followed by &amp;ldquo;Sword of Honour&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Catch&amp;rsquo;em&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Ocean were porting the Nintendo hit &amp;ldquo;Bart Versus the World&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #5 June/July 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 22:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</guid>
      <description>In this issue you can find:&#xA;A bit of a rant by the Ed on the &amp;ldquo;joys&amp;rdquo; of running a software mail order service and dealing with clueless, impatient and down right rude customers calling up. A report from the first European Computer Trade Show, which sounded like a right disappointment: &amp;ldquo;Where were the First Ever Showings? The Exclusive Demos? The Sneako Previews? Well, they certainly weren&amp;rsquo;t present on the day I visited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 08:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Firebird closed a deal with Activision/Electric Dreams which would see the budget publisher re-releasing a slew of older titles from the US for £1.99 each.&#xA;No changes at Zzap! this month, though Julian Rignall got engaged to Glenys Powell, the “ever-effervescent” Editorial Assistant.&#xA;Zzap! launched in Italy. Note the lack of “64” - Speccy, Atari, MSX and C16 gamers would all be catered for.&#xA;The Sensi Software lads were wrapping up their next game: the awesome &amp;ldquo;Wizball”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 08:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw C&amp;amp;VG getting a revamp based on reader feedback. Coin ops and consoles would get more pages, the adventure section got a make over, there was more space dedicated to previews and overall there would be a lot more colour. The announcement of these changes referenced the fact that some features were dropped, but they didn’t actually specify which. Somewhat worryingly, there were no adventure game reviews - just some tips.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 08:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Antony Jacobson wrote a withering attack on Zzap! and Crash in Computer Trade Weekly. It really was oddly vitriolic and included such gems as: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; a certain kind of magazine should only be handled with rubber gloves and antiseptic fire tongs. No-one forces them to publish contagious rubbish but magazines that do so are not simply to be described as boring, but debasing the values of their readership&amp;hellip; and polluting the social and commercial environment in which we live and work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/21/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 08:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/21/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The issue came with a &amp;ldquo;Barbarian II&amp;rdquo; poster.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Pandora&amp;rdquo; was a new sci-fi game from Firebird where character interaction was as important as blasting.&#xA;London&amp;rsquo;s The Museum of Mankind opened a new exhibit that made use of video discs and computers to create a game where visitors would learn what life in the Arctic was like.&#xA;The first game to hit the shelves from new publisher Electra was to be &amp;ldquo;Better Dead than Alien&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 07:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News The &amp;ldquo;silly season&amp;rdquo; was upon us with new releases rather sparse as programmers/software houses focussed their sights on Christmas.&#xA;Kevin Toms was putting the finishing touches on the long awaited &amp;ldquo;Football Manager II&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Domark were producing &amp;ldquo;Live and Let Die&amp;rdquo;, a game based on Roger Moore&amp;rsquo;s first Bond film.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Barbarian II&amp;rdquo; was due for release in August and promised a &amp;ldquo;multiload extravaganza&amp;rdquo; with a large, mappable area.&#xA;In last month&amp;rsquo;s review of &amp;ldquo;Stealth Mission&amp;rdquo;, Zzap!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 07:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News US Gold had signed a deal to sponsor race driver David Hall&amp;rsquo;s car for the Formula Forward season.&#xA;Meanwhile, US Gold released &amp;ldquo;Deeper Dungeons&amp;rdquo; for those &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo; fans wanting more.&#xA;The British Open AD&amp;amp;D Championships were held at the Reading University Students Union building. Up to 600 people were expected.&#xA;Laser tag guns were the toy of the moment. The two main contenders were &amp;ldquo;Laser Combat&amp;rdquo; from Action GT, and &amp;ldquo;Laser Tag&amp;rdquo; from Mattel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 03:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Activision announced &amp;ldquo;Murder on the Missippi[sic]&amp;rdquo;, which was being written by Adam Bellin. Rather oddly C&amp;amp;VG described Bellin as &amp;ldquo;part of the team who produced the controversial &amp;lsquo;Ghostbusters&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;. I have no idea what the controversy was.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Dr Blitzen and the Islands of Arcanum&amp;rdquo; would be the followup to the popular &amp;ldquo;Dynamite Dan&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Alligata released &amp;ldquo;Who Dares Wins II&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Colin McLinton won Firebird&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Elite&amp;rdquo; competition. There were 11 finalists, all of which had achieved Elite status.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 02:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News One year and two months after Newsfield launched LM, the decision was made to end the experiment. Only 4 issues of the ambitious magazine were published and it had struggled to gain the support of ad agencies and their clients. The magazine had set out to cover &amp;ldquo;every aspect of life&amp;rdquo; for the youth audience, but was seen as being &amp;ldquo;too widely targeted&amp;rdquo; by advertisers, despite healthy sales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 05:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Computers and Art&amp;rdquo; was a new travelling exhibition that had just opened at the IBM Gallery of Science and Art in NYC. It was an attempt to bring &amp;ldquo;computer art&amp;rdquo; into the mainstream - not just graphics, but works using fabric etc. Elsewhere, Carnegie Mellon began a course on writing &amp;ldquo;interactive fiction.&amp;rdquo; CRL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Wolfman&amp;rdquo; was in the news for failing to be slapped with a British Board of Censors rating certificate, unlike their previous adventures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-crash-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 05:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-crash-88/</guid>
      <description>News On the back of the news that the price of the Spectrum 128K had dropped following the acquisition by Amstrad, rumours started to circulate that a 256K &amp;ldquo;games machine&amp;rdquo; was in the pipeline. According to the rumours the machine would be Spectrum based but would use credit card sized &amp;ldquo;cartridges&amp;rdquo;. Reactions were mixed - while this would drastically reduce piracy, software houses feared Amstrad having control over what games would be released.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/16/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 04:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/16/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Atari announced they were about to launch a new range of computers. First there were the new XEs which were basically upgraded/re-styled 800 XLs. But more importantly were the STs which would provide an impressive jump from the existing machines. Robert Schifreen who had written the &amp;ldquo;Bug hunter&amp;rdquo; and Micronet columns for C&amp;amp;VG was arrested for hacking. Notable Reviews &amp;ldquo;Starion&amp;rdquo; Melbourne House - Spectrum Game of the Month 10/10 &amp;ldquo;Programmer David Webb, a 19-year old student, spent nine months working on Starion - and if there&amp;rsquo;s any justice in the world he will be rewarded with a number one hit!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
