<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:26:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Point-and-Click Adventure Games pre-orders are live!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/4/the-art-of-point-and-click-adventure-games-pre-orders-are-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/4/the-art-of-point-and-click-adventure-games-pre-orders-are-live/</guid>
      <description>There is a slight irony around my love of point &amp;amp; click adventures over the last few years. Back in the 8 and 16 bit days I would often pour my disdain on these games while proclaiming the superiority of the good old text adventure. I was willing to accept the static images that accompanied games like &amp;ldquo;The Guild of Thieves&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;The Boggit&amp;rdquo;, but controlling a pixeled character and clicking on things with a limited set of verbs?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Kickstarters</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 23:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a good time to be a retro gaming fan recently with several promising Kickstarters. Of course I dawdled too long on writing about them, so some have already finished, but they&amp;rsquo;re still worth keeping an eye on.&#xA;Reformation 2 from Matt Gray The first Reformation took a little longer to ship than originally expected, but it was well worth the wait. 5 CDs of excellent remakes of some of the best tunes to grace the C64 (and therefore, games in general).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Commodore Amiga: a visual Commpendium&#34; Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 01:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Following on from his beautiful C64 book, Sam Dyer is running a Kickstarter campaign to give the same loving treatment to the Amiga. He has an impressive list of prominent Amiga folk lined up as contributors and - quite rightly - plans to include a section on the demo scene, which played a huge role in making the machine so amazing. The campaign smashed through the initial goal within a short time but there are still some rather tasty looking stretch goals that would be great to hit.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
