<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>july on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/july/</link>
    <description>Recent content in july on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:34:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/july/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2020/7/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2020/7/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News The fate of Commodore UK was close to becoming a bit clearer with an announcement regarding a new owner was due &amp;ldquo;any day now&amp;rdquo;. The &amp;ldquo;most solid&amp;rdquo; information pointed to a &amp;ldquo;Far-Eastern&amp;rdquo; company, with Acer, Samsung and Goldstar all rumoured to be in the running. While the UK office had continued trading, they weren&amp;rsquo;t receiving any new units to sell which meant they had to make do with whatever stock they had in their warehouses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/7/31/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 07:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/7/31/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The first images of the fighters in Team 17&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Body Blows 2&amp;rdquo; surfaced.
Domark snapped up the rights to the F1 championship, with the appropriately named &amp;ldquo;F1&amp;rdquo; being the first title out the door.
The infamous &amp;ldquo;Night Trap&amp;rdquo; had resulted in politicians &amp;amp; law makers wanting to create a new mandatory classification scheme for games.
After Ocean signed a large deal with them, Digital Image Design revealed two upcoming games: &amp;ldquo;TFX&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Inferno: The Odyssey Continues&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/7/30/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/7/30/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News The upcoming Christmas battle for number one looked to be between Konami’s “Batman Returns”, Acclaim’s “Alien 3” and Ocean’s latest movie license signing: “Lethal Weapon 3”.
Commodore continued their run of stupid business decision with the announcement that they were to stop selling the A500 Plus in favour of the new A600.
The ‘92 Barcelona Olympics would soon be starting and Ocean was preparing “Espagna 92” [sic] to take on US Gold’s “Megasports”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #5 June/July 1989</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 22:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</guid>
      <description>In this issue you can find:
A bit of a rant by the Ed on the &amp;ldquo;joys&amp;rdquo; of running a software mail order service and dealing with clueless, impatient and down right rude customers calling up. A report from the first European Computer Trade Show, which sounded like a right disappointment: &amp;ldquo;Where were the First Ever Showings? The Exclusive Demos? The Sneako Previews? Well, they certainly weren&amp;rsquo;t present on the day I visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/7/16/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 06:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/7/16/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Software Projects announced that they were reducing their prices to £5.95 in the run up to Christmas. Others were expected to follow suit, though that did seem somewhat unlikely as that’s a steep drop down from £9.95. Gary Penn pondered how lower prices might affect the quality of games - lower budgets for development? less licensed tie-ins? (The latter was considered a good thing)
Ciaran Brennan was promoted to Assistant Editor, and Gary Liddon was due to make his return next month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/7/4/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 08:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/7/4/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News The industry was abuzz with talk of Nintendo’s Game Boy. The handheld had seen a very successful launch in Japan with over 500,000 units being sold (300,000 of which were on the first day), and now the question was when would it reach the UK. Nintendo were unable to give any dates, but confirmed they had plans…
The FIST telephone game was getting a sequel (I have no idea what this was).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/7/14/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/7/14/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News The Commodore Show in London was the biggest dedicated C64 event of the year. Zzap!&amp;rsquo;s own booth proved very popular - especially when games programmers dropped by to show off their latest wares (often yet to be signed to a publisher). So why weren&amp;rsquo;t the crowds impressed with the show? It seemed software houses were very thin on the ground&amp;hellip;
Tony Takoushi was at the show touting a new gizmo called &amp;ldquo;Speedos&amp;rdquo; which was a mod for 1541 floppy drives enabling much faster load times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/7/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/7/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The 1988 Euros were about to start and Grandslam were putting the finishing touches on &amp;ldquo;Peter Beardsley’s International Football&amp;rdquo;.
Titus was following up their &amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;Fire and Forget&amp;rdquo;, a vehicular combat game featuring cars decked out with an array of weapons.
Crocodile Dundee was heading back to the cinemas, but this time his antics would take place in New York.
German developer house Logotron was to release a heavily Defender inspired shooter, &amp;ldquo;Stay Ray&amp;rdquo;, for the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/7/27/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 07:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/7/27/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Mastertronic was to release a followup to &amp;ldquo;Kane&amp;rdquo;, unsurprisingly called &amp;ldquo;Kane II&amp;rdquo;.
Up until this point Microprose&amp;rsquo;s games had been distributed in the UK by US Gold, but now they were going to handle it all themselves. This would allow them to use much fancier packaging, for starters.
Tynesoft and Virgin were both readying new compilations.
Elite started a new budget label, Encore, which would see their back catalogue classics re-released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/7/19/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 06:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/7/19/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Dungeons, Amethysts, Alchemists &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Everythin&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; from Atlantis Software promised &amp;ldquo;the occasional rude word and sexual innuendo, novice nuns, entangled lovers and busty barmaids&amp;rdquo;. The cover of the game came with a &amp;ldquo;Not suitable for persons under the age of 16&amp;rdquo; label.
Paul Hardcastle had a big hit with his Vietnam war song &amp;ldquo;19&amp;rdquo; and Cascade were turning it into a game. Rather interestingly, the player would be faced with a choice at the start: fight the war or the draft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/7/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 04:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/7/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Leading this month&amp;rsquo;s news was US Gold&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;World Cup Carnival&amp;rdquo;, the official World Cup &amp;lsquo;86 game. A team of programmers had been working on it for 6 months and US Gold boldly claimed that it would &amp;ldquo;reach new standards in football simulation&amp;rdquo;. Sadly it would turn out to be one of the most infamously terrible games of the time, and was just a repackaging of an older title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/7/19/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 21:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/7/19/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Not a game as such, but the latest book from William Gibson, &amp;ldquo;Mona Lisa Overdrive&amp;rdquo;, was about to hit the shelves. To mark the occasion, the Cyberpunk theme would be visited several times in this issue.
What was billed &amp;ldquo;the first mass-market desktop-publishing (DTP) packag&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; was launched by mouse manufacturer AMS for PC-XT and AT compatibles. It featured a mouse, a handheld scanner and software - all for only £447.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/7/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 06:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/7/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Plans were afoot to build Britain&amp;rsquo;s first Laser tag centre. It would be built on Wellington Pier in Great Yarmouth and promised to &amp;ldquo;take leisure and entertainment &amp;lsquo;into the 21st century.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;
Games Workshop was about to release &amp;ldquo;Chaos&amp;rdquo; by a certain Julian Gollop who would go onto produce such genre defining games as Rebelstar and XCom. He has a remake of &amp;ldquo;Chaos&amp;rdquo; underway and you can follow his progress on his blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
