<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>December on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/december/</link>
    <description>Recent content in December on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/december/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2020/12/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2020/12/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News While there was still no news on the fate of Commodore, the UK office was busy preparing for the World of Commodore show, which was to take place at the Wembley Exhibition Centre, December 9th through 11th. It was to be a “buying show” where the primary goal was for attendees to do a bit of shopping, but The One wondered if there’d be any Commodore kit left to purchase by then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/12/17/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 07:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2019/12/17/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Editor David Upchurch had “deserted” the mag for a couple of months which left Simon Byron in charge.
The CD32 received some encouraging news as high street retailer Menzies announced they would be stocking it in time for Christmas.
After some months of silence (on the Amiga at any rate), Thalamus was about to release “S.U.B.” (unreleased). The One wondered what had happened to “Arsenal” - rumour was the programmer had gone missing&amp;hellip; It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see the light of day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/12/12/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 06:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/12/12/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Psygnosis announced &amp;ldquo;Lemmings 2: The Tribes&amp;rdquo;. This took a slightly different twist on the original, with the goal being to re-unite twelve tribes of Lemmings, each tribe having a different theme complete with their own abilities.
An update to Sensi Software&amp;rsquo;s smash hit &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; had arrived and boasted a bevy of new and improved features, including red &amp;amp; yellow cards, the back pass rule and more competent goalies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #8 December &#39;88/January &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</guid>
      <description>As we bid goodbye to the 80s, the Editor pondered what lay ahead in the coming decade. After the world had lived in fear of nuclear annihalation for so many years, the arrival of the likes of Gorbachev meant we could now focus on the &amp;ldquo;prospect of irreversible doom&amp;rdquo; thanks to global warming. Technology would, of course, play a significant role in what was to come: &amp;ldquo;Our ability to manipulate information and communicate the results to the whole World within seconds, could lead us into chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/12/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 07:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/12/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Hot off the presses from Japan was news of the PC Engine Super Grafx which looked to build on the already impressive original. New custom chips meant it could chuck around 128 sprites (up from 64) and the cartridges saw a decent boost in size. Perhaps the most intriguing aspect was the Power Console add on which the console slotted into and featured a full on steering yoke, a gear stick/throttle, LCD clock/timer, LED radar display, numeric keypad and a bunch of buttons and knobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #2 Dec 1988/Jan 1989</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 08:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</guid>
      <description>Postal strikes had caused delays to the first issue, and - whether it was due to this or some other reason - November came and went without the second issue. Going forward they would be sticking to the every-other-month schedule.
Contents:
Interview with Philippe Ulrich, head of the EXXOS group at French software house ERE Informatique which had recently released the rather original and intriguing &amp;ldquo;Captain Blood&amp;rdquo;. A somewhat tongue in cheek guide to playing adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December Games Revisited</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/31/december-games-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 04:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/31/december-games-revisited/</guid>
      <description>One of these days I’ll get my act together and not wait until the dying hours of the month (and even year in this case) to write these things… With that said, I did manage to have a decent play on a bunch of the biggest December games from 1986 and 1988.
”The Sentinel”, Geoff Crammond/Firebird, 1986
Reviewed Zzap!64 December 1986.
I recall playing this quite a bit on the C64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 04:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News More changes were afoot, with Strategy Front writer Sean Masterson moving on and the start of a make over that would take effect during the next few months.
Last month Zzap! teased readers by asking them to check out a screenshot of the hotly anticipated arcade conversion of &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; and then failed to print it. To make up for the error they provided not one but four shots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/15/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 07:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/15/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News There were big changes at the mag, with Tony Takoushi &amp;ldquo;getting the boot&amp;rdquo; and replaced by Julian Rignall. This issue hit 114 pages.
Mandarin Software were developing &amp;ldquo;Grand Prix Circuit&amp;rdquo;, an F1 racing sim to be published by Accolade.
Elite&amp;rsquo;s lineup for Christmas included &amp;ldquo;Space Harrier 2&amp;rdquo; for the 16bits (seems that Grandslam actually had the rights for that, weird) , &amp;ldquo;Mike Read’s Pop Quiz&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Storm Warrior&amp;rdquo;. Their arcade truck racer &amp;ldquo;Supertrux&amp;rdquo; was narrowly going to miss the holiday season and was due early January.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/12/29/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 05:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/12/29/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Rainbird&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Universal Military Simulator&amp;rdquo; for the ST promised wargaming fans the ability to re-enact a vast array of different battles, including ones between armies from different time periods.
&amp;ldquo;Stratton&amp;rdquo; from CRL would see the player attempt to shutdown the automated defence units of a space station which had suffered a terrorist attack and had turned on its inhabitants. (unable to find evidence of this being released)
Bike racing game &amp;ldquo;500 Grand Prix&amp;rdquo;, published by French house Loricels, was heading to the ST, IBM and C64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 03:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Ciaran Brennan had only just taken over the helm at ZZap! but he was already moving onto pastures new. This ushered in Julian Rignall as editor.
US Gold acquired the rights to the &amp;ldquo;Rolling Thunder&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Roadblasters&amp;rdquo; coin ops. Meanwhile, the publisher dropped the price of all of their C64 disk games from £14.99 to £11.99 (thanks to economies of scale).
Telecomsoft scored a bit of a coup, signing Graftgold away from Hewson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 02:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Probe Software was porting two arcade games, &amp;ldquo;Quartet&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Enduro Racer&amp;rdquo; to home computers for Activision.
&amp;ldquo;Tracker&amp;rdquo; from Rainbird promised tactical battles against an &amp;ldquo;artificially intelligent enemy&amp;rdquo; which would involve strategy and fast 3D arcade sections.
Beyond continued to promote their much hyped &amp;ldquo;Star Trek&amp;rdquo; game, which would never see a release. They also revealed &amp;ldquo;Infodroid&amp;rdquo; - a new game from Denton Designs.
After Ocean&amp;rsquo;s exceptionally disappointing &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo; a few months earlier, Activision owned the US rights to the cartoon and David Crane had been working on an entirely different &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo; game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/12/22/this-month-in-tgm-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 22:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/12/22/this-month-in-tgm-88/</guid>
      <description>News The console wars were heating up as rumours surfaced that Nintendo and Sega were working on 16bit machines. Neither the NES or Master System had managed to gain much of a foothold in the UK - both machines selling around 45,000 units each - but the tide did seem to be turning. Code Masters were rather bullish about the console market, with Operations Manager Bruce Everiss being particularly enthusiastic about the Konix Slipstream: &amp;ldquo;I think Konix has the potential to be another Amstrad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/12/15/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 22:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/12/15/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News A Crash contingent went down to London for the 20th ZX Microfair. While the event was usually held in the &amp;ldquo;cavernous&amp;rdquo; Royal Horticultural Hall, a booking mixup meant this one had to move to &amp;ldquo;several rooms and various floors&amp;rdquo; at Central Hall in Westminster. There were very few new products to talk about, the only ones receiving a mention being &amp;ldquo;The Professional Adventure Writing System&amp;rdquo;, a new disk interface from Rockfort called &amp;ldquo;The Disciple&amp;rdquo; and Romantic Robot&amp;rsquo;s video digitiser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/12/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 21:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/12/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Ariolasoft released a couple of screenshots from a new game which promised to be a &amp;ldquo;totally interactive graphic adventure &amp;lsquo;movie&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; The game, &amp;ldquo;Wild West&amp;rdquo;, received luke warm reviews, but it was notable in that it was one of those rarities at the time: a game developed behind the iron curtain.
Activision were to take on EA&amp;rsquo;s excellent &amp;ldquo;Racing Destruction Set&amp;rdquo; with their own racing game with a built in editor called &amp;ldquo;Fast Tracks&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
