<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 12:13:24 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Sudden Change of Plans</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/posts/a-sudden-change-of-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 12:13:24 +1300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/posts/a-sudden-change-of-plans/</guid>
      <description>At the end of August - almost 29 years to the day since I begun my career in the games industry - I resigned and entered into what I&amp;rsquo;ve been describing as &amp;ldquo;retirement&amp;rdquo;. The quotes indicating that I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite decided what form it will take.&#xA;Quitting had been on my mind for a while, in that typically vague wishy washy &amp;ldquo;oh, I dunno - sometime in the future&amp;rdquo; way, but a surprise decision by company execs to pursue a business partnership I felt was deeply unethical and problematic suddenly brought the need to make a change front and centre with a real jolt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 07:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Andy Nuttall reckoned this issue was &amp;ldquo;more fruitsome and lovely than ever&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;A new contender for acquiring Commodore entered the ring: Escom, who had put in a bid for £5 million. The Commodore UK team downplayed this saying the bid was low and their own offer was still favourite. Meanwhile, Escom had bought out failed UK high street shop chain Rumbelows.&#xA;Retailer Silica were staying the course with their Amiga sales and launched a new CD32 bundle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/4/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 06:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/5/4/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News The One had had a bit of a facelift with the Contents page getting a re- design, along with various sections getting re-labelled.&#xA;The big news for the month was that Commodore UK had announced a new Amiga: the A1(M). The specs included &amp;ldquo;32 megabytes of RAM, a 1 gigabyte hard drive, 32-bit graphics card, 64-bit processor, 8x speed CD-ROM drive&amp;rdquo;. And of course it was The One&amp;rsquo;s April Fools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 06:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Despite some recent colossal flops at the box office (&amp;ldquo;Mario Brothers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Double Dragon&amp;rdquo;) it seemed the success of &amp;ldquo;Street Fighter&amp;rdquo; was enough for Hollywood to take another stab it with &amp;ldquo;Mortal Kombat&amp;rdquo;. The only &amp;ldquo;big names&amp;rdquo; attached to it were Christopher Lambert and Talisa Soto (a Bond girl in &amp;ldquo;Licence to Kill&amp;rdquo;). Unknown Paul Anderson was to direct. Elsewhere there were rumours of movies based on &amp;ldquo;Doom&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Myst&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/3/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/3/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Andy Nuttall officially took over the Editor role.&#xA;If you thought that the future of Commodore would be sorted out by this month, then you were sorely mistaken. The end did seem in sight (something that had been said for nearly a year), with only Commodore UK and US-based CEI remaining in the running. Meanwhile retailers were getting frustrated with the lack of new stock. With that said, apparently 82% of stores surveyed were keen to continue selling the machines (if they were provided some to sell&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/1/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/1/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Apparently the higher ups at EMAP were putting pressure on The One to cut back on pages and coverdisks, but Acting Editor Andy Nuttall and team stood firm, delivering a bumper issue. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t without its price, tho: &amp;ldquo;So, it&amp;rsquo;s taken us ages longer than normal to write, the coverdisks nearly killed us, and getting in the finished version of SWOS for review was a nightmare.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The fate of Commodore remained up in the air, with little news to be had.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/12/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/12/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News While there was still no news on the fate of Commodore, the UK office was busy preparing for the World of Commodore show, which was to take place at the Wembley Exhibition Centre, December 9th through 11th. It was to be a “buying show” where the primary goal was for attendees to do a bit of shopping, but The One wondered if there’d be any Commodore kit left to purchase by then.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/11/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/11/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Simon Byron announced he was stepping down to work at a chip shop on the outskirts of Bognor: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that the life of a simple chippy is preferable to slogging my guts out on Britain&amp;rsquo;s least popular Amiga games magazine.&amp;rdquo; Andy Nuttall would be filling in as Acting Editor.&#xA;Frustrating times for Amiga journos and fans alike as there was still no news from Commodore on the future of the company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/9/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 07:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/9/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News After reporting that the saga of Commodore&amp;rsquo;s fate would be resolved &amp;ldquo;any day now&amp;rdquo; for the past few months, The One decided to quit guessing the timeline. In the latest twist, word arrived Commodore UK (lead by David Pleasance and Colin Proudfoot) were now the favourites with their proposal of a Management Buy Out, with Samsung apparently still keen. At the US head office Mehdi Ali was officially out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 08:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News While Commodore was still without a buyer, word leaked that the company leading the pack was in fact Samsung who were looking to gain more of a foothold in the European market. It seemed everything was hanging on that deal.&#xA;Dominik Diamond was rumoured to be returning to &amp;ldquo;Gamesmaster&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;A report from Mintel showed that the UK games industry contracted by 4% last year. The market value in 1993 was £670 million compared to £700 million in 1992.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/7/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/7/29/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News The fate of Commodore UK was close to becoming a bit clearer with an announcement regarding a new owner was due &amp;ldquo;any day now&amp;rdquo;. The &amp;ldquo;most solid&amp;rdquo; information pointed to a &amp;ldquo;Far-Eastern&amp;rdquo; company, with Acer, Samsung and Goldstar all rumoured to be in the running. While the UK office had continued trading, they weren&amp;rsquo;t receiving any new units to sell which meant they had to make do with whatever stock they had in their warehouses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/6/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/6/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News News broke as the mag went to press that Commodore worldwide had basically filed for administration in the Bahamas, where the company was registered. Just what this meant was unclear, but things did not look good. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly surprising considering the losses the company had posted over the last couple of years, though Commodore UK had performed well. While this move was obviously concerning, The One were confident that the continued popularity of the Amiga would mean a positive outcome one way or another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 22:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/31/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Andy Nuttall (aka “Nutts”) joined the mag as Deputy Editor after having done five months hard time at ST Format.&#xA;Third time’s the charm - or so Commodore hoped with its third CD32 bundle since launch. The Voyage pack included “Microcosm” and “The Chaos Engine”, plus four games from the two existing bundles while stocks lasted, all for £299.99.&#xA;Codemasters were bringing “Captain Dynamo” and the “Dizzy CD Collection” to the CD32.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Well, that was quite a ride</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/7/well-that-was-quite-a-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 22:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/5/7/well-that-was-quite-a-ride/</guid>
      <description>When I made the decision to join Magic Leap back at the start of 2013, I told my friends that I had no idea where it was going to lead, but I knew it would be a ride&amp;hellip; and that it was.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s two weeks to the day that myself, my team here in NZ and over 1,000 of my workmates at offices across the world were laid off. Well, technically those of us in NZ entered into a &amp;ldquo;consultation&amp;rdquo; period of a few days as mandated by NZ law, but that ended on Monday with all of us being made redundant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/4/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/4/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Contrary to last month’s news, while ex-The One editor David Upchurch had been assigned to a new mag, it was to EMAP’s latest launch, PC Games, and not a reboot of Sinclair User&amp;hellip; which made a little more sense.&#xA;Ocean struck a deal with Virgin to release twelve of its games on Hit Squad, their budget label. The lineup included “Cannon Fodder”, “Dune”, “Dune 2”, “Jimmy White’s Whirlwind Snooker”, “Archer Maclean’s Pool”, “Realms”, “Legend of Kyrandia”, “Supremacy”, “KGB”, “Reach for the Skies”, “Shuttle” and “Lure of the Temptress”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 05:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>theone199403&#xA;News This was to be David Upchurch&amp;rsquo;s last issue as Editor as off to head up EMAP&amp;rsquo;s relaunch of&amp;hellip; Sinclair User. Apparently the Speccy had been seeing a resurgence, though I find that a little hard to believe. At any rate, Simon Byron was to take over the helm.&#xA;Team 17 were embracing the CD32 starting with &amp;ldquo;Ultimate Body Blows&amp;rdquo;, a revamped version of their beat&amp;rsquo;em up featuring new AGA backdrops, digitised speech and a digital CD soundtrack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/2/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 06:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/2/25/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Editor David Upchurch saw a bright 1994 ahead for the Amiga.&#xA;Word on the street was that Commodore UK were close to striking a deal with LucasArts that would see them bring their PC hits &amp;ldquo;Rebel Assault&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Day of the Tentacle&amp;rdquo; to the CD32. (It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen)&#xA;While England had suffered the shame of failing to qualify for the upcoming World Cup, Virgin were keen to join with Adidas to sponsor a new initiative to promote youth footballing skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 08:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Late breaking news was that Maxis were porting &amp;ldquo;Sim City 2000&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga. The PC original was impressive, but would it survive the translation?&#xA;It looked like &amp;ldquo;The Second Samurai&amp;rdquo; would be Vivid Image Design&amp;rsquo;s last title for a little while as they were going all in on CD gaming. Mev Dinc and his team were taking the interesting approach of insisting that all design and illustration work be finished before a single line of code was written.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #12 August/September 1990</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/1/2/confidential-magazine-12-augustseptember-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this issue&amp;hellip;&#xA;The editor reflected on 2 years of Special Reserve: memberships had shot passed 25,000, with 5,500 of those also subscribing to Official Secrets (and, therefore, Confidential). While there had been the usual summer lull in game sales, they were expecting a bumper Xmas due to the Amiga&amp;rsquo;s popularity and had decided to also carry Atari Lynx, Sega Megadrive and CDTV titles.&#xA;The news included details of SSI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Secret of Silver Blades&amp;rdquo;, a bunch of upcoming flight sims, Alexey Pajitnov&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Tetris&amp;rdquo; followup &amp;ldquo;Welltris&amp;rdquo;, along with rumours of a new adventure from Level 9 (&amp;ldquo;Billy the Kid&amp;rdquo;), a game based on the book &amp;ldquo;Neuromancer&amp;rdquo;, and Sierra bringing &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Quest IV&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Colonel&amp;rsquo;s Bequest&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/12/17/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 07:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/12/17/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Editor David Upchurch had “deserted” the mag for a couple of months which left Simon Byron in charge.&#xA;The CD32 received some encouraging news as high street retailer Menzies announced they would be stocking it in time for Christmas.&#xA;After some months of silence (on the Amiga at any rate), Thalamus was about to release “S.U.B.” (unreleased). The One wondered what had happened to “Arsenal” - rumour was the programmer had gone missing&amp;hellip; It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see the light of day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/11/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 03:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/11/29/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The CD32 launch hadn&amp;rsquo;t exactly gotten off to a great start, with sales looking rather lacklustre. To try to turn things around Commodore kicked off a marketing push starting with a big presence at the Live &amp;lsquo;93 exhibition and an upcoming TV advert. Satellite stations would be targeted first before switching to ITV and C4 over the Christmas period. Apparently Live &amp;lsquo;93 was such a big hit that Commodore had already booked its presence at next year&amp;rsquo;s event.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/10/30/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 07:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/10/30/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Renegade&amp;rsquo;s release schedule was looking rather impressive with “Uridium 2” first up, followed soon after by “Turrican 3” and “Elfmania”. If that wasn’t enough, “Ruff ‘n’ Tumble”, “Sensible World of Soccer”, “Flight of the Amazon Queen” and “Z”) were all due by the end of the year. The last one - a real time strategy game from the Bitmap Brothers - was particularly interesting since it’d be years before it saw the light of day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/9/29/zlkv83ofoauysfxxv490x1maf0etuj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 06:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/9/29/zlkv83ofoauysfxxv490x1maf0etuj/</guid>
      <description>News In an effort to draw some attention away from the other popular gaming mascots, Mindscape decided to enter &amp;ldquo;Alfred the Chicken&amp;rdquo; in the Christchurch by-election. Alfred managed to bring in 18 votes - two ahead of the Rainbow Alliance Party. The resulting media &amp;ldquo;circus&amp;rdquo; was certainly worth the 500 quid it cost them.&#xA;Europress teased some screen shots of racing sim &amp;ldquo;Rally&amp;rdquo;, though they were from the PC version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/8/28/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 08:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/8/28/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News A year after announcing they were leaving the Amiga behind, news arrived that Sierra On-Line were bringing &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Quest VI&amp;rdquo; to our beloved machine. The conversion was being handled by Charles Cecil&amp;rsquo;s Revolution which had created a hybrid of its &amp;ldquo;Virtual Theatre&amp;rdquo; system for the job to ensure the game felt at home on the system, rather than some shoddy PC port.&#xA;Krisalis spawned a new sub-label, Buzz, as home for its back catalogue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/7/31/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 07:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/7/31/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The first images of the fighters in Team 17&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Body Blows 2&amp;rdquo; surfaced.&#xA;Domark snapped up the rights to the F1 championship, with the appropriately named &amp;ldquo;F1&amp;rdquo; being the first title out the door.&#xA;The infamous &amp;ldquo;Night Trap&amp;rdquo; had resulted in politicians &amp;amp; law makers wanting to create a new mandatory classification scheme for games.&#xA;After Ocean signed a large deal with them, Digital Image Design revealed two upcoming games: &amp;ldquo;TFX&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Inferno: The Odyssey Continues&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Bride&#39;s Article</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/7/29/st-brides-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/7/29/st-brides-article/</guid>
      <description>This is a great piece on the mysterious text adventure creators, St Bride&amp;rsquo;s; an edited version of which appeared in GamesTM mag.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d written about them previously, but this article does a far better job at uncovering their somewhat bizarre story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/6/23/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 05:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/6/23/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News The Amiga had a strong showing at this year&amp;rsquo;s Golden Joysticks awards. Team 17 and Sensible Software won Software House of the Year and Computer Game of the Year respectively, with Jon Hare giving a &amp;ldquo;stirring speech warning against the dangers of complacency.&amp;rdquo; The Amiga related winners were:&#xA;Software House of the Year: Team 17 Computer Game of the Year: &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; Sensible Software Best Licensed Computer Game: &amp;ldquo;Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis&amp;rdquo; LucasArts Programming Team of the Year: LucasArts Best Computer Simulation: &amp;ldquo;Formula One Grand Prix&amp;rdquo; Geoff Crammond/Microprose Team 17 announced two new titles, both racing games: &amp;ldquo;Overdrive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;F1 Challenge&amp;rdquo; (the latter would be renamed to &amp;ldquo;F17 Challenge&amp;rdquo; after some legal issues).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/4/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/4/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News I&amp;rsquo;m guessing this was an April Fools joke, but the lead news story concerned PC game &amp;ldquo;X-Wing&amp;rdquo; appearing &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; the Amiga&amp;hellip; as in, it was a photo of an &amp;ldquo;X-Wing&amp;rdquo; box sitting on an Amiga&amp;hellip;&#xA;Mindscape revealed that their upcoming Gameboy platformer &amp;ldquo;Alfred Chicken&amp;rdquo; would be getting an Amiga release.&#xA;Ocean reckoned that the somewhat crowded car racer genre was in need of something with a bit more realism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/3/18/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 07:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/3/18/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Comic artist Dave Gibbons (of &amp;ldquo;Watchmen&amp;rdquo; fame) had been collaborating with Charles Cecil and Revolution Software on the cyberpunk point-and-click adventure &amp;ldquo;Beneath a Steel Sky&amp;rdquo;. It transpired that his involvement came about after he contacted The One to complain they&amp;rsquo;d forgotten to credit him for &amp;ldquo;Watchmen&amp;rdquo;. The mag decided to lend him an Amiga and a copy of &amp;ldquo;Deluxe Paint&amp;rdquo; for a followup article, which sparked his interest in computer art and lead to an introduction to Cecil.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/2/27/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 07:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/2/27/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Under the headline &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3 Shocker!&amp;rdquo; came the news that Dino Dini had parted ways with Anco and signed with Virgin to develop a &amp;ldquo;world-beating follow-up to &amp;lsquo;Kick Off 2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;, with the working title &amp;ldquo;Goal!&amp;rdquo;. The move cast doubts on whether there would be an official &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3&amp;rdquo;, though co-designer Steve Screech remained at Anco.&#xA;From the ashes of the hyped &amp;ldquo;Apocalypse&amp;rdquo;, Jason Perkins and Robin Levy were continuing their partnership on a new game from Renegade, &amp;ldquo;Ruff n&amp;rsquo; Tumble&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Game: Part 4 - Item Activation, Interpolation and... Bugs</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/2/24/diary-of-a-game-part-4-item-activation-interpolation-and-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/2/24/diary-of-a-game-part-4-item-activation-interpolation-and-bugs/</guid>
      <description>Since my last update work has been a bit quieter post-ship and I enjoyed an unexpectedly low key Christmas break, so surely I&amp;rsquo;ve made a lot of progress, right? Well&amp;hellip; life decided to intervene which resulted in a lot less time to work on the game than I had hoped. But I have managed to tick off a few things on the long to-do list&amp;hellip;&#xA;Item Activation The main - and, I must admit, only - playing facing addition is items that need to be activated before they can be matched.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/1/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 06:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/1/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Digital Image Design had two new titles on the way. The first up was a &amp;ldquo;pseudo-sequel&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Epic&amp;rdquo; - called &amp;ldquo;Odyssey&amp;rdquo; - set 90 years further in the future and would feature more of an open world feel. Sadly it looks like it was never released.. The second was another sequel, jet fighter sim &amp;ldquo;TFX Inferno&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Relative newcomer Miracle Games were rather bullish about their upcoming platformer, &amp;ldquo;Miracle Bat&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/12/12/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 06:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/12/12/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Psygnosis announced &amp;ldquo;Lemmings 2: The Tribes&amp;rdquo;. This took a slightly different twist on the original, with the goal being to re-unite twelve tribes of Lemmings, each tribe having a different theme complete with their own abilities.&#xA;An update to Sensi Software&amp;rsquo;s smash hit &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; had arrived and boasted a bevy of new and improved features, including red &amp;amp; yellow cards, the back pass rule and more competent goalies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/11/16/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 04:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/11/16/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Ocean had scored a #1 hit last Christmas with ”WWF Wrestlemania”, and hoped for a repeat in the form of ”WWF European Rampage”. While the earlier title had been panned by critics, the publisher were adamant this one would be better.&#xA;Commodore had announced the A4000 which, with a £1999 price tag, was very much targeted at the serious user. This fuelled rumours of a more affordable gaming machine and right as the mag went to press it looked like they had news&amp;hellip; though that would have to wait until next month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #10 April/May 1990</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/23/confidential-magazine-10-aprilmay-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 05:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/23/confidential-magazine-10-aprilmay-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s issue&amp;hellip;&#xA;The subject on the editor&amp;rsquo;s mind was, perhaps unexpectedly for an adventure gaming mag, taxation as he had a good rant about how much money from each game the club sold went to the HMRC.&#xA;Games making the news this month included several horror games (&amp;ldquo;Elvira&amp;rdquo;, [&amp;ldquo;Demon&amp;rsquo;s Tomb - The Awakening&amp;rdquo;][4403], [&amp;ldquo;Mystery of the Mummy&amp;rdquo;][4404]), the next title from The Bitmaps in the form of [&amp;ldquo;Cadaver&amp;rdquo;][4405], and some new games from Origin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/18/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 06:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/18/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News After months of mystery, Dino Dini&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Kick Off 3&amp;rdquo; was finally unveiled. Unlike the second instalment which was effectively tweaks and improvements to the original&amp;rsquo;s codebase, this one was re-coded from the ground up. Would it be able to take back the crown from &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer&amp;rdquo; ?&#xA;Speaking of which, the Sensi lads hadn&amp;rsquo;t been resting on their laurels and &amp;ldquo;Sensible Soccer v1.1&amp;rdquo; was due out next month. Player and club data had been updated for the new season, and there were other welcome changes such as re-written goalie behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Game: Part 3 - Sprites, Character Animation and Input</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/15/diary-of-a-game-part-3-sprites-character-animation-and-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/15/diary-of-a-game-part-3-sprites-character-animation-and-input/</guid>
      <description>Good grief, in my mind my last update was 3, maybe 4, months ago&amp;hellip; but May?! Well, I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve had a decent excuse.&#xA;Despite being embarassingly tardy with writing updates, some progress has been made. This is the current state of the game:&#xA;Sprites I&amp;rsquo;ve continued to stick with the C64&amp;rsquo;s standard character mode - I may well switch to the multicolour character mode, but a character approach seems to be working well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Of Magic Leap &amp; Dr Grordbort&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/15/of-magic-leap-amp-dr-grordborts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 21:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/15/of-magic-leap-amp-dr-grordborts/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a little break from looking back to the past and cast our gaze towards the tech of the present and future&amp;hellip;&#xA;Some (almost) 6 years ago I was approached to help out with a prototype Weta Workshop was developing with a highly secretive tech start up called Magic Leap. Workshop was well known, especially here in NZ, but there was little to no info out there about the latter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #9 February/March 1990</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/13/confidential-magazine-9-februarymarch-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 23:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/10/13/confidential-magazine-9-februarymarch-1990/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s editorial, The Boss Upstairs reflected on the success of the Special Reserve and Official Secrets clubs. The team had grown to 30 to cope with the increased orders, with some 200 being processed every day. The future looked bright.&#xA;Elsewhere in the mag:&#xA;A lengthy interview with Anita Sinclair of Magnetic Scrolls. The newest Special Reserve/Official Secrets team members were introduced. A back to basics primer on how to tackle adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/9/26/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 08:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/9/26/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Team 17 were having another crack at the beat &amp;rsquo;em up genre with &amp;ldquo;Body Blows&amp;rdquo;, along with a top down racer, &amp;ldquo;Overdrive&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Rumours started to circulate that there was yet another Amiga model on the way: the A800. It would be a 32bit machine with 68030 CPU and would sit between the A600 and the A1500. Commodore&amp;rsquo;s Market Director Kelly Sumner was adamant there would be no machine called the A800, but did confirm there was another machine on the way&amp;hellip; I assume it was the A1200.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/8/7/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/8/7/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Sad news this month as one of the oldest software houses closed up shop. Palace Software had been going for almost a decade and had been behind some cracking games, including &amp;ldquo;Barbarian&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Sacred Armour of Antiriad&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Shoot&amp;rsquo;em Up Construction Kit&amp;rdquo;. The move came after months of legal wrangling, and the London office became Titus&amp;rsquo;s UK HQ. It was unclear what would happen with titles like &amp;ldquo;Hostile Breed&amp;rdquo; (unreleased, but was actually finished and reviewed two issues earlier), and &amp;ldquo;Super Barbarian&amp;rdquo; (also unreleased).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/7/30/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/7/30/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News The upcoming Christmas battle for number one looked to be between Konami’s “Batman Returns”, Acclaim’s “Alien 3” and Ocean’s latest movie license signing: “Lethal Weapon 3”.&#xA;Commodore continued their run of stupid business decision with the announcement that they were to stop selling the A500 Plus in favour of the new A600.&#xA;The ‘92 Barcelona Olympics would soon be starting and Ocean was preparing “Espagna 92” [sic] to take on US Gold’s “Megasports”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/21/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 09:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/21/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News Virgin snapped up Sensi&amp;rsquo;s upcoming war game, &amp;ldquo;Cannon Fodder&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;TV show Gamesmaster was set to return for a second series and the production company were on the look out for young talent to take part.&#xA;DMI had signed a deal with German developer Prestige to bring their games to the UK. First up was &amp;ldquo;Doofus&amp;rdquo;, which would be followed by &amp;ldquo;Sword of Honour&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Catch&amp;rsquo;em&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Ocean were porting the Nintendo hit &amp;ldquo;Bart Versus the World&amp;rdquo; to the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #8 December &#39;88/January &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</guid>
      <description>As we bid goodbye to the 80s, the Editor pondered what lay ahead in the coming decade. After the world had lived in fear of nuclear annihalation for so many years, the arrival of the likes of Gorbachev meant we could now focus on the &amp;ldquo;prospect of irreversible doom&amp;rdquo; thanks to global warming. Technology would, of course, play a significant role in what was to come: &amp;ldquo;Our ability to manipulate information and communicate the results to the whole World within seconds, could lead us into chaos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/28/this-month-in-the-one-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 07:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/28/this-month-in-the-one-92/</guid>
      <description>News The transformation/infiltration/coup was complete and the team from ACE magazine had taken over reigns. The One for Amiga was now just &amp;ldquo;The One&amp;rdquo; as the ST mag had been rolled into ST Action. Notable changes included the scrapping of the developer profile section (which I personally liked) in favour of &amp;ldquo;special interviews&amp;rdquo; because the latter was &amp;ldquo;simply more interesting&amp;rdquo;, and more detailed, critical reviews (the previous team may have gone a little easy on games).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Game: Part 2 - Matching and Testing</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/20/diary-of-a-game-part-2-matching-and-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/20/diary-of-a-game-part-2-matching-and-testing/</guid>
      <description>Once again a depressing amount of time has passed since my last update. Given what&amp;rsquo;s on my plate workwise over the next few months I suspect the sporadic nature of my posts will continue. Thankfully I have continued to find time to chip away at the game, and some progress has been made.&#xA;After I managed to get a super rough first pass of the (very) initial base of the game done (with the balls/bubbles/whatever falling down the board and stacking up correctly), the next thing to tackle was the colour matching.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #7 October/November 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/6/confidential-magazine-7-octobernovember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 08:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/5/6/confidential-magazine-7-octobernovember-1989/</guid>
      <description>While they didn&amp;rsquo;t reveal actual subscription figures, the situation sounded a bit grim - the membership fee was to increase and there was a plea for readers to spread the word.&#xA;Meanwhile the helpline seemed to have switched to be a largely answering machine based service, and there was a request for solutions to a bunch of big recent adventures.&#xA;In this issue:&#xA;The news included details of several upcoming adventures from Electronic Arts and Gary Gygax consulting for Infogrames on &amp;ldquo;Drakkhen&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zzap!64 Annual 2019 Kickstarter launched</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/29/zzap64-annual-2019-kickstarter-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 22:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/29/zzap64-annual-2019-kickstarter-launched/</guid>
      <description>The folks behind last year&amp;rsquo;s rather excellent Crash Annual are back. Chris Wilkins, Roger Kean and Oli Frey have teamed up once again, this time to resurrect Crash&amp;rsquo;s sister mag, Zzap!64, for an annual due out towards the end of the year.&#xA;I must admit I didn&amp;rsquo;t read the Kickstarter pitch or even watch the video before backing it as there was no question in my mind, so it was only through seeing people discussing it online that I realised that the likes of Mel Croucher, Julian Rignall and Robin Hogg were also involved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/25/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/25/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</guid>
      <description>News It seemed this would be the final issue for the whole editorial crew as they were being replaced by the folk from &amp;ldquo;ex-sister magazine ACE&amp;rdquo;. Such a drastic move must&amp;rsquo;ve been a bitter pill to swallow, but it did mean the return of Gary Whitta.&#xA;TV companies had begun to take an interest in video games, with Channel 4&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Gamesmaster&amp;rdquo; clocking in at around 3 million viewers during its first season.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revision 2018</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/4/revision-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 06:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/4/revision-2018/</guid>
      <description>The main demoscene event of the year, Revision, took place last weekend in Saarbrücken, Germany. Once again I failed to actually make it over there, but I did manage to catch a fair amount of the live streams.&#xA;The full compo results can be found here.&#xA;Here are a few of my faves:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Point-and-Click Adventure Games pre-orders are live!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/4/the-art-of-point-and-click-adventure-games-pre-orders-are-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 22:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/4/the-art-of-point-and-click-adventure-games-pre-orders-are-live/</guid>
      <description>There is a slight irony around my love of point &amp;amp; click adventures over the last few years. Back in the 8 and 16 bit days I would often pour my disdain on these games while proclaiming the superiority of the good old text adventure. I was willing to accept the static images that accompanied games like &amp;ldquo;The Guild of Thieves&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;The Boggit&amp;rdquo;, but controlling a pixeled character and clicking on things with a limited set of verbs?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/3/31/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 21:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/3/31/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</guid>
      <description>This month in&amp;hellip; The One for Amiga &amp;lsquo;92 News A new TV show catering for gamers had recently debuted and The One wanted to hear from readers about what they thought of it. Did Gamesmaster provide what gaming fans were looking for?&#xA;Electronic Arts were to publish &amp;ldquo;Castles&amp;rdquo;, a &amp;ldquo;SimCity&amp;rdquo; meets RPG game from Interplay.&#xA;A new book from Sigma sought to help players struggling to get to grips with adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Game: Part 1 - Wha&#39; Happen?</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/3/24/diary-of-a-game-part-1-wha-happen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 01:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/3/24/diary-of-a-game-part-1-wha-happen/</guid>
      <description>Man, what happened to the last couple of months?! In the first part of this series I mentioned that my work tended to be rather full on.. at that point I knew I was going to be spending the end of January traveling on business, but what I didn&amp;rsquo;t know was that that would be immediately followed by another, longer business trip. I had a whole 4 days at home during February, and not a single weekend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;90</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/2/8/this-month-in-cvg-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 07:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/2/8/this-month-in-cvg-90/</guid>
      <description>News Code Masters unveiled their fancy new CD compilations for the Spectrum and C64. The package included a computer interface to connect your regular CD player and the CD-ROM containing 30 Code Masters games. The Spectrum version was able to load games in under a minute, while the C64 utilised the stereo audio signal to encode a timing track enabling even quicker load times. C&amp;amp;VG marvelled at the possibilities: &amp;ldquo;Imagine a game with minutes of digitised speech or amazing digitised graphics!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Game: Part 0 - Genesis</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/22/diary-of-a-game-part-0-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 22:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/22/diary-of-a-game-part-0-genesis/</guid>
      <description>Here is the first screenshot of a new game I&amp;rsquo;m working on - awesome eh? Wait, don&amp;rsquo;t walk away! It&amp;rsquo;ll get better, I promise!&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last 23 years working in the games industry and at various points I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to muster the motivation/energy to create a game in my spare time. Only one of those (a simple iPhone game, no longer available) made it through to the end and even that took way too long.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C64 Reloaded mk2 Board</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/9/c64-reloaded-mk2-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 08:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/9/c64-reloaded-mk2-board/</guid>
      <description>Updated with info about the remote control menu&#xA;I have a reasonable collection of C64s - 3 breadbins and 2 C64Cs - but out of those only two are fully functioning, so I&amp;rsquo;ve become quite aware that these machines are getting flakey in their old age. I&amp;rsquo;ve sunk quite a lot of hours into attempting to diagnose the faults and finding replacement bits online, with mixed success. Given that it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that I was eagerly awaiting the release of the C64 Reloaded mk2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #6 August/September 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 06:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s mag included:&#xA;A rather depressing Editorial which opened with &amp;ldquo;Boom-time for the computer games world is over, at least for the next few years.&amp;rdquo; The Japanese consoles were wiping the floor with computers - the 8bits were barely hanging on, the ST not far behind them. There looked to be some life left in the Amiga, but it was the IBM PC that stood the best chance of lasting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Guild of Thieves Remastered&#34; is out!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/guild-of-thieves-remastered-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 22:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/guild-of-thieves-remastered-is-out/</guid>
      <description>I guess this is a sign of how recent life has been all-consumed by work, but I only just noticed that Strand Games have released the second of their Magnetic Scrolls remasters, &amp;ldquo;The Guild of Thieves&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;There are few games which I remember as fondly as this, not just because it is a brilliant adventure (which it certainly is), but because it was the game - and only game - I ordered alongside my beloved Amiga 500.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #5 June/July 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 22:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/29/confidential-magazine-junejuly-1989/</guid>
      <description>In this issue you can find:&#xA;A bit of a rant by the Ed on the &amp;ldquo;joys&amp;rdquo; of running a software mail order service and dealing with clueless, impatient and down right rude customers calling up. A report from the first European Computer Trade Show, which sounded like a right disappointment: &amp;ldquo;Where were the First Ever Showings? The Exclusive Demos? The Sneako Previews? Well, they certainly weren&amp;rsquo;t present on the day I visited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 07:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/12/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Hot off the presses from Japan was news of the PC Engine Super Grafx which looked to build on the already impressive original. New custom chips meant it could chuck around 128 sprites (up from 64) and the cartridges saw a decent boost in size. Perhaps the most intriguing aspect was the Power Console add on which the console slotted into and featured a full on steering yoke, a gear stick/throttle, LCD clock/timer, LED radar display, numeric keypad and a bunch of buttons and knobs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/11/16/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 07:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/11/16/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News A new computer was about to be unleashed on Europe which boasted specs that certainly beat the 8bits, but also - apparently - rivaled the Amiga and ST. While that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem terribly exciting, it did have one interesting feature: the ability to run most Speccy games. The SAM Coupe was due to launch in the UK on November 20th.&#xA;With Christmas around the corner, Hewson were to release a couple of compilations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectrum Addict: Load &#34;FILM 2&#34; Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/spectrum-addict-load-film-2-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 04:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/spectrum-addict-load-film-2-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>The Kickstarter for a follow up to the &amp;ldquo;Memoirs of a Spectrum Addict&amp;rdquo; documentary, &amp;ldquo;Load &amp;lsquo;FILM 2&amp;rsquo; has entered its final week. The line up of Speccy developers is impressive, including the likes of my old boss Jon Ritman and Bo Jangeborg. As someone who was obsessed by Delta4&amp;rsquo;s adventure games back in the day, I&amp;rsquo;m particularly pleased to see Fergus McNeil in there as well.&#xA;These documentaries are clearly a labour of love for Andy and I strongly believe that we need to be capturing the stories of these pioneers, so I really hope this funds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;91</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-91/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 01:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/29/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-91/</guid>
      <description>News The European Computer Entertainment show was on, then off, then back on.&#xA;Editor Ciaran Brennan pondered the dearth of releases for this time of year. Were publishers simply holding them for Christmas? Judging by the slew of previews and announcements it certainly looked like there was plenty on the way.&#xA;French developer Delphine were touting their new animation system, Cinematique. The first game to utilise it would be &amp;ldquo;Another World&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunter&#39;s Moon Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/28/hunters-moon-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 21:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/28/hunters-moon-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>The legendary C64 software house Thalamus is back! Created in 1986 by mag publisher Newsfield, it quickly grew a reputation for quality titles. The connection with Zzap!64 probably didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt either.&#xA;News broke a couple of months ago that the label was being reborn as Thalamus Digital, and that we could look forward to some of those classic games making a come back - including the possibility of a new installment of Creatures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Hubbard Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/18/project-hubbard-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 07:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/18/project-hubbard-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to overstate the impact Rob Hubbard had on the UK games scene during the 80s. He was a prolific musician who turned out some incredible tunes. Seeing &amp;ldquo;Commando&amp;rdquo; at my mate&amp;rsquo;s place one afternoon after school helped convince me I needed a C64. I remember going back to his house, tape recorder in hand, to record the music to listen to on repeat (especially that lovely game over tune).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/15/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 08:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/10/15/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Konix Here At Last&amp;rdquo; proclaimed the headline leading off this issue. The much hyped Konix Multisystem was going to be available to buy this month at stores across the UK for around 200 quid. Not all of the eagerly anticipated peripherals would be on sale to start with - the hydraulic chair was &amp;ldquo;on the horizon&amp;rdquo; and expected to cost another 200 quid. Of course, sadly, none of this was to be&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thimbleweed Park Day!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/19/happy-thimbleweed-park-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 07:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/19/happy-thimbleweed-park-day/</guid>
      <description>The iPad has become my preferred platform for playing adventure games, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to this one. I backed the Kickstarter almost three years ago and it&amp;rsquo;s been a treat to see it take shape - the dev blog posts and podcasts were worth it alone.&#xA;As luck would have it, my next overseas business trip is coming up in a few days which I hope will provide ample of opportunity to dive into it proper.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #4 April/May 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</guid>
      <description>This issue came hot on the heels of British Telecom&amp;rsquo;s decision to bail out of the games industry. They were looking to sell off the Rainbird, Firebird and Silverbird labels as one lot, while winding Telecomsoft down. The official reason given was that games were no longer in line with the goals of BT, and the asking price was rumoured to be around £5 million. The editorial questioned the motives, highlighting a series of recent misteps resulting in significant financial losses, which included the purchase of Beyond Software (closed down soon after due to poor performance), and the US based Firebird Licensees Inc which lasted less than a year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Official Magnetic Scrolls Solution Books</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/official-magnetic-scrolls-solution-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 06:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/official-magnetic-scrolls-solution-books/</guid>
      <description>While digging through some boxes of old Stuff from the attic I came across a couple of solution books for the adventure games &amp;ldquo;Corruption&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Fish!&amp;rdquo; by Magnetic Scrolls. I got these directly from Magnetic Scrolls, and they&amp;rsquo;re far superior to regular old walkthroughs as they include location maps, hints for specific situations along with the step by step solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/5/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 07:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/5/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Two years after it launched in the US, Atari were bringing the 7800 ProSystem to the UK. On paper the specs weren&amp;rsquo;t up to much when compared to Nintendo and Sega&amp;rsquo;s offerings, but at £69.95 it looked decent value for money. Stateside the 7800 was the number 2 selling console ahead of the Master System.&#xA;Spectravideo&amp;rsquo;s popular range of Quickshot joysticks (the Quickshot II Turbo was my personal fave back in the day) was being joined by their new Wizmaster gamepad.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #2 Dec 1988/Jan 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 08:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/3/confidential-magazine-2-dec-1988jan-1989/</guid>
      <description>Postal strikes had caused delays to the first issue, and - whether it was due to this or some other reason - November came and went without the second issue. Going forward they would be sticking to the every-other-month schedule.&#xA;Contents:&#xA;Interview with Philippe Ulrich, head of the EXXOS group at French software house ERE Informatique which had recently released the rather original and intriguing &amp;ldquo;Captain Blood&amp;rdquo;. A somewhat tongue in cheek guide to playing adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/8/27/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 07:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/8/27/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn bid farewell as he strode off &amp;ldquo;on a secret mission&amp;rdquo;. Ciaran Brennan was to take the reins, with Julian Rignall as his assistant. Phillipa Irving&amp;rsquo;s war game section took a break as she was busy with exams. There was also a small change to the review format, with the &amp;ldquo;Value&amp;rdquo; rating being dropped.&#xA;Arnie&amp;rsquo;s latest film &amp;ldquo;Predator&amp;rdquo; had grossed $12 million at the box office in its first 3 days and Activision had signed the license.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 08:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Atari unveiled their impressive handheld, the Lynx. Julian Rignall got to check it out and was gobsmacked: &amp;ldquo;Erm&amp;hellip; hmmm&amp;hellip; What can I say about the most exciting thing to happen to the games industry since the invention of the home console?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Sinclair (aka Amstrad) were to launch a new bundle. The &amp;ldquo;Action Pack&amp;rdquo; would consist of a Spectrum +2 (£149) or +3 (£199), a Magnum light gun and 6 games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crash Annual 2018 Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/24/crash-annual-2018-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 02:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/24/crash-annual-2018-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>The Kickstarter for the 99th issue of Crash magazine has gone live. Roger Kean is back on editing duties, and Oli Frey will be creating the cover and art - we&amp;rsquo;ll even see the return of the Jetman comic strip. The line up of other contributors is also looking rather impressive.&#xA;Crash holds a special place in my heart - it was my main go to mag back in the day (before, I admit, I jumped ship to the C64&amp;hellip;), and I still have all the well worn issues I used to pore over each month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full Throttle Remastered arrives on iOS</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/20/full-throttle-remastered-arrives-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 09:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/20/full-throttle-remastered-arrives-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>Finally! I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this one for a while: &amp;ldquo;Full Throttle Remastered&amp;rdquo; has been released for iOS. The iPad has become my adventure gaming device of choice (aside from 8bit text adventures, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out a solution for that), so it&amp;rsquo;s great to see another LucasArts classic on the platform.&#xA;Not only that, but to coincide with the release Double Fine have slashed the prices of &amp;ldquo;Grim Fandango Remastered&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Day of the Tentacle Remastered&amp;rdquo; - both highly recommended and absolute bargains at this price.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/16/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 06:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/16/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Software Projects announced that they were reducing their prices to £5.95 in the run up to Christmas. Others were expected to follow suit, though that did seem somewhat unlikely as that’s a steep drop down from £9.95. Gary Penn pondered how lower prices might affect the quality of games - lower budgets for development? less licensed tie-ins? (The latter was considered a good thing)&#xA;Ciaran Brennan was promoted to Assistant Editor, and Gary Liddon was due to make his return next month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: The Bear Essentials (C64) by Pondsoft</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/14/review-the-bear-essentials-c64-by-pondsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 01:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/14/review-the-bear-essentials-c64-by-pondsoft/</guid>
      <description>When I first started to get into the resurgent C64 game scene after discovering the likes of Psytronik and Protovision, there was one game that everyone seemed to be talking about. Graham Axten’s platformer, which starred a rather charming bear, was looking great and was eagerly anticipated.&#xA;The game draws heavily from Manic Miner and Jet Set Willy, with a graphics style reminiscent of Creatures. The influence of Matthew Smith’s classic games is clear right from the start, where instead of housekeeper Maria turning Willy away to go tidy the house after a massive party, it’s Bear’s wife wanting enough apples to get the family through the winter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C64 Reloaded Mk2 Announced!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/14/c64-reloaded-mk2-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/14/c64-reloaded-mk2-announced/</guid>
      <description>Well, hot on the heels of yesterdays Ultimate-64 announcement comes the news that Individual Computers are about to start production of the C64 Reloaded Mk2. This is a rather different approach, and requires the user to install a few chips of their own in order to have a functioning C64. The required chips are:&#xA;CPU 6510 or 8500 Two CIA 6526 or 8521 Video chip 6567, 6569, 8565 or 8562 SID 6581 and/or 8580 The board supports a dual SID configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate-64 Announced!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/13/ultimate-64-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 23:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/13/ultimate-64-announced/</guid>
      <description>I received my 1541 Ultimate-II+ a couple of months ago and love it (which reminds me, I really need to do a write up of it), so the news that Gideon had announced a new product today certainly caught my attention.&#xA;The Ultimate-64 is a an FPGA implementation of the entire C64 board. This means it has all the ports of an original C64, so you can attach tape &amp;amp; disk drives and hook it up to your old Commodore monitors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #1 Sept/Oct 1988</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/8/confidential-magazine-1-septoct-1988/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 06:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/8/confidential-magazine-1-septoct-1988/</guid>
      <description>Back in 1987 I ordered a copy of the classic adventure &amp;ldquo;Guild of Thieves&amp;rdquo; along with my Amiga 500. Included in the game&amp;rsquo;s package was a copy of &amp;ldquo;What Burglar?&amp;rdquo; magazine, and an advert for a mysterious &amp;ldquo;Confidential&amp;rdquo; club. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s how I remember it - looking through the box now I don&amp;rsquo;t see such an advert in there, though there is an offer to write in to Magnetic Scrolls to receive some swag.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/4/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 08:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/4/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News The industry was abuzz with talk of Nintendo’s Game Boy. The handheld had seen a very successful launch in Japan with over 500,000 units being sold (300,000 of which were on the first day), and now the question was when would it reach the UK. Nintendo were unable to give any dates, but confirmed they had plans…&#xA;The FIST telephone game was getting a sequel (I have no idea what this was).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SNES mini announced - includes Star Fox 2!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/27/snes-mini-announced-includes-star-fox-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 19:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/27/snes-mini-announced-includes-star-fox-2/</guid>
      <description>While the announcement of the SNES mini is hardly a surprise, especially given the runaway success of its 8bit sibling, the inclusion of Star Fox 2 certainly is. The sequel to arguably one of the finest games of the 16bit era was cancelled late into its development and never saw the light of day (aside from a leaked prototype ROM).&#xA;I missed out on the NES mini, mainly because I assumed that Nintendo would keep on churning them out for a good while, so I&amp;rsquo;m much more tempted this time around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: &#34;The Camp&#34; (C64) by Protovision</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/22/review-the-camp-c64-by-protovision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 08:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/22/review-the-camp-c64-by-protovision/</guid>
      <description>Way back in the mists of time (well, 1982) my parents took me and my sister out of school for a few months to embark on a trip around the UK, Europe and the US. For the European leg we jaunted about in a campervan, staying at campsites (and occasionally on roadsides) along the way. My memories of that time are sadly vague - my main recollection is the ridiculously rough toilet paper that one had to endure in the bathrooms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 08:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Firebird closed a deal with Activision/Electric Dreams which would see the budget publisher re-releasing a slew of older titles from the US for £1.99 each.&#xA;No changes at Zzap! this month, though Julian Rignall got engaged to Glenys Powell, the “ever-effervescent” Editorial Assistant.&#xA;Zzap! launched in Italy. Note the lack of “64” - Speccy, Atari, MSX and C16 gamers would all be catered for.&#xA;The Sensi Software lads were wrapping up their next game: the awesome &amp;ldquo;Wizball”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 08:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw C&amp;amp;VG getting a revamp based on reader feedback. Coin ops and consoles would get more pages, the adventure section got a make over, there was more space dedicated to previews and overall there would be a lot more colour. The announcement of these changes referenced the fact that some features were dropped, but they didn’t actually specify which. Somewhat worryingly, there were no adventure game reviews - just some tips.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The return of Magnetic Scrolls? (Sort of)</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/18/the-return-of-magnetic-scrolls-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 06:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/18/the-return-of-magnetic-scrolls-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>Well, this is very interesting indeed. Hugh Steers - a founding member of Magnetic Scrolls - has formed Strand Games along with Stefan Meier (from if-legends.org). Their first release is a a remaster of the classic adventure &amp;ldquo;The Pawn&amp;rdquo;, available for Mac, Win and Linux. Not only that, but they have the support of other Magnetic Scrolls alumni, including Anita Sinclair and Ken Gordon.&#xA;I stumbled across their site somewhat randomly - I&amp;rsquo;m a bit surprised it hasn&amp;rsquo;t received more coverage in the retro gaming scene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Arrivals</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/18/new-arrivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 05:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/18/new-arrivals/</guid>
      <description>Since getting back into the C64/Amiga scene, one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve really loved is that there are still people out there making &amp;amp; publishing games for the machines. So I finally got around to picking up a few. From Psytronkik there is:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Kung Fu Maniacs Trilogy&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Gravitrix&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;X-Force&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Space Trip 2086&amp;rdquo;. And one from Pond that I had been eagerly awaiting:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Bear Essentials&amp;rdquo; These should keep me busy for a little while&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rogue Squadron in Retro Gamer</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/18/rogue-squadron-in-retro-gamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 05:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/18/rogue-squadron-in-retro-gamer/</guid>
      <description>Issue 168 of Retro Gamer (May-ish 2017 - my copy didn&amp;rsquo;t arrive until a week or so into June) has a great article on the &amp;ldquo;Rogue Squadron&amp;rdquo; series of games, complete with a few ramblings from myself. The other people interviewed were my old Factor 5 colleagues Julian Eggebrecht, Jamie Uhrmacher and Chris Crawford, plus Ryan Kaufman who was a level designer at Lucasarts.&#xA;I joined Factor 5 soon after &amp;ldquo;Rogue Squadron&amp;rdquo; had been released, and my first game there would be the sadly underrated and somewhat unknown &amp;ldquo;Battle for Naboo&amp;rdquo; - the fact that it was an Episode 1 game right after Star Wars fans worldwide had been punched in the guts by that terrible movie didn&amp;rsquo;t help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/15/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/15/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Thanks to a tweet from Julian Rignall I finally noticed that the ships getting blown up by Zzap!64 on the cover represented Commodore User &amp;amp; C&amp;amp;VG. Cheeky.&#xA;The reason for such a cover? Sales had climbed to 67,728 per month and showed no signs of letting up. The mag would be undergoing a few changes - they looked to be broadening the scope of what they were covering, including “unusual, but relevant” features.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Footage of Jeff Minter&#39;s &#34;Polybius&#34;</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/7/footage-of-jeff-minters-polybius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 07:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/7/footage-of-jeff-minters-polybius/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Minter takes us through the first 7 levels of his upcoming PS4/PSVR shoot&amp;rsquo;em up, &amp;ldquo;Polyius&amp;rdquo;, and it looks as crazy full on as you might expect. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that he says people have reported they find it quite meditative as it&amp;rsquo;s all about the flow&amp;hellip; but even as a spectactor I found it tricky to follow. Will be interesting to see how much difference playing it in VR makes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amiga 3000&#43; Board on eBay</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/7/amiga-3000-board-on-ebay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 04:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/7/amiga-3000-board-on-ebay/</guid>
      <description>Well, this is rather fascinating: an Amiga 3000+ prototype board was sold on eBay by none other than Dave Haynie. It fetched a decent $2,155 USD and included a couple of his notebooks from the period when he was working on it.&#xA;As if the fact that such a board still exists isn&amp;rsquo;t interesting enough, he penned a long description of the board and what was going on at Commodore at the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/24/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/24/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>[Oh dear, I got confused and thought this was the April issue.. turns out my April issue appears to be missing - no doubt the fault of one of my High School friends back in the day]&#xA;News Rignall and Glancey took on Domark’s Mark Strachan and Andy Blazdell in three rounds of Tengen’s &amp;ldquo;Vindicators&amp;rdquo; arcade machine. The C&amp;amp;VG lads won two out of three and claimed the Tengen Trophy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 07:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News A couple of new arrivals at Zzap! this month, with Steve Jarratt swapping industrial chemistry for games journalism and Philipa Irving who, er, swapped Crash for its Newsfield sibling.&#xA;Ariolasoft’s Starlight label had three games on the way. &amp;ldquo;Dogfight 2187&amp;rdquo; promised 3D wireframe shoot ‘em up action with a vertically split screen giving two views of the action. The other two games were &amp;ldquo;Deathscape&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Greyfell”. Meanwhile Tony Crowther had teamed up with Keith Blake and Ross Goodley to develop ”Challenge of the Gobots” based on the popular kids cartoon, which would be published by Ariolasoft.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Kickstarters</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 23:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/25/recent-kickstarters/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a good time to be a retro gaming fan recently with several promising Kickstarters. Of course I dawdled too long on writing about them, so some have already finished, but they&amp;rsquo;re still worth keeping an eye on.&#xA;Reformation 2 from Matt Gray The first Reformation took a little longer to ship than originally expected, but it was well worth the wait. 5 CDs of excellent remakes of some of the best tunes to grace the C64 (and therefore, games in general).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZX Spectrum Next Kickstarter Launched!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/23/zx-spectrum-next-kickstarter-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 04:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/23/zx-spectrum-next-kickstarter-launched/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s even designed by the original&amp;rsquo;s designer, Rick Dickinson!&#xA;After months of anticipation, the ZX Spectrum Next Kickstarter campaign has been launched. I was fortunate to see a prototype in action at the Revival Solstice event last July when Henrique gave a talk on the project and was very impressed. After some high profile crowdfunded retro gaming failures over the last couple of years it&amp;rsquo;s easy to be sceptical, but these guys are not only doing everything right, but all indications are that their hearts are in the right place too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 07:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn wrote a long editorial on a matter that had been on a lot of people’s minds: had quality and innovation taken a dive as software houses relied more and more on coin-op, TV and film licenses? The market seemed to be full of these unimaginative and often shoddy tie ins which, aside from the attached IP, only had good presentation going for them. Developers were feeling the pinch as well: publishers would “guarantee 100,000” copies sold, giving them an excuse to lower royalties.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/20/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 08:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/20/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Michael Jackson’s “Moonwalker” movie had only just come out and US Gold had already snaffled the game license.&#xA;Titus announced their futuristic deadly sport game &amp;ldquo;Titan”.&#xA;The Vocalizer 1000 was a music gadget where the user would hum/whistle/sing a tune at it and it would detect the varying pitches and allow playback of the tune using a selection of 28 instruments.&#xA;Gary Liddon was teaming up with renowned game artist Paul Docherty to develop &amp;ldquo;Tyger Tyger&amp;rdquo; for Mastertronic’s Ricochet label.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 06:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn responded to grumblings from readers about the Christmas issue. The main complaints were around the lack of reviews and the price. The former issue was hardly the magazine’s fault as publisher’s were taking any morsel of time they could get in order to get games on the shelves for the Christmas shoppers.&#xA;Electric Dreams/Activision had a whopping dozen licensed arcade conversions heading to the C64. They included: &amp;ldquo;Tempest” (unreleased?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/23/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 08:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/23/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Death Stalks the Night&amp;rdquo; was an upcoming arcade adventure from Ubi Soft where the player assumed the role as Count Dracula to take on “the usual Van Helsings”.&#xA;New software house EAS announced a space trading game called &amp;ldquo;STAG&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST.&#xA;Mr Chip’s &amp;ldquo;Wrangler&amp;rdquo;would see the player take control over Clint Eastwood (yes, apparently) and his ‘droid in what looked like a puzzle game.&#xA;Budget label Alternative were moving into the 16bits with Don Priestly’s &amp;ldquo;Mad Flunky”, a follow-up to his Spectrum game &amp;ldquo;Flunky”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/25/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 08:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/25/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Gary Penn lamented the fact that for the first time there had not been a single Sizzler or Gold Medal awarded in an issue. Well, that’s not entirely true as &amp;ldquo;The Bard’s Tale&amp;rdquo; picked up a very respectable Sizzler, though apparently it didn’t count as it was “a role playing game”. It seemed that software houses were spending as much time as possible before Christmas to polish up their hopeful hits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/11/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 08:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/11/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News C&amp;amp;VG were giving away a Body Rap toy which would be strapped to your body and emit audio (bass, drum, snare, cymbal etc) when hit. They described it as a “neat little gizmo” but I can’t imagine it being anything other than dreadful.&#xA;The Amiga, ST and Amstrad versions of Titus’ car racing game &amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars II&amp;rdquo; were on the shelves, with the C64 due this month.&#xA;German software house Rainbow Arts were to release &amp;ldquo;Spherical”, a Gauntlet-style game, and &amp;ldquo;The Game&amp;rdquo; which promised to be a “space battle spectacular.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December Games Revisited</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/31/december-games-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 04:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/31/december-games-revisited/</guid>
      <description>One of these days I’ll get my act together and not wait until the dying hours of the month (and even year in this case) to write these things… With that said, I did manage to have a decent play on a bunch of the biggest December games from 1986 and 1988.&#xA;”The Sentinel”, Geoff Crammond/Firebird, 1986&#xA;Reviewed Zzap!64 December 1986.&#xA;I recall playing this quite a bit on the C64.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 04:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News More changes were afoot, with Strategy Front writer Sean Masterson moving on and the start of a make over that would take effect during the next few months.&#xA;Last month Zzap! teased readers by asking them to check out a screenshot of the hotly anticipated arcade conversion of &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; and then failed to print it. To make up for the error they provided not one but four shots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/15/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 07:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/12/15/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News There were big changes at the mag, with Tony Takoushi &amp;ldquo;getting the boot&amp;rdquo; and replaced by Julian Rignall. This issue hit 114 pages.&#xA;Mandarin Software were developing &amp;ldquo;Grand Prix Circuit&amp;rdquo;, an F1 racing sim to be published by Accolade.&#xA;Elite&amp;rsquo;s lineup for Christmas included &amp;ldquo;Space Harrier 2&amp;rdquo; for the 16bits (seems that Grandslam actually had the rights for that, weird) , &amp;ldquo;Mike Read’s Pop Quiz&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Storm Warrior&amp;rdquo;. Their arcade truck racer &amp;ldquo;Supertrux&amp;rdquo; was narrowly going to miss the holiday season and was due early January.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November Games Revisited</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/30/november-games-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 07:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/30/november-games-revisited/</guid>
      <description>I had hoped to have a number of opportunities to spend some quality time playing these games (and more) this month, but one of the downsides of travelling so much for business is that such occasions are rare. Very rare in the case of this month: I managed a pathetic few hours last Sunday.&#xA;At any rate&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief look back at a few games that hit the shelves in November many years ago to rave reviews.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 08:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Editor Gary Penn trumpeted the success of Zzap!, saying that it had become the &amp;ldquo;biggest selling Commodore magazine in the civilised World.&amp;rdquo; The healthy sales meant more advertisers, which meant more content - this month the mag hit 148 pages.&#xA;A Commodore show took place in Manchester. Commodore did have a stand (which apparently bore a resemblance to Parisian public toilets), where they were showing off was the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 08:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/11/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News It was Superman vs Batman as to who would have the better game. Tynesoft delivering the former, while Ocean took on the latter. Early indications were that Batman had the edge.&#xA;Loricel&amp;rsquo;s next attempt to crack the UK would come in the form of Porsche racing game &amp;ldquo;944 Turbo Cup&amp;rdquo;. Driver Rene Metge (&amp;ldquo;who?&amp;rdquo; asked C&amp;amp;VG) provided the endorsement and the software house hoped to include a model car in the box, but apparently British retailers weren&amp;rsquo;t so keen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Parallax&#34; Re-visited</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/parallax-re-visited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 07:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/parallax-re-visited/</guid>
      <description>Parallax Sensible Software/Ocean, 1986 This month in 1986 saw Sensible&amp;rsquo;s first big title reviewed in Zzap!64, scoring a very respectable 93% overall and receiving a Sizzler.&#xA;Over the past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to remember where I first saw &amp;ldquo;Parallax&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; I want to say it was at my friend Neil&amp;rsquo;s house, but did he even have a C64?? I know he had a Spectrum and later an Amiga&amp;hellip; Maybe it was someone else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 04:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/24/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News An article appeared in the Canberra Times in which a Mr Paul Gathercoal blathered on about the evils of games. Mr Gathercoal firmly believed games were corrupting the minds of children, driving them to lives of robberies, killing and masturbation. He claimed that playing &amp;ldquo;Franke Goes To Hollywood&amp;rdquo; would lead to &amp;ldquo;pill-popping&amp;rdquo;. What utter nonsense.&#xA;Gary Liddon had buggered off to Newsfield&amp;rsquo;s new software house, Thalamus, and a call went out to find someone to replace him at Zzap!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 07:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News Grand Slam were bringing the &amp;ldquo;Pacmania&amp;rdquo; coin-op to home computers (the Amiga, ST and Spectrum versions would be first, with C64 and Amstrad to follow next month). The software house was also working on a computer game based on board game &amp;ldquo;sensation&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Espionage&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Software Horizons was new on the scene and would be publishing three 16bit games within the next month or so: &amp;ldquo;Veteran&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Luxor&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mafdet&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Chris Crawford was updating his well received &amp;ldquo;Balance of Power&amp;rdquo; with some &amp;ldquo;new trouble zones of strategic importance&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 09:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News More staffing changes at the magazine this month. Roger Kean was moving over to a new Newsfield mag called L.M., with Gary Penn stepping in to the Editor role. There were three new faces with Richard &amp;ldquo;Dick&amp;rdquo; Eddy, Jonathan Rignall (Julian&amp;rsquo;s younger brother) and Massimo Valducci starting.&#xA;Beyond announced the upcoming release of not one but two Denton Design games: &amp;ldquo;Dante’s Inferno&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Infodroid&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Meanwhile, Beyond had managed to secure the first ever Star Trek license.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 07:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/9/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News For the first time, major games were being released on the 16bits before the 8bits. C&amp;amp;VG reassured its readers that almost all the games would make their way to the C64/Spectrum/Amstrad, and that the magazine would continue to cover those machines.&#xA;The Bitmap Brothers were following up their well received 16bit shoot&amp;rsquo;em up &amp;ldquo;Xenon&amp;rdquo; with a new futuristic sports game, &amp;ldquo;Speedball&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Mirrorsoft had created a new label, Imageworks, which would be their flagship for most of its new games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/8/20/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 06:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/8/20/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Liddon was leaving Zzap! to join Newsfield&amp;rsquo;s new software house, Thalamus, as Technical Executive. The company was headed by ex-Activision Press Officer Andrew Wright. The first game was due to be released in September on the C64 and Spectrum, with an Amstrad version following.&#xA;Gremlin were readying four new titles in time for Christmas: &amp;ldquo;Pentacle&amp;rdquo; (unreleased?), &amp;ldquo;Future Knight&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Bounder II&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Trailblazer&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Arkana&amp;rsquo;s BBC game &amp;ldquo;Powerplay&amp;rdquo; was heading to the C64.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/8/18/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 09:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/8/18/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw ex-Zzap!64 editor Julian Rignall and ex-Crash editor Steve Jarret join the C&amp;amp;VG writing staff.&#xA;With the Seoul olympic games about to start, Ocean were to release &amp;ldquo;Daley Thompson&amp;rsquo;s Olympic Challenge&amp;rdquo;. Official olympic sponsor Adidas were also sponsoring the game.&#xA;The first screenshot of Realtime Games&amp;rsquo; impressive 16bit &amp;ldquo;Carrier Command&amp;rdquo; Spectrum port appeared. The game was also to appear on the Amstrad and C64.&#xA;French software house Lankhor were working on a car racing game called &amp;ldquo;Vroom&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/7/14/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/7/14/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News The Commodore Show in London was the biggest dedicated C64 event of the year. Zzap!&amp;rsquo;s own booth proved very popular - especially when games programmers dropped by to show off their latest wares (often yet to be signed to a publisher). So why weren&amp;rsquo;t the crowds impressed with the show? It seemed software houses were very thin on the ground&amp;hellip;&#xA;Tony Takoushi was at the show touting a new gizmo called &amp;ldquo;Speedos&amp;rdquo; which was a mod for 1541 floppy drives enabling much faster load times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/7/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/7/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The 1988 Euros were about to start and Grandslam were putting the finishing touches on &amp;ldquo;Peter Beardsley’s International Football&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Titus was following up their &amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;Fire and Forget&amp;rdquo;, a vehicular combat game featuring cars decked out with an array of weapons.&#xA;Crocodile Dundee was heading back to the cinemas, but this time his antics would take place in New York.&#xA;German developer house Logotron was to release a heavily Defender inspired shooter, &amp;ldquo;Stay Ray&amp;rdquo;, for the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 08:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Antony Jacobson wrote a withering attack on Zzap! and Crash in Computer Trade Weekly. It really was oddly vitriolic and included such gems as: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; a certain kind of magazine should only be handled with rubber gloves and antiseptic fire tongs. No-one forces them to publish contagious rubbish but magazines that do so are not simply to be described as boring, but debasing the values of their readership&amp;hellip; and polluting the social and commercial environment in which we live and work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/21/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 08:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/6/21/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The issue came with a &amp;ldquo;Barbarian II&amp;rdquo; poster.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Pandora&amp;rdquo; was a new sci-fi game from Firebird where character interaction was as important as blasting.&#xA;London&amp;rsquo;s The Museum of Mankind opened a new exhibit that made use of video discs and computers to create a game where visitors would learn what life in the Arctic was like.&#xA;The first game to hit the shelves from new publisher Electra was to be &amp;ldquo;Better Dead than Alien&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/31/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 08:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/31/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News A rather triumphant Zzap! boasted about the latest ABC figures which showed it was the &amp;ldquo;leading magazine in the field&amp;rdquo;. Sister publication Crash did even better, not only beating rival Sinclair User but also C&amp;amp;VG, which meant it was the best selling computer title of any kind in the UK.&#xA;In the same editorial, Roger Kean lamented the recent trend of game releases being pushed back. The common excuse for delays seemed to be &amp;ldquo;programming complexity&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 08:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/5/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News Stephen Crow&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Starquake&amp;rdquo; was heading to the ST and Amstrad PC thanks to Mandarin Software.&#xA;Hewson were to re-release several classic titles by Gargoyle Games. &amp;ldquo;Dun Darach&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Marsport&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Tir Na Nog&amp;rdquo; would available for a mere £1.99.&#xA;C&amp;amp;VG apologised for incorrectly stating the price of &amp;ldquo;IO&amp;rdquo; for the C64 last month.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Stir Crazy&amp;rdquo; from Infogrames starred a &amp;ldquo;crazy criminal character&amp;rdquo; attempting to escape prison.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Batman: The Killing Joke&amp;rdquo; by Alan Moore and Brian Bolland was proving quite a hit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 01:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Roger Kean pondered whether the games industry &amp;ldquo;coming of age&amp;rdquo; after 5-ish years with the conglomeration of software houses and the emergence of a small number of dominating companies was a good thing. On the one hand it did mean developers were able to focus more on creating games rather than managing the marketing and distribution, but on the other the desire to get as many games on the shelves as possible was putting a real strain on quality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 23:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News May 28th would see Video Charity Day take place as part of the &amp;ldquo;massive&amp;rdquo; &amp;lsquo;88 Telethon charity drive. Video rental customers would be &amp;ldquo;encouraged&amp;rdquo; to donate while in video stores and there would be competitions and raffles.&#xA;C&amp;amp;VG found the fact that the player character in Martech&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Vixen&amp;rdquo; was female &amp;ldquo;doubly refreshing&amp;rdquo;. The double part may have been a reference to the game&amp;rsquo;s cover/advertisements which featured a photo of a Page 3 girl Corinne Russell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 06:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Commodore announced they were closing their Corby factory and ceasing the manufacture of the 64 in Britain. Was this a sign of bigger troubles? The price of the C64 remained higher than that of competitors, and rather than address this, Commodore had introduced the C16 - but what did this actually solve?&#xA;English Software were finally about to release &amp;ldquo;Elektra Glide&amp;rdquo; on the C64 - some months after the original Atari version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 06:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The big buzz this month was the arrival of &amp;ldquo;Xenon&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST which heralded the first true coin-op quality game on home computers.&#xA;Electronic Arts were working on a graphic adventure for the Amiga called &amp;ldquo;Return to Atlantis&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Infocom were trying something a bit different with their Infocomix line of interactive comics. Rather than a typical adventure game, each issue would allow the reader to choose their path through the storyline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/29/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News This month&amp;rsquo;s editorial warned readers to expect some divisive reviews. Not divisive in that reviewers were unable to agree, but in the sense that they had some truly great games, some utterly awful, and few in between. So some &amp;ldquo;savage criticism&amp;rdquo; was in store.&#xA;One amusing aspect of the editorial is that Roger Kean seemed quite bothered by the fact that a reader had written in to complain about Kean&amp;rsquo;s assertion that the C64&amp;rsquo;s xmas release schedule was &amp;ldquo;disappointing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 23:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/2/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw Eugene Lacey take over as editor. Lacey came from editing Commodore User, and had been a C&amp;amp;VG staff writer sometime earlier.&#xA;Go!&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bedlam&amp;rdquo; promised arcade action featuring up to 18 aliens at any one time.&#xA;Sega&amp;rsquo;s Master System recently launched in the UK and now a slew of titles were heading its way. These included: &amp;ldquo;Kung-Kid&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Fantasy Zone II&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;After Burner&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Global Defense&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Zaxxon 3D&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alien Syndrome&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rescue &amp;amp; Mission&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Zillion II: The Tri Formation&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alex Kidd: The Lost Stars&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Boys Monster Land&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Cube Zone&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Maze Hunter 3D&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/1/10/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 05:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/1/10/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This issue came with an audio cassette featuring music from 720º and Out Run.&#xA;Electric Dreams&amp;rsquo; Spectrum port of &amp;ldquo;Super Hang-On&amp;rdquo; narrowly missed the review window for the month, but a tasty screenshot of it was included instead. C&amp;amp;VG assured readers it was &amp;ldquo;simply brilliant&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;The Edge was bringing comic cat &amp;ldquo;Garfield&amp;rdquo; to home computers.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars&amp;rdquo; was a rather promising looking 16bit racing game from Titus.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Robocop&amp;rdquo; had taken US movie goers by storm and was due to hit UK screens early in the New Year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/12/29/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 05:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/12/29/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Rainbird&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Universal Military Simulator&amp;rdquo; for the ST promised wargaming fans the ability to re-enact a vast array of different battles, including ones between armies from different time periods.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Stratton&amp;rdquo; from CRL would see the player attempt to shutdown the automated defence units of a space station which had suffered a terrorist attack and had turned on its inhabitants. (unable to find evidence of this being released)&#xA;Bike racing game &amp;ldquo;500 Grand Prix&amp;rdquo;, published by French house Loricels, was heading to the ST, IBM and C64.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/11/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 07:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/11/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Microprose&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;F-15 Strike Eagle&amp;rdquo; was about to land on the ST. The ST would also get a port of Mirrorsoft&amp;rsquo;s flightsim featuring a somewhat older aircraft, &amp;ldquo;Spitfire 40&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Viz were working on &amp;ldquo;Werewolves of London&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;For the first time since being bought out by Mastertronic, Melbourne House announced its upcoming titles: &amp;ldquo;Roadwars&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rockford&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pulse Warrior&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Street Hassle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Metropolis&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kelly X&amp;rdquo; (I was unable to find any sign that the latter two were released, at least not under those names).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/10/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 22:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/10/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Jim Synoski and Arnold Hendrick, designers of Microprose&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Project: Stealth Fighter&amp;rdquo;, were promoting the game ahead of its launch. While they admitted nothing official was known about the fighter, they felt that they had &amp;ldquo;a fair idea of what the capabilities of the plane must be&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Incentive&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo; was shaping up well on the Speccy.&#xA;Electric Dreams had the rights to &amp;ldquo;Knightmare&amp;rdquo; - the game of the TV series.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/9/13/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 06:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/9/13/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Digital Integration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bobsleigh&amp;rdquo; was a departure from their usual flight sims and would centre around the winter event.&#xA;Incentive teased their impressive new Freescape engine with a couple of screenshots of the upcoming &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;English Software were working on a Rambo-esque game: &amp;ldquo;Captain Courageous&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Atari dropped the price of the 520STFM to £299.99. They were also planning to re-launch the 130XE and position it as &amp;ldquo;the ultimate teaching computer&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/8/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 05:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/8/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Perhaps the biggest news for Zzap! readers this month was that Julian Rignall had left Newsfield to take up freelancing (including for rival publisher EMAP). Gordon Houghton took over as editor, and there were quite a few changes (mainly cosmetic, but also an expanded news section for a start).&#xA;Mastertronic had a bunch of upcoming releases planned: &amp;ldquo;Rogue&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;World Darts&amp;rdquo; (may have become &amp;ldquo;180&amp;rdquo;), &amp;ldquo;Night Racer&amp;rdquo; and a re-release of Activision&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/8/25/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 08:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/8/25/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Catch 23&amp;rdquo; was a new 3D vector arcade adventure from Martech.&#xA;Epyx were continuing their &amp;ldquo;Games&amp;rdquo; series, this time focussing on events such as BMXing, skateboarding, surfing and flying disks (frisbees) in &amp;ldquo;California Games&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Microprose were to release a new flight sim, &amp;ldquo;Project: Stealth Fighter&amp;rdquo; based on the top secret American stealth plane, and a more arcade-y combat game, &amp;ldquo;Airborne Ranger&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Activision &amp;amp; System 3 got the game rights for Arnie&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Predator&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/7/27/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 07:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/7/27/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Mastertronic was to release a followup to &amp;ldquo;Kane&amp;rdquo;, unsurprisingly called &amp;ldquo;Kane II&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Up until this point Microprose&amp;rsquo;s games had been distributed in the UK by US Gold, but now they were going to handle it all themselves. This would allow them to use much fancier packaging, for starters.&#xA;Tynesoft and Virgin were both readying new compilations.&#xA;Elite started a new budget label, Encore, which would see their back catalogue classics re-released.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/7/19/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 06:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/7/19/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Dungeons, Amethysts, Alchemists &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Everythin&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; from Atlantis Software promised &amp;ldquo;the occasional rude word and sexual innuendo, novice nuns, entangled lovers and busty barmaids&amp;rdquo;. The cover of the game came with a &amp;ldquo;Not suitable for persons under the age of 16&amp;rdquo; label.&#xA;Paul Hardcastle had a big hit with his Vietnam war song &amp;ldquo;19&amp;rdquo; and Cascade were turning it into a game. Rather interestingly, the player would be faced with a choice at the start: fight the war or the draft.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 07:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News The &amp;ldquo;silly season&amp;rdquo; was upon us with new releases rather sparse as programmers/software houses focussed their sights on Christmas.&#xA;Kevin Toms was putting the finishing touches on the long awaited &amp;ldquo;Football Manager II&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Domark were producing &amp;ldquo;Live and Let Die&amp;rdquo;, a game based on Roger Moore&amp;rsquo;s first Bond film.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Barbarian II&amp;rdquo; was due for release in August and promised a &amp;ldquo;multiload extravaganza&amp;rdquo; with a large, mappable area.&#xA;In last month&amp;rsquo;s review of &amp;ldquo;Stealth Mission&amp;rdquo;, Zzap!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 07:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News US Gold had signed a deal to sponsor race driver David Hall&amp;rsquo;s car for the Formula Forward season.&#xA;Meanwhile, US Gold released &amp;ldquo;Deeper Dungeons&amp;rdquo; for those &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo; fans wanting more.&#xA;The British Open AD&amp;amp;D Championships were held at the Reading University Students Union building. Up to 600 people were expected.&#xA;Laser tag guns were the toy of the moment. The two main contenders were &amp;ldquo;Laser Combat&amp;rdquo; from Action GT, and &amp;ldquo;Laser Tag&amp;rdquo; from Mattel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This (er, last) month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/1/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 07:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/1/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>I managed to miss May by one day - mea culpa.&#xA;News Julian Rignall defended the status of the C64 in light of the recently arrived 16bit machines, citing the strength of recent release compared to rather disappointing 16bit titles: &amp;ldquo;To me, the Commodore 64 is leading the way when it comes to new ideas - Driller, the up-and-coming Echelon, Apollo 18, Nebulus, Soko Ban and Deflektor are recent examples that inject new life and innovation into the computer game format.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/5/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 04:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/5/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Simon Price, who had previously worked on &amp;ldquo;Redhawk&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kwah!&amp;rdquo;, was developing &amp;ldquo;Wiz&amp;rdquo; for Melbourne House.&#xA;Danish software house Kele Line had two new C64 releases this month, &amp;ldquo;Thunder Force&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Unitrax&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;The 4th Dimension&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Vikings&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Pirates of the Ocean&amp;rdquo; were to follow. Seems that only &amp;ldquo;Thunder Force&amp;rdquo; (published by Hewson) and &amp;ldquo;Vikings&amp;rdquo; made it out.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Mystery of Arkham Manor&amp;rdquo; would see the player take on the role of a journo investigating a - as the title suggests - mysterious murder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/15/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 06:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/15/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Gordon Leslie Houghton was the newest person to join the Zzap!64 writing team.&#xA;Hard to know whether Zzap! fell for an April fools, or were behind it themselves, but they carried a news story about a Norwegian firm creating a C64 add-on that would turn the humble 64 into an Amiga. The &amp;ldquo;Amulator&amp;rdquo; was being made by Blue Tec and would cost around £280.&#xA;Features Martin Walker had just finished off &amp;ldquo;Hunter&amp;rsquo;s Moon&amp;rdquo; and had embarked on a new dev diary for his next (yet to be decided) game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/12/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 05:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/12/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News This month C&amp;amp;VG became the biggest selling games mag in the UK, shifting 106,571 copies monthly.&#xA;The Edge picked up the license for &amp;ldquo;Garfield&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Superior Software were launching a big spring recruitment drive, and had written a handbook for budding games programmers titled &amp;ldquo;Success in Software&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Beano-esque comic &amp;ldquo;Oink!&amp;rdquo; was to be turned into a game by CRL.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Dan Dare&amp;rdquo; creator, Andy Wilson, was finishing up &amp;ldquo;Laurel and Hardy&amp;rdquo; which featured a &amp;ldquo;new programming technique called Cinevision&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 06:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News A fresh faced 18yr old Paul Glancey joined the Zzap!64 team.&#xA;Features Julian Rignall and Steve Jarratt popped along to the 44th Amusement Trade Exhibition International to check out the latest arcade machines.&#xA;Sci-fi films and TV had taken a stab at many predictions of the future of computers over the previous 35 years, and Zzap!64 cast a critical eye over them.&#xA;Zzap!64 visited the offices of Digital Pictures to drool over their high power CG machines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 05:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Indoor Sports&amp;rdquo; by Mindscape was to feature a set of &amp;ldquo;unusual&amp;rdquo; sports, such as air hockey.&#xA;Creative Sparks announced not one but four new budget titles: &amp;ldquo;Little Alien&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Smudge and the Moonees&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Shuffle&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Cyber I&amp;rdquo;. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like any of these were released.&#xA;Melbourne House&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Murder at Arkham Hall&amp;rdquo; was to be a detective style adventure with the player taking on the role of a reporter investigating a murder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms To Billions: The Amiga Years</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 03:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/from-bedrooms-to-billions-the-amiga-years/</guid>
      <description>The good folk behind the absolutely brilliant &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms to Billions&amp;rdquo; documentary have announced their new project: a 90 minute film on the Amiga. This time rather than focussing on the British contribution to the industry, they&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking to prominent Amiga developers, musicians, demo sceners and so on from around the world.&#xA;Given my love for the Amiga - a machine that was so beautifully and elegantly architected and years ahead of its time - I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely delighted they&amp;rsquo;ve chosen it as the subject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 02:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/22/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News This issue would see the introduction of a new (potentially controversial) regular section: a roundup of Amiga games.&#xA;GO!, a sublabel of US Gold, won the rights to release conversions of 10 of Capcom&amp;rsquo;s upcoming arcade machines.&#xA;Mastertronic signed a deal with Japanese arcade company Technos for the rights to all current and future releases. First up would be &amp;ldquo;Double Dragon&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Features Julian Rignall and Steve Jarratt visited Britsh Airways&amp;rsquo; Flight Crew Training Centre to check out the state of the art in flight simulators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/14/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 21:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/14/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News The Robot Society of America was offering newly signed up members the chance to win an &amp;ldquo;experimental sound-activated robot&amp;rdquo; kit. Membership was $50 per year.&#xA;Bug Byte was to release old Virgin games under its budget label. &amp;ldquo;Strangeloop&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Falcon Patrol II&amp;rdquo; were among the first batch.&#xA;Also getting in on the budget action was newcomer Alternative Software with releases such as &amp;ldquo;Howzat&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Henry&amp;rsquo;s Hoard&amp;rdquo;. Not exactly the most thrilling line up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Rather oddly there was no news section, despite it being a bumper issue. Perhaps this was a change of direction now that Julian Rignall was editor?&#xA;Features Jon Hare provided a run down of how to use SEUCK.&#xA;A bunch of joysticks were reviewed. The Competition Pro 5000 came out on top.&#xA;The Harlequin looked back on what was a bit of a lacklustre year for adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 20:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Ocean was to bring &amp;ldquo;Donkey Kong&amp;rdquo; to the C64, Spectrum and Amstrad.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Blood n&amp;rsquo; Guts&amp;rdquo; was heading to the C64 and was described by publisher American Action as &amp;ldquo;an ancient barbarian decathlon with all the violence and brutality you&amp;rsquo;ve ever dreamed about in a computer game&amp;rdquo;. Oo-kay.&#xA;Atari&amp;rsquo;s 7800 was about to hit the shelves retailing for around £70, with games costing £10-15.&#xA;Bo Jangeborg was busy finishing &amp;ldquo;Fairlight II&amp;rdquo;, which was to be double the size and feature a greater variety of graphics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 03:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Ciaran Brennan had only just taken over the helm at ZZap! but he was already moving onto pastures new. This ushered in Julian Rignall as editor.&#xA;US Gold acquired the rights to the &amp;ldquo;Rolling Thunder&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Roadblasters&amp;rdquo; coin ops. Meanwhile, the publisher dropped the price of all of their C64 disk games from £14.99 to £11.99 (thanks to economies of scale).&#xA;Telecomsoft scored a bit of a coup, signing Graftgold away from Hewson.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 02:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Probe Software was porting two arcade games, &amp;ldquo;Quartet&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Enduro Racer&amp;rdquo; to home computers for Activision.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Tracker&amp;rdquo; from Rainbird promised tactical battles against an &amp;ldquo;artificially intelligent enemy&amp;rdquo; which would involve strategy and fast 3D arcade sections.&#xA;Beyond continued to promote their much hyped &amp;ldquo;Star Trek&amp;rdquo; game, which would never see a release. They also revealed &amp;ldquo;Infodroid&amp;rdquo; - a new game from Denton Designs.&#xA;After Ocean&amp;rsquo;s exceptionally disappointing &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo; a few months earlier, Activision owned the US rights to the cartoon and David Crane had been working on an entirely different &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo; game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News This issue came complete with a pair of red/blue 3D glasses and to use when reading the &amp;ldquo;3D Tips Supplement&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Incentive Software&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Graphic Adventure Creator Plus&amp;rdquo; was due in the coming month. This new version would allow games to use a disc-access system - similar to Infocom&amp;rsquo;s games - which would allow much bigger adventures. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure if this was actually released.&#xA;Level 9 unveiled their latest adventure, &amp;ldquo;Gnome Ranger&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 23:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw C&amp;amp;VG turn 5 years old and to celebrate they had a bunch of special features, including a Spectrum listing by Steve Turner&amp;rsquo;s dad.&#xA;Microsphere revealed their next game would be &amp;ldquo;Contact Sam Cruise&amp;rdquo;, which was inspired by classic private eye movies. There was also a hint that there might be something for fans of &amp;ldquo;Skool Daze&amp;rdquo; at Christmas.&#xA;Arioalasoft got the licenses for two Hanna-Barbera cartoons: &amp;ldquo;The Centurions&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Challenge of the Gobots&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Commodore Amiga: a visual Commpendium&#34; Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 01:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/commodore-amiga-a-visual-commpendium-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Following on from his beautiful C64 book, Sam Dyer is running a Kickstarter campaign to give the same loving treatment to the Amiga. He has an impressive list of prominent Amiga folk lined up as contributors and - quite rightly - plans to include a section on the demo scene, which played a huge role in making the machine so amazing. The campaign smashed through the initial goal within a short time but there are still some rather tasty looking stretch goals that would be great to hit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/this-month-in-zzap-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 00:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/this-month-in-zzap-87/</guid>
      <description>News The Audit Bureau of Circulations report showed that Zzap!&amp;rsquo;s readership had reached an impressive 77,483 in the first 6 months of the year.&#xA;Delta4 re-surfaced as Abstract Concepts and Fergus McNeil was busy working on a new fancy adventure system.&#xA;The next game from Stavros Fasoulas under the Thalamus label would be &amp;ldquo;Quedex&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Features Part one of a series on the history of the shoot&amp;rsquo;em up.&#xA;Andrew Braybrook&amp;rsquo;s development diary of &amp;ldquo;Morpheus&amp;rdquo; drew to an end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms To Billions</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 04:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</guid>
      <description>A little over 2 years ago I stumbled across an Indiegogo campaign that was raising funds for a documentary on the birth of the UK games industry. They already had an impressive list of interviewees lined up and the clips they&amp;rsquo;d released were very promising. It was clear that the producers had a deep respect for the subject and the people they were recording, and that they weren&amp;rsquo;t setting out to create some cheesey fluff piece (unlike certain other productions).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 03:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Ariolasoft spun out two new software houses, 39 Steps to focus on adventure games and Reaktor arcade/action games. First up from 39 Steps would be &amp;ldquo;They Stole a Million&amp;rdquo; while Reaktor&amp;rsquo;s would be &amp;ldquo;Deactivators&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Martial arts games were proving popular and Martech threw their hat in the ring with &amp;ldquo;Uchi-Mata&amp;rdquo;, a &amp;ldquo;more subtle&amp;rdquo; simulation based on Judo.&#xA;Beyond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Star Trek&amp;rdquo; was to land in time for Christmas and would feature more than 1000 stars and 256 subplots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 02:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Sensible Software signed to Outlaw, Palace Software&amp;rsquo;s new label. The first game the sensi chaps would deliver was &amp;ldquo;Shoot&amp;rsquo;em Up Construction Kit&amp;rdquo; (or SEUCK as it came to be known as).&#xA;A game based on Jeffrey Archer&amp;rsquo;s first novel, &amp;ldquo;Not a Penny More, Not a Penny Less&amp;rdquo; was in the works. Meanwhile, Archer had been busy in a highly publicised court case and had just been acquitted.&#xA;There was a &amp;ldquo;Ten Things You Never Knew About Mark Cale&amp;rdquo; section (head of System 3).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 01:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Peter Jones and Trevor Lever (the blokes behind &amp;ldquo;Terrormolinos&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hampstead&amp;rdquo;) were back with a new two part adventure &amp;ldquo;Dodgy Geezers&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;US Gold had a strong upcoming lineup with &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Masters of the Universe&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Infiltrator&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Cycle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Championship Wrestling&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Movie Monster&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;World Games&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Xevious&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Express Raider&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Break Thru&amp;rdquo;. Phew.&#xA;Lucasfilm and Activision picked up the game rights for &amp;ldquo;Labyrinth&amp;rdquo;. The movie had been received well in the US and was due to hit the UK around Christmas</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 03:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s nearly here&amp;rdquo;, declared C&amp;amp;VG about Mike Singleton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dark Sceptre&amp;rdquo;. The ambitious strategy/adventure (which was intended to have an optional Play By Mail service to allow players to compete with each other and Mike himself) had been in progress for a while and looked fantastic, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be until February 1988 that C&amp;amp;VG finally got to play it. From the review: &amp;ldquo;Was it worth the wait? We&amp;rsquo;ll pass on that&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (it received 8/10)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/7/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 04:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/7/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Leading this month&amp;rsquo;s news was US Gold&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;World Cup Carnival&amp;rdquo;, the official World Cup &amp;lsquo;86 game. A team of programmers had been working on it for 6 months and US Gold boldly claimed that it would &amp;ldquo;reach new standards in football simulation&amp;rdquo;. Sadly it would turn out to be one of the most infamously terrible games of the time, and was just a repackaging of an older title.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Slightly Magic&#34; Available for Pre-Order</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/slightly-magic-available-for-pre-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 03:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/slightly-magic-available-for-pre-order/</guid>
      <description>The remake of &amp;ldquo;Slightly Magic&amp;rdquo; by Colin Jones is almost ready for release and can now be pre-ordered. Earlier this year Colin ran a sadly unsuccessful Kickstarter for it, so it&amp;rsquo;s great to see this will indeed see the light of day.&#xA;The game features the original&amp;rsquo;s graphics and a remastered soundtrack by Allister Brimble.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 03:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Activision announced &amp;ldquo;Murder on the Missippi[sic]&amp;rdquo;, which was being written by Adam Bellin. Rather oddly C&amp;amp;VG described Bellin as &amp;ldquo;part of the team who produced the controversial &amp;lsquo;Ghostbusters&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;. I have no idea what the controversy was.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Dr Blitzen and the Islands of Arcanum&amp;rdquo; would be the followup to the popular &amp;ldquo;Dynamite Dan&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Alligata released &amp;ldquo;Who Dares Wins II&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Colin McLinton won Firebird&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Elite&amp;rdquo; competition. There were 11 finalists, all of which had achieved Elite status.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 02:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News One year and two months after Newsfield launched LM, the decision was made to end the experiment. Only 4 issues of the ambitious magazine were published and it had struggled to gain the support of ad agencies and their clients. The magazine had set out to cover &amp;ldquo;every aspect of life&amp;rdquo; for the youth audience, but was seen as being &amp;ldquo;too widely targeted&amp;rdquo; by advertisers, despite healthy sales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/25/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 01:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/25/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Tony Crowther moved back Alligata, the company he started out with. He had briefly run his own software house called Wizard Developments.&#xA;After finding success with Delta4&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bored of the Rings&amp;rdquo; CRL had signed up the new St Brides spoof &amp;ldquo;The Very Big Cave Adventure&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Little of the much hyped &amp;ldquo;Nexus&amp;rdquo; had been heard over the previous few months, but now it had resurfaced with news that Beyond would no longer be the publisher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/4/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/4/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News More changes at Crash towers this month with three new staff members: Ian Phillipson, Gareth Adams and, perhaps most notably, Ciaran Brennan.&#xA;Mastertronic was branching out into the video and music markets by launching the Master Vision and Master Sound labels.&#xA;The Tau Ceti system was to once again be the setting for a new game from CRL called &amp;ldquo;Traxxion&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Piracy was rife in the USSR with the &amp;ldquo;Raid Over Moscow&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Rambo&amp;rdquo; proving particularly popular.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News Roger Kean, who was the original editor of Crash, returned to resume his role after moving to Zzap64 a couple of years earlier (which had earned him the title of &amp;ldquo;traitor&amp;rdquo; from loyal Spectrum fans). Graeme Kidd was now to be editor of the ill fated LM magazine.&#xA;Spring had arrived and there were a slew of announcements by software houses of upcoming games. Some of the notable ones included:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 23:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News The UK release of &amp;ldquo;Questprobe 3&amp;rdquo; (aka &amp;ldquo;The Fantastic Four&amp;rdquo;) had suffered more delays. There had been hopes it&amp;rsquo;d be out for Christmas, but it looks like licensing issues had pushed it back.&#xA;Rhino announced &amp;ldquo;Ark Pandora&amp;rdquo; for the C64.&#xA;PSS had released two new wargames: &amp;ldquo;Falklands 82&amp;rdquo; for the Spectrum and &amp;ldquo;Theatre of Europe&amp;rdquo; for the Amstrad.&#xA;Global Software announced a game based on &amp;ldquo;the Worst Vegetable Movie of All Time&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The Attack of the Killer Tomatoes&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/22/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 23:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/22/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News Word leaked out that Epyx was working on a new console. David Morse (CEO of Epyx, and one of the original Amiga hardware designers) was involved on what was rumoured to be a new handheld. This, of course, would become the Atari Lynx.&#xA;Megadrives and NES consoles started appearing in arcades in the UK where players could purchase a set amount of play time with a range of games available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/20/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 06:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/20/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News With yet more consolidation of software houses, Graeme Kidd painted a rather bleak outlook for innovative and original games. Fewer, bigger companies spending more and more on licenses and marketing meant there was little room for fresh ideas. The only hope, in his eyes, was a system much like book publishing where &amp;ldquo;authors tout their wares around the large publishers.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;More tweaks were made to Crash&amp;rsquo;s review process. The quality of software had improved substantially since the early days and it was time for Crash to take a step back and judge games on a scale where 50% meant an average game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chaos Reborn Kickstarter Launched</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/chaos-reborn-kickstarter-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 06:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/chaos-reborn-kickstarter-launched/</guid>
      <description>After about a year of building a prototype and refining the systems, Julian Gollop has launched a Kickstarter for &amp;ldquo;Chaos Reborn&amp;rdquo;. Gollop has created many brilliant games over the years - &amp;ldquo;Rebelstar&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Laser Squad&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;X-Com&amp;rdquo; to name a few - and now he&amp;rsquo;s returning to one of his first, [&amp;ldquo;Chaos&amp;rdquo;][131]. It will be a turn based affair, set in a fantasy realm with magic and unique creatures, and will feature a variety of multiplayer modes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 06:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News The biggest news by far this month was that US Gold had merged with Ultimate Play The Game, and that US Gold would now handle all international manufacturing, promotion, marketing and sales of Ultimate games. Ultimate said that they were going to concentrate on making games and planned to release six new titles during 1986. What wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear was just how involved the Stamper brothers were to be, but it would turn out that they already had their eyes on the new Japanese consoles and the formation of a certain company called Rare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 05:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News Atari Games (not to be confused with hardware manufacturer, Atari) sued Nintendo for $100 million over the inability to publish games for the NES without going through the Japanese company. Nintendo seemed unphased by the move, saying that they had never lost a lawsuit.&#xA;Confusion reigned over the specifics for the Konix Slipstream. TGM attempted to clear things up by confirming that it would retail at £150 (or slightly higher), have a set of peripherals (hydraulic chair, light gun, 3D helmet), some of which would be included with the console (not the chair!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 05:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Graeme Kidd lamented the glut of poor games with big movie, TV and arcade licenses attached. Were game developers spending too much time and money on the licenses while neglecting the actual games? And was this just a temporary phase or would it become a trend?&#xA;Crash made some changes to their review system: reviews would now be signed, and the rated categories were massaged (Getting Started and Use Of Computer were replaced by Presentation).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/9/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 01:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/9/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Andrew Braybrook revealed his new game, &amp;ldquo;Uridium&amp;rdquo;. It promised &amp;ldquo;super- fast scrolling and authentically addictive action&amp;rdquo; and would certainly end up delivering.&#xA;Infocom slashed the prices on several of their games for a Christmas promotion. &amp;ldquo;Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide To The Galaxy&amp;rdquo; would drop to £24.95, while others would be between £14 and £22.&#xA;Two schoolboys raised £80 for famine relief in Ethiopia by playing games for 24 hours. The games included &amp;ldquo;Castle Quest&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alien 8&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Revs&amp;rdquo;, all on their BBC which apparently &amp;ldquo;did get a bit hot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw a new &amp;ldquo;bigger and brighter&amp;rdquo; look for TGM.&#xA;Excitement was growing for the impending release of the Konix Slipstream megaconsole. Costing a mere £149 it was due to go on sale in Autumn and would be able to read software from standard 3&amp;quot; disks as well as cartridges. Disks were looking like the preferred format due to being much cheaper to produce - customers could look forward to paying only 15 quid for games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broken Age Part 1</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/broken-age-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 23:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/19/broken-age-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The Double Fine Adventure Kickstarter was one of those few moments where you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re actually seeing a seismic shift in the industry. I jumped in within hours of the campaign going live - as a huge fan of adventure games, particularly those from Lucasfilm/Lucas Arts, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to think twice. It&amp;rsquo;s been a really fascinating ride since then - the behind the scenes videos are the best accounts of game development ever committed to film, and I almost don&amp;rsquo;t want them to finish the game as that will mean the end of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/12/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 01:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/12/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News With the news that Ultimate had morphed into Rare and committed exclusively to consoles - due to hit the UK in the coming months - and the arrival of powerful 16bit machines, Graeme Kidd tried allay the fears of readers about the future of the Speccy. A swath of top quality games had come out for the Spectrum in the last few months of 1986 and Graeme reckoned all those talented programmers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to suddenly jump ship to the new platforms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Midwinter Remake</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/10/midwinter-remake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 21:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/10/midwinter-remake/</guid>
      <description>Chris Wild, who was behind the excellent iOS remake of &amp;ldquo;Lords of Midnight&amp;rdquo;, has announced that his company is now taking on a brand new version of another Mike Singleton classic: &amp;ldquo;Midwinter&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Midwinter&amp;rdquo; received considerable critical claim but slipped by unnoticed by many (including myself). A sprawling open world game originally released on the Amiga in 1989, &amp;ldquo;Midwinter&amp;rdquo; was an early, influential example of sandbox gameplay.&#xA;The game is currently in pre-production, with a Kickstarter campaign expected to start in the next few months.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/5/mun4x70unjj1dh0jl2mlo3doj77olx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/5/mun4x70unjj1dh0jl2mlo3doj77olx/</guid>
      <description>News Dave Perry and Nick Jones had nearly wrapped up the latest Wally game for MikroGen - &amp;ldquo;Three Weeks in Paradise&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Domark released a screenshot of their rather controversial &amp;ldquo;Friday the 13th&amp;rdquo;. The game certainly got the attention of the press but - unsurprisingly - for all the wrong reasons, as it turned out to be rubbish. (&amp;ldquo;Oh dear, oh dear&amp;rdquo; lamented Crash in their review).&#xA;A BBC conversion of Imagine&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Arcadia&amp;rdquo; called &amp;ldquo;Wet Zone&amp;rdquo; was to be distributed on the Micronet 800 dialup service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter for a Bluetooth Speccy</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/22/kickstarter-for-a-bluetooth-speccy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 22:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/22/kickstarter-for-a-bluetooth-speccy/</guid>
      <description>This draft Kickstarter campaign for a Bluetooth ZX Spectrum could be interesting. My old 48K only has a partially function keyboard (I really should get around to getting a new keyboard membrane for it), and Elite&amp;rsquo;s emulation on iOS is generally pretty good so this could be a good way to get a more authentic Speccy experience. I certainly hope that it will be useable as a standard Bluetooth keyboard so other emulators (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/22/this-month-in-tgm-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 22:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/22/this-month-in-tgm-88/</guid>
      <description>News The console wars were heating up as rumours surfaced that Nintendo and Sega were working on 16bit machines. Neither the NES or Master System had managed to gain much of a foothold in the UK - both machines selling around 45,000 units each - but the tide did seem to be turning. Code Masters were rather bullish about the console market, with Operations Manager Bruce Everiss being particularly enthusiastic about the Konix Slipstream: &amp;ldquo;I think Konix has the potential to be another Amstrad.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retro Gamer site revamp</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/15/retro-gamer-site-revamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 23:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/15/retro-gamer-site-revamp/</guid>
      <description>The site for the best retro gaming magazine out there (and, arguably, one of the finest gaming mags ever) has received a lick of fresh paint. It looks like they&amp;rsquo;ll be updating it more frequently with new articles, and emphasis on profiles (be they a game, old software house, retro hero or community member) should be interesting.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve been subscribing since around issue 15 (issue 123 has just been published!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/15/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 22:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/15/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News A Crash contingent went down to London for the 20th ZX Microfair. While the event was usually held in the &amp;ldquo;cavernous&amp;rdquo; Royal Horticultural Hall, a booking mixup meant this one had to move to &amp;ldquo;several rooms and various floors&amp;rdquo; at Central Hall in Westminster. There were very few new products to talk about, the only ones receiving a mention being &amp;ldquo;The Professional Adventure Writing System&amp;rdquo;, a new disk interface from Rockfort called &amp;ldquo;The Disciple&amp;rdquo; and Romantic Robot&amp;rsquo;s video digitiser.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contradiction Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/8/contradiction-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 21:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/8/contradiction-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Tim Follin (one of the great composers from the 8/16 bit years) has launched a rather interesting looking Kickstarter campaign for an &amp;ldquo;interactive murder mystery movie&amp;rdquo; called &amp;ldquo;Contradiction&amp;rdquo;. While the game looks to be similar to traditional FMV games, the way the player interacts with it promises to be far more fluid. Murder mysteries are bizarrely under-represented in games and it&amp;rsquo;s a genre that I love dearly, so it&amp;rsquo;s great to see someone taking this on and adding their own twist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 21:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Ariolasoft released a couple of screenshots from a new game which promised to be a &amp;ldquo;totally interactive graphic adventure &amp;lsquo;movie&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; The game, &amp;ldquo;Wild West&amp;rdquo;, received luke warm reviews, but it was notable in that it was one of those rarities at the time: a game developed behind the iron curtain.&#xA;Activision were to take on EA&amp;rsquo;s excellent &amp;ldquo;Racing Destruction Set&amp;rdquo; with their own racing game with a built in editor called &amp;ldquo;Fast Tracks&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slightly Magic Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/slightly-magic-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/slightly-magic-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Colin Jones is probably best known for his excellent rock star management simulation, &amp;ldquo;Rock Star Ate My Hamster&amp;rdquo;, which featured many thinly veiled (rather biting) pop culture references. &amp;ldquo;Slightly Magic&amp;rdquo; was a later creation of his which was always intended to be part of a trilogy of games, but sadly the latter two chapters were never released. Colin is now hoping to resurrect Slightly, starting with an updated version of &amp;ldquo;Slightly Magic&amp;rdquo; followed by two new games to complete the series.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Elite announced &amp;ldquo;Scooby-Doo in the Castle Mystery&amp;rdquo;, teasing gamers with a couple of amazing looking screens. It promised to provide cartoon like quality graphics but the game then promptly disappeared, only to resurface some time later as a very good, but very different game developed for Elite by Gargoyle Games.&#xA;Christian Urqhart (programmer behind games like &amp;ldquo;Daley Thompson&amp;rsquo;s Decathlon&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hunchback&amp;rdquo;) had left Ocean and formed his own company, Alphabatim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News The Crash staff, along with all the other Newsfield folk, went down to London for the launch party of their new magazine, LM. The venue was the Camden Palace and plenty of gaming bigwigs were in attendance. Sadly the magazine failed to gain much traction, folding after only a handful of issues.&#xA;The release of Amstrad&amp;rsquo;s Spectrum +2 had many scratching their heads. Despite the official release having taken place in September, people were unable to find any in shops.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News After months of speculation, Amstrad finally revealed their 16bit Sinclair. It was not, as many thought, a games console, but a rather unimpressive PC. The reception was luke warm at best: &amp;ldquo;is Amstrad&amp;rsquo;s Sinclair a powerless business computer or a games machine that&amp;rsquo;s unsuitable for games?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Meanwhile, excitement was riding high for the Konix console. The release date was to be January 28th and would include a bunch of add ons, including the hydraulic chair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter for a book by Andrew Hewson</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/kickstarter-for-a-book-by-andrew-hewson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 21:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/kickstarter-for-a-book-by-andrew-hewson/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Hewson is running a Kickstarter for a new book detailing his experiences and insights from a long career in videogame development. I&amp;rsquo;m not terribly keen on the title of the book (&amp;ldquo;Hints &amp;amp; Tips for Videogame Pioneers&amp;rdquo;) as it sounds a bit like those &amp;ldquo;Learn how to program C++ in 24 hours!&amp;rdquo; books, but I would love to read his accounts of what was one my favourite software houses of the 80s/90s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 21:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/27/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Word on the street was that Atari was readying not one, but four new ST machines. The main one would be a &amp;ldquo;super ST&amp;rdquo; that would take on the Amiga, then there was a portable ST, a &amp;ldquo;Pocket PC&amp;rdquo; and an ST based console. Not only that, but the existing 520STFM would have its price slashed by £100 and get a software bundle valued at £440. How many of these would actually hit the selves?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 01:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News Celebrations at Crash towers as the latest circulation figures showed they had sold 101,483 copies a month on average between January and June. That number placed Crash ahead of all other computer mags.&#xA;This issue was the first to feature a cover drawn by someone other than Oliver Frey - Ian Craig was the illustrator responsible. It seemed that with the increasing array of magazines published by Newsfield, Frey had too much on his plate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 23:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News After months of teasing, the new look for C&amp;amp;VG was here. It was quite a radical change and still looks pretty decent today.&#xA;The excellent &amp;ldquo;Bored of the Rings&amp;rdquo; was going to be re-launched by Silversoft and would feature new locations and graphics.&#xA;Beyond struck a deal with Mindscape that would see its games distributed in the the US. First up were &amp;ldquo;Lords of Midnight&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Shadowfire&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Quake Minus One&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/29/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 01:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/29/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News The Personal Computer World Show was about to happen and publishers were busy announcing/teasing their upcoming games. Full details of what was on display would be in next month&amp;rsquo;s issue, but there was a boatload of previews to do.&#xA;Not one but two winners had been chosen for the Genesis competition Crash launched a few months earlier. The first was a shoot em up called &amp;ldquo;Kat Trap&amp;rdquo; by John Eggleton that would hopefully be out by Christmas, while the second - &amp;ldquo;The Sewer&amp;rdquo; by Martin Lee - was planned for Spring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blitz Games closes down</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/blitz-games-closes-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 05:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/blitz-games-closes-down/</guid>
      <description>Well, this is sad. Blitz Games has closed down after 23 years. The Oliver Twins have been prominent members of the UK games industry since they shot to fame in the 80s for their much loved Dizzy series of games. I&amp;rsquo;ve never met them myself, but everyone I know that has has nothing but glowing things to say about them - they&amp;rsquo;ve been an immense help to many UK developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-the-games-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 04:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-the-games-machine/</guid>
      <description>News Atari appeared to be winning the battle of the 16bits. A combination of a very generous software bundle, price drop and big ad campaign saw sales of the ST see a rise even during the usual summer slump. Meanwhile, the Amiga was still having problems with reliability - some shops putting returns as high as 25%. Software sales were reportedly 70/30 in favour of the ST.&#xA;A small South Wales company called Miles Gordon Technology (MGT) was about to release a Spectrum &amp;ldquo;super clone&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 04:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News The Golden Sundial of Pi prize from &amp;ldquo;Pimania&amp;rdquo; was finally found! The winners - Sue Cooper and Lizi Newman - solved the puzzle by being at Hindover Hill in Sussex on July 22nd. The competition had begun on the release of &amp;ldquo;Pimania&amp;rdquo; in 1982.&#xA;British Telecom were about to open up public access to M.U.D. (multi-user dungeon), which had previously just been available to students and staff at Essex University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;91</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-91/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 01:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/25/this-month-in-the-one-91/</guid>
      <description>News The Bitmap Brothers announced their next game. It would be a top down arcade game with role playing elements where the player took control of one of six characters. It was very much a multiplayer game, and the AI had been designed so that they computer would fill in for any unused players. The graphical style was fresh and quite unique and the game would become known as one of the first examples of Steampunk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/18/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 08:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/18/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Commodore had been reluctant to try to bring the Amiga&amp;rsquo;s price in line with the cheaper Atari ST, but this month the long rumoured £100 cut happened. The ST had stormed ahead in sales and it looked like it would be a tough battle for the Amiga, which Commodore had originally pitched as a business machine but was now accepting that it&amp;rsquo;s destiny would be games.&#xA;Sugar&amp;rsquo;s Amstrad entered into a partnership with Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s Sky satellite TV company which would see Amstrad producing and selling £199 dishes that would receive the four Sky channels once the service launched early in the following year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Chaos Engine remake announced</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/18/the-chaos-engine-remake-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 01:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/18/the-chaos-engine-remake-announced/</guid>
      <description>Rather exciting news: a remake of the excellent Amiga game The Chaos Engine has been announced for PS, Mac and Linux. This game has always struck me as an obvious candidate for an update, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to hear it&amp;rsquo;s finally happening. Development duties are being handled by Abstraction Games who most recently ported Hotline Miami to the PS3 an Vita. Fingers crossed it&amp;rsquo;ll have been worth the wait.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/13/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 08:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/8/13/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News US Gold had signed the licenses to a couple of Disney games, &amp;ldquo;Winnie the Pooh in the Hundred Acre Wood&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Donald Duck&amp;rsquo;s Playground&amp;rdquo;. Both were aimed at children, and both were written by Al Lowe (including the music).&#xA;Even though Ocean had been publishing Konami&amp;rsquo;s games in the US, they were strangely absent from UK shelves. This was about to change with &amp;ldquo;Hypersports&amp;rdquo;, followed by &amp;ldquo;Konami Tennis&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Yie Ar Kung-Fu&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Hyper Rally&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Golf&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Mikie&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Comic Bakery&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deus Ex Machina 2 take two</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/7/23/deus-ex-machina-2-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 22:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/7/23/deus-ex-machina-2-take-two/</guid>
      <description>After an unsuccessful first attempt at a Kickstarter, the Automata folks have solicited feedback and re-launched the campaign with tweaked rewards, logo and even aspects of the game itself. Perhaps more importantly, they&amp;rsquo;re asking for considerably less. Hopefully this time they&amp;rsquo;ll make it, though I do wonder why the campaign is only lasting for 2 weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/7/19/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 21:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/7/19/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Not a game as such, but the latest book from William Gibson, &amp;ldquo;Mona Lisa Overdrive&amp;rdquo;, was about to hit the shelves. To mark the occasion, the Cyberpunk theme would be visited several times in this issue.&#xA;What was billed &amp;ldquo;the first mass-market desktop-publishing (DTP) packag&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; was launched by mouse manufacturer AMS for PC-XT and AT compatibles. It featured a mouse, a handheld scanner and software - all for only £447.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/7/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 06:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/7/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Plans were afoot to build Britain&amp;rsquo;s first Laser tag centre. It would be built on Wellington Pier in Great Yarmouth and promised to &amp;ldquo;take leisure and entertainment &amp;lsquo;into the 21st century.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Games Workshop was about to release &amp;ldquo;Chaos&amp;rdquo; by a certain Julian Gollop who would go onto produce such genre defining games as Rebelstar and XCom. He has a remake of &amp;ldquo;Chaos&amp;rdquo; underway and you can follow his progress on his blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 05:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Computers and Art&amp;rdquo; was a new travelling exhibition that had just opened at the IBM Gallery of Science and Art in NYC. It was an attempt to bring &amp;ldquo;computer art&amp;rdquo; into the mainstream - not just graphics, but works using fabric etc. Elsewhere, Carnegie Mellon began a course on writing &amp;ldquo;interactive fiction.&amp;rdquo; CRL&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Wolfman&amp;rdquo; was in the news for failing to be slapped with a British Board of Censors rating certificate, unlike their previous adventures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-crash-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 05:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-crash-88/</guid>
      <description>News On the back of the news that the price of the Spectrum 128K had dropped following the acquisition by Amstrad, rumours started to circulate that a 256K &amp;ldquo;games machine&amp;rdquo; was in the pipeline. According to the rumours the machine would be Spectrum based but would use credit card sized &amp;ldquo;cartridges&amp;rdquo;. Reactions were mixed - while this would drastically reduce piracy, software houses feared Amstrad having control over what games would be released.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deus Ex Machina 2 Kickstarter!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/16/deus-ex-machina-2-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 04:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/16/deus-ex-machina-2-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>As I previously mentioned , a sequel the the amazing &amp;ldquo;Deus Ex Machina&amp;rdquo; is in the works. Well, Mel is now looking for backers to help fund the final stages of production. I&amp;rsquo;m still unsure of just how the game will turn out (the original was more about the experience as a whole, rather than they gameplay itself), but it cannot be overstated how important the original and Mel himself was to the early game scene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/16/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 04:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/16/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Atari announced they were about to launch a new range of computers. First there were the new XEs which were basically upgraded/re-styled 800 XLs. But more importantly were the STs which would provide an impressive jump from the existing machines. Robert Schifreen who had written the &amp;ldquo;Bug hunter&amp;rdquo; and Micronet columns for C&amp;amp;VG was arrested for hacking. Notable Reviews &amp;ldquo;Starion&amp;rdquo; Melbourne House - Spectrum Game of the Month 10/10 &amp;ldquo;Programmer David Webb, a 19-year old student, spent nine months working on Starion - and if there&amp;rsquo;s any justice in the world he will be rewarded with a number one hit!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 09:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News The first ever British entertainment software conference took place, with representatives from Britain&amp;rsquo;s top software houses and distributors in attendance. A gala awards dinner was held which handed out awards based on Crash and Zzap!64 reader awards. Best Spectrum game went to &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo; from Incentive, with &amp;ldquo;California Games&amp;rdquo; from Epyx/US Gold winning best C64 game. Ocean won best software house for readers of both magazines.&#xA;Games Workshop opened a new retail outlet on Oxford Street and a queue of &amp;ldquo;well over&amp;rdquo; 1000 people showed up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 03:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News Huge news arrived just hours before this issue went to press - Amstrad had bought Sinclair for meagre £5 million. What would this mean for Sinclair products? The QL and microdrive would be likely casualties, but it sounded like Amstrad had promising plans for the Spectrum. Overall it was taken as a positive happening, though the alternative would&amp;rsquo;ve been receivership for Sinclair. Sir Clive himself was to return to research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Woakes interviewed?!</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/paul-woakes-interviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 21:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/paul-woakes-interviewed/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the people behind the &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms To Billions&amp;rdquo; doco tweeted something very intriguing indeed:&#xA;Latest interview just shot! With the sword of Damocles over our heads we needed a Mercenary to bail us out! What an Encounter that was!&#xA;— FrmBedrooms2Billions (@FromBedrooms) May 17, 2013&#xA;This is obviously a reference to Novagen, but could this actually mean they interviewed Paul Woakes? As far as I&amp;rsquo;m aware, this would be a first if true.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/12/this-month-in-cvg-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/12/this-month-in-cvg-/</guid>
      <description>News Not games related as such, but May saw the launch of C&amp;amp;VG&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bring Back the Doctor&amp;rdquo; campaign after the BBC announced Doctor Who was to end. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the BBC had specified when this was to happen, as it would last another 4 years.&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;Designer of the Month&amp;rdquo; was Stephen Redman, a 21 year old uni student who released the somewhat controversial (how innocent we all were) game &amp;ldquo;A Day in the Life&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Return of the PiMan?</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/5/return-of-the-piman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 20:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/5/return-of-the-piman/</guid>
      <description>I have no idea how this managed to escape my attention for so long, but it appears Mel Croucher has relaunched Automata. According to the site, not only is Deus Ex Machina 2 on the way, but also remakes of PiMania and even Thanatos. The latter is interesting seeing as I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure Croucher had nothing to do with the original.&#xA;The original Deus Ex Machina was quite easily one of the most incredible game experiences I had during that time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 19:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Rare had been inundated with calls from developers wanting in on the Nintendo market and the Z80 arcade board that they (Rare) were working on. This all follows on from a pretty amazing interview with Rare in the previous issue of TGM - amazing because it was the first (and perhaps only?) proper interview conducted with the Stamper brothers. Everyone had been wondering what happened to Ultimate Play The Game (arguably the finest developer of the 8bit years), and now we all knew.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St Brides</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/23/st-brides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 04:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/23/st-brides/</guid>
      <description>St Brides were easily one of those most intriguing software houses of the 80s. For a start they produced some great adventures games - &amp;ldquo;The Very Big Cave Adventure&amp;rdquo; was my first exposure to them, which I remember fondly. Their games were known for being well written with a keen sense of humour. Then there was the fact that they appeared to be a company consisting entirely of women (quite unique in the industry), as they were generally referred to as &amp;ldquo;the sisters&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;the ladies&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;the belles&amp;rdquo;/etc of St Brides (to what extent this was actually the case, I&amp;rsquo;m unsure).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/21/this-month-in-crash-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 22:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/21/this-month-in-crash-85/</guid>
      <description>Compared to the previous few months, there seemed like a relative dearth of good games released for the Spectrum. Crash pondered whether this had anything to do with the recent release of the Spectrum 128K. Game compilations (often tied to a charity) were coming out at a ridiculous rate - would this result in the cost of games for the consumer (typically kids) going down? or will the revenue developers see take a big hit as people choose cheap compilations over &amp;ldquo;single&amp;rdquo; release games?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensible World of Soccer (XBLA)</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/14/sensible-world-of-soccer-xbla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/14/sensible-world-of-soccer-xbla/</guid>
      <description>When I finally got around to picking up a 360 a couple of years ago, the first thing I did when I set it up was download Sensible World Of Soccer (SWOS). Forget Halo, or Gears of War, or Mass Effect; SWOS was what I cared about. The Amiga version is the game I routinely tell people is &amp;ldquo;the best game ever made&amp;rdquo; and I played it everyday for years during the 90s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Bedrooms to Billions</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/3/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 19:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/3/12/from-bedrooms-to-billions/</guid>
      <description>After a successful round of crowdfunding last year, the people behind the &amp;ldquo;From Bedrooms to Billions&amp;rdquo; documentary and conducting a new Kickstarter campaign in order to cover the myriad of costs involved in finishing and polishing the film. With the passing of Mike Singleton, it&amp;rsquo;s become clear that we need to record the histories of the people involved in the UK games industry during the 80s. The interviews they&amp;rsquo;ve managed to snag are extremely impressive - so many of my heroes are in there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year Walk (iOS)</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/2/25/year-walk-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 23:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/2/25/year-walk-ios/</guid>
      <description>The walk begins.&#xA;While it isn&amp;rsquo;t retro related as such, this certainly deserves a mention. Last week the consistently excellent iOS developer Simogo released their latest game, &amp;ldquo;Year Walk&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a highly atmospheric affair, rather beautiful yet sinister, that references various Swedish folk tales (the &amp;ldquo;Year Walk&amp;rdquo; itself being an old tradition). After a brief setup, the player is placed in a snowy landscape with no instructions on what to do - the game is all about letting the player discover everything for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archipelagos (iOS)</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/2/20/archipelagos-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 07:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/2/20/archipelagos-ios/</guid>
      <description>Archipelagos appeared on the Amiga back in 1989 and is a first person realtime puzzle/strategy game. I certainly remember playing it, but I also remember not really knowing what I was doing. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat reminiscent of The Sentinel (surely a remake of that must be on the cards?), and features 9999 procedurally generated levels.&#xA;The original scored well in magazines of the day (Zzap! gave it 90%) and the remake is a decent job, though it feels a little rough and finicky - it seems to be a pretty straightforward port of the modern desktop version and the touch controls could use some love.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
