<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1987 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1987/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1987 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 07:42:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/1987/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/8/27/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 07:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/8/27/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn bid farewell as he strode off &amp;ldquo;on a secret mission&amp;rdquo;. Ciaran Brennan was to take the reins, with Julian Rignall as his assistant. Phillipa Irving&amp;rsquo;s war game section took a break as she was busy with exams. There was also a small change to the review format, with the &amp;ldquo;Value&amp;rdquo; rating being dropped.
Arnie&amp;rsquo;s latest film &amp;ldquo;Predator&amp;rdquo; had grossed $12 million at the box office in its first 3 days and Activision had signed the license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/16/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 06:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/16/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Software Projects announced that they were reducing their prices to £5.95 in the run up to Christmas. Others were expected to follow suit, though that did seem somewhat unlikely as that’s a steep drop down from £9.95. Gary Penn pondered how lower prices might affect the quality of games - lower budgets for development? less licensed tie-ins? (The latter was considered a good thing)
Ciaran Brennan was promoted to Assistant Editor, and Gary Liddon was due to make his return next month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 08:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/6/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Firebird closed a deal with Activision/Electric Dreams which would see the budget publisher re-releasing a slew of older titles from the US for £1.99 each.
No changes at Zzap! this month, though Julian Rignall got engaged to Glenys Powell, the “ever-effervescent” Editorial Assistant.
Zzap! launched in Italy. Note the lack of “64” - Speccy, Atari, MSX and C16 gamers would all be catered for.
The Sensi Software lads were wrapping up their next game: the awesome &amp;ldquo;Wizball”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/15/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 08:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/5/15/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Thanks to a tweet from Julian Rignall I finally noticed that the ships getting blown up by Zzap!64 on the cover represented Commodore User &amp;amp; C&amp;amp;VG. Cheeky.
The reason for such a cover? Sales had climbed to 67,728 per month and showed no signs of letting up. The mag would be undergoing a few changes - they looked to be broadening the scope of what they were covering, including “unusual, but relevant” features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 07:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News A couple of new arrivals at Zzap! this month, with Steve Jarratt swapping industrial chemistry for games journalism and Philipa Irving who, er, swapped Crash for its Newsfield sibling.
Ariolasoft’s Starlight label had three games on the way. &amp;ldquo;Dogfight 2187&amp;rdquo; promised 3D wireframe shoot ‘em up action with a vertically split screen giving two views of the action. The other two games were &amp;ldquo;Deathscape&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Greyfell”. Meanwhile Tony Crowther had teamed up with Keith Blake and Ross Goodley to develop ”Challenge of the Gobots” based on the popular kids cartoon, which would be published by Ariolasoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 07:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn wrote a long editorial on a matter that had been on a lot of people’s minds: had quality and innovation taken a dive as software houses relied more and more on coin-op, TV and film licenses? The market seemed to be full of these unimaginative and often shoddy tie ins which, aside from the attached IP, only had good presentation going for them. Developers were feeling the pinch as well: publishers would “guarantee 100,000” copies sold, giving them an excuse to lower royalties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 06:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/2/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn responded to grumblings from readers about the Christmas issue. The main complaints were around the lack of reviews and the price. The former issue was hardly the magazine’s fault as publisher’s were taking any morsel of time they could get in order to get games on the shelves for the Christmas shoppers.
Electric Dreams/Activision had a whopping dozen licensed arcade conversions heading to the C64. They included: &amp;ldquo;Tempest” (unreleased?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/25/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 08:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/1/25/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Gary Penn lamented the fact that for the first time there had not been a single Sizzler or Gold Medal awarded in an issue. Well, that’s not entirely true as &amp;ldquo;The Bard’s Tale&amp;rdquo; picked up a very respectable Sizzler, though apparently it didn’t count as it was “a role playing game”. It seemed that software houses were spending as much time as possible before Christmas to polish up their hopeful hits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/12/29/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 05:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/12/29/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Rainbird&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Universal Military Simulator&amp;rdquo; for the ST promised wargaming fans the ability to re-enact a vast array of different battles, including ones between armies from different time periods.
&amp;ldquo;Stratton&amp;rdquo; from CRL would see the player attempt to shutdown the automated defence units of a space station which had suffered a terrorist attack and had turned on its inhabitants. (unable to find evidence of this being released)
Bike racing game &amp;ldquo;500 Grand Prix&amp;rdquo;, published by French house Loricels, was heading to the ST, IBM and C64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/11/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 07:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/11/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Microprose&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;F-15 Strike Eagle&amp;rdquo; was about to land on the ST. The ST would also get a port of Mirrorsoft&amp;rsquo;s flightsim featuring a somewhat older aircraft, &amp;ldquo;Spitfire 40&amp;rdquo;.
Viz were working on &amp;ldquo;Werewolves of London&amp;rdquo;.
For the first time since being bought out by Mastertronic, Melbourne House announced its upcoming titles: &amp;ldquo;Roadwars&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rockford&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pulse Warrior&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Street Hassle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Metropolis&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kelly X&amp;rdquo; (I was unable to find any sign that the latter two were released, at least not under those names).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/10/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 22:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/10/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Jim Synoski and Arnold Hendrick, designers of Microprose&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Project: Stealth Fighter&amp;rdquo;, were promoting the game ahead of its launch. While they admitted nothing official was known about the fighter, they felt that they had &amp;ldquo;a fair idea of what the capabilities of the plane must be&amp;rdquo;.
Incentive&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo; was shaping up well on the Speccy.
Electric Dreams had the rights to &amp;ldquo;Knightmare&amp;rdquo; - the game of the TV series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/9/13/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 06:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/9/13/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Digital Integration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bobsleigh&amp;rdquo; was a departure from their usual flight sims and would centre around the winter event.
Incentive teased their impressive new Freescape engine with a couple of screenshots of the upcoming &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo;.
English Software were working on a Rambo-esque game: &amp;ldquo;Captain Courageous&amp;rdquo;.
Atari dropped the price of the 520STFM to £299.99. They were also planning to re-launch the 130XE and position it as &amp;ldquo;the ultimate teaching computer&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/8/25/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 08:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/8/25/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Catch 23&amp;rdquo; was a new 3D vector arcade adventure from Martech.
Epyx were continuing their &amp;ldquo;Games&amp;rdquo; series, this time focussing on events such as BMXing, skateboarding, surfing and flying disks (frisbees) in &amp;ldquo;California Games&amp;rdquo;.
Microprose were to release a new flight sim, &amp;ldquo;Project: Stealth Fighter&amp;rdquo; based on the top secret American stealth plane, and a more arcade-y combat game, &amp;ldquo;Airborne Ranger&amp;rdquo;.
Activision &amp;amp; System 3 got the game rights for Arnie&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Predator&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/7/19/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 06:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/7/19/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Dungeons, Amethysts, Alchemists &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Everythin&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; from Atlantis Software promised &amp;ldquo;the occasional rude word and sexual innuendo, novice nuns, entangled lovers and busty barmaids&amp;rdquo;. The cover of the game came with a &amp;ldquo;Not suitable for persons under the age of 16&amp;rdquo; label.
Paul Hardcastle had a big hit with his Vietnam war song &amp;ldquo;19&amp;rdquo; and Cascade were turning it into a game. Rather interestingly, the player would be faced with a choice at the start: fight the war or the draft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 07:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News US Gold had signed a deal to sponsor race driver David Hall&amp;rsquo;s car for the Formula Forward season.
Meanwhile, US Gold released &amp;ldquo;Deeper Dungeons&amp;rdquo; for those &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo; fans wanting more.
The British Open AD&amp;amp;D Championships were held at the Reading University Students Union building. Up to 600 people were expected.
Laser tag guns were the toy of the moment. The two main contenders were &amp;ldquo;Laser Combat&amp;rdquo; from Action GT, and &amp;ldquo;Laser Tag&amp;rdquo; from Mattel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/5/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 04:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/5/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Simon Price, who had previously worked on &amp;ldquo;Redhawk&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kwah!&amp;rdquo;, was developing &amp;ldquo;Wiz&amp;rdquo; for Melbourne House.
Danish software house Kele Line had two new C64 releases this month, &amp;ldquo;Thunder Force&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Unitrax&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;The 4th Dimension&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Vikings&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Pirates of the Ocean&amp;rdquo; were to follow. Seems that only &amp;ldquo;Thunder Force&amp;rdquo; (published by Hewson) and &amp;ldquo;Vikings&amp;rdquo; made it out.
&amp;ldquo;The Mystery of Arkham Manor&amp;rdquo; would see the player take on the role of a journo investigating a - as the title suggests - mysterious murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/12/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 05:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/12/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News This month C&amp;amp;VG became the biggest selling games mag in the UK, shifting 106,571 copies monthly.
The Edge picked up the license for &amp;ldquo;Garfield&amp;rdquo;.
Superior Software were launching a big spring recruitment drive, and had written a handbook for budding games programmers titled &amp;ldquo;Success in Software&amp;rdquo;.
Beano-esque comic &amp;ldquo;Oink!&amp;rdquo; was to be turned into a game by CRL.
&amp;ldquo;Dan Dare&amp;rdquo; creator, Andy Wilson, was finishing up &amp;ldquo;Laurel and Hardy&amp;rdquo; which featured a &amp;ldquo;new programming technique called Cinevision&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 05:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Indoor Sports&amp;rdquo; by Mindscape was to feature a set of &amp;ldquo;unusual&amp;rdquo; sports, such as air hockey.
Creative Sparks announced not one but four new budget titles: &amp;ldquo;Little Alien&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Smudge and the Moonees&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Shuffle&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Cyber I&amp;rdquo;. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like any of these were released.
Melbourne House&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Murder at Arkham Hall&amp;rdquo; was to be a detective style adventure with the player taking on the role of a reporter investigating a murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/14/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 21:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/2/14/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News The Robot Society of America was offering newly signed up members the chance to win an &amp;ldquo;experimental sound-activated robot&amp;rdquo; kit. Membership was $50 per year.
Bug Byte was to release old Virgin games under its budget label. &amp;ldquo;Strangeloop&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Falcon Patrol II&amp;rdquo; were among the first batch.
Also getting in on the budget action was newcomer Alternative Software with releases such as &amp;ldquo;Howzat&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Henry&amp;rsquo;s Hoard&amp;rdquo;. Not exactly the most thrilling line up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 20:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Ocean was to bring &amp;ldquo;Donkey Kong&amp;rdquo; to the C64, Spectrum and Amstrad.
&amp;ldquo;Blood n&amp;rsquo; Guts&amp;rdquo; was heading to the C64 and was described by publisher American Action as &amp;ldquo;an ancient barbarian decathlon with all the violence and brutality you&amp;rsquo;ve ever dreamed about in a computer game&amp;rdquo;. Oo-kay.
Atari&amp;rsquo;s 7800 was about to hit the shelves retailing for around £70, with games costing £10-15.
Bo Jangeborg was busy finishing &amp;ldquo;Fairlight II&amp;rdquo;, which was to be double the size and feature a greater variety of graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 03:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Ciaran Brennan had only just taken over the helm at ZZap! but he was already moving onto pastures new. This ushered in Julian Rignall as editor.
US Gold acquired the rights to the &amp;ldquo;Rolling Thunder&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Roadblasters&amp;rdquo; coin ops. Meanwhile, the publisher dropped the price of all of their C64 disk games from £14.99 to £11.99 (thanks to economies of scale).
Telecomsoft scored a bit of a coup, signing Graftgold away from Hewson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News This issue came complete with a pair of red/blue 3D glasses and to use when reading the &amp;ldquo;3D Tips Supplement&amp;rdquo;.
Incentive Software&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Graphic Adventure Creator Plus&amp;rdquo; was due in the coming month. This new version would allow games to use a disc-access system - similar to Infocom&amp;rsquo;s games - which would allow much bigger adventures. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure if this was actually released.
Level 9 unveiled their latest adventure, &amp;ldquo;Gnome Ranger&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/this-month-in-zzap-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 00:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/10/19/this-month-in-zzap-87/</guid>
      <description>News The Audit Bureau of Circulations report showed that Zzap!&amp;rsquo;s readership had reached an impressive 77,483 in the first 6 months of the year.
Delta4 re-surfaced as Abstract Concepts and Fergus McNeil was busy working on a new fancy adventure system.
The next game from Stavros Fasoulas under the Thalamus label would be &amp;ldquo;Quedex&amp;rdquo;.
Features Part one of a series on the history of the shoot&amp;rsquo;em up.
Andrew Braybrook&amp;rsquo;s development diary of &amp;ldquo;Morpheus&amp;rdquo; drew to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 02:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-zzap64/</guid>
      <description>News Sensible Software signed to Outlaw, Palace Software&amp;rsquo;s new label. The first game the sensi chaps would deliver was &amp;ldquo;Shoot&amp;rsquo;em Up Construction Kit&amp;rdquo; (or SEUCK as it came to be known as).
A game based on Jeffrey Archer&amp;rsquo;s first novel, &amp;ldquo;Not a Penny More, Not a Penny Less&amp;rdquo; was in the works. Meanwhile, Archer had been busy in a highly publicised court case and had just been acquitted.
There was a &amp;ldquo;Ten Things You Never Knew About Mark Cale&amp;rdquo; section (head of System 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 02:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News One year and two months after Newsfield launched LM, the decision was made to end the experiment. Only 4 issues of the ambitious magazine were published and it had struggled to gain the support of ad agencies and their clients. The magazine had set out to cover &amp;ldquo;every aspect of life&amp;rdquo; for the youth audience, but was seen as being &amp;ldquo;too widely targeted&amp;rdquo; by advertisers, despite healthy sales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/4/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/4/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News More changes at Crash towers this month with three new staff members: Ian Phillipson, Gareth Adams and, perhaps most notably, Ciaran Brennan.
Mastertronic was branching out into the video and music markets by launching the Master Vision and Master Sound labels.
The Tau Ceti system was to once again be the setting for a new game from CRL called &amp;ldquo;Traxxion&amp;rdquo;.
Piracy was rife in the USSR with the &amp;ldquo;Raid Over Moscow&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Rambo&amp;rdquo; proving particularly popular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News Roger Kean, who was the original editor of Crash, returned to resume his role after moving to Zzap64 a couple of years earlier (which had earned him the title of &amp;ldquo;traitor&amp;rdquo; from loyal Spectrum fans). Graeme Kidd was now to be editor of the ill fated LM magazine.
Spring had arrived and there were a slew of announcements by software houses of upcoming games. Some of the notable ones included:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/20/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 06:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/20/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News With yet more consolidation of software houses, Graeme Kidd painted a rather bleak outlook for innovative and original games. Fewer, bigger companies spending more and more on licenses and marketing meant there was little room for fresh ideas. The only hope, in his eyes, was a system much like book publishing where &amp;ldquo;authors tout their wares around the large publishers.&amp;rdquo;
More tweaks were made to Crash&amp;rsquo;s review process. The quality of software had improved substantially since the early days and it was time for Crash to take a step back and judge games on a scale where 50% meant an average game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 05:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Graeme Kidd lamented the glut of poor games with big movie, TV and arcade licenses attached. Were game developers spending too much time and money on the licenses while neglecting the actual games? And was this just a temporary phase or would it become a trend?
Crash made some changes to their review system: reviews would now be signed, and the rated categories were massaged (Getting Started and Use Of Computer were replaced by Presentation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/12/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 01:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/12/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News With the news that Ultimate had morphed into Rare and committed exclusively to consoles - due to hit the UK in the coming months - and the arrival of powerful 16bit machines, Graeme Kidd tried allay the fears of readers about the future of the Speccy. A swath of top quality games had come out for the Spectrum in the last few months of 1986 and Graeme reckoned all those talented programmers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to suddenly jump ship to the new platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
