<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crash on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/crash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crash on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 02:48:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/crash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crash Annual 2018 Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/24/crash-annual-2018-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 02:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/7/24/crash-annual-2018-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>The Kickstarter for the 99th issue of Crash magazine has gone live. Roger Kean is back on editing duties, and Oli Frey will be creating the cover and art - we&amp;rsquo;ll even see the return of the Jetman comic strip. The line up of other contributors is also looking rather impressive.&#xA;Crash holds a special place in my heart - it was my main go to mag back in the day (before, I admit, I jumped ship to the C64&amp;hellip;), and I still have all the well worn issues I used to pore over each month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 02:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News One year and two months after Newsfield launched LM, the decision was made to end the experiment. Only 4 issues of the ambitious magazine were published and it had struggled to gain the support of ad agencies and their clients. The magazine had set out to cover &amp;ldquo;every aspect of life&amp;rdquo; for the youth audience, but was seen as being &amp;ldquo;too widely targeted&amp;rdquo; by advertisers, despite healthy sales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/4/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/5/4/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News More changes at Crash towers this month with three new staff members: Ian Phillipson, Gareth Adams and, perhaps most notably, Ciaran Brennan.&#xA;Mastertronic was branching out into the video and music markets by launching the Master Vision and Master Sound labels.&#xA;The Tau Ceti system was to once again be the setting for a new game from CRL called &amp;ldquo;Traxxion&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Piracy was rife in the USSR with the &amp;ldquo;Raid Over Moscow&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Rambo&amp;rdquo; proving particularly popular.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News Roger Kean, who was the original editor of Crash, returned to resume his role after moving to Zzap64 a couple of years earlier (which had earned him the title of &amp;ldquo;traitor&amp;rdquo; from loyal Spectrum fans). Graeme Kidd was now to be editor of the ill fated LM magazine.&#xA;Spring had arrived and there were a slew of announcements by software houses of upcoming games. Some of the notable ones included:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/20/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 06:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/20/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News With yet more consolidation of software houses, Graeme Kidd painted a rather bleak outlook for innovative and original games. Fewer, bigger companies spending more and more on licenses and marketing meant there was little room for fresh ideas. The only hope, in his eyes, was a system much like book publishing where &amp;ldquo;authors tout their wares around the large publishers.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;More tweaks were made to Crash&amp;rsquo;s review process. The quality of software had improved substantially since the early days and it was time for Crash to take a step back and judge games on a scale where 50% meant an average game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 05:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/2/23/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Graeme Kidd lamented the glut of poor games with big movie, TV and arcade licenses attached. Were game developers spending too much time and money on the licenses while neglecting the actual games? And was this just a temporary phase or would it become a trend?&#xA;Crash made some changes to their review system: reviews would now be signed, and the rated categories were massaged (Getting Started and Use Of Computer were replaced by Presentation).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/12/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 01:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/1/12/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News With the news that Ultimate had morphed into Rare and committed exclusively to consoles - due to hit the UK in the coming months - and the arrival of powerful 16bit machines, Graeme Kidd tried allay the fears of readers about the future of the Speccy. A swath of top quality games had come out for the Spectrum in the last few months of 1986 and Graeme reckoned all those talented programmers weren&amp;rsquo;t going to suddenly jump ship to the new platforms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/15/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 22:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/12/15/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News A Crash contingent went down to London for the 20th ZX Microfair. While the event was usually held in the &amp;ldquo;cavernous&amp;rdquo; Royal Horticultural Hall, a booking mixup meant this one had to move to &amp;ldquo;several rooms and various floors&amp;rdquo; at Central Hall in Westminster. There were very few new products to talk about, the only ones receiving a mention being &amp;ldquo;The Professional Adventure Writing System&amp;rdquo;, a new disk interface from Rockfort called &amp;ldquo;The Disciple&amp;rdquo; and Romantic Robot&amp;rsquo;s video digitiser.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News The Crash staff, along with all the other Newsfield folk, went down to London for the launch party of their new magazine, LM. The venue was the Camden Palace and plenty of gaming bigwigs were in attendance. Sadly the magazine failed to gain much traction, folding after only a handful of issues.&#xA;The release of Amstrad&amp;rsquo;s Spectrum +2 had many scratching their heads. Despite the official release having taken place in September, people were unable to find any in shops.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 01:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News Celebrations at Crash towers as the latest circulation figures showed they had sold 101,483 copies a month on average between January and June. That number placed Crash ahead of all other computer mags.&#xA;This issue was the first to feature a cover drawn by someone other than Oliver Frey - Ian Craig was the illustrator responsible. It seemed that with the increasing array of magazines published by Newsfield, Frey had too much on his plate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/29/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 01:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/9/29/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News The Personal Computer World Show was about to happen and publishers were busy announcing/teasing their upcoming games. Full details of what was on display would be in next month&amp;rsquo;s issue, but there was a boatload of previews to do.&#xA;Not one but two winners had been chosen for the Genesis competition Crash launched a few months earlier. The first was a shoot em up called &amp;ldquo;Kat Trap&amp;rdquo; by John Eggleton that would hopefully be out by Christmas, while the second - &amp;ldquo;The Sewer&amp;rdquo; by Martin Lee - was planned for Spring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-crash-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 05:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/6/30/this-month-in-crash-88/</guid>
      <description>News On the back of the news that the price of the Spectrum 128K had dropped following the acquisition by Amstrad, rumours started to circulate that a 256K &amp;ldquo;games machine&amp;rdquo; was in the pipeline. According to the rumours the machine would be Spectrum based but would use credit card sized &amp;ldquo;cartridges&amp;rdquo;. Reactions were mixed - while this would drastically reduce piracy, software houses feared Amstrad having control over what games would be released.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/this-month-in-crash-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 03:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/5/19/this-month-in-crash-86/</guid>
      <description>News Huge news arrived just hours before this issue went to press - Amstrad had bought Sinclair for meagre £5 million. What would this mean for Sinclair products? The QL and microdrive would be likely casualties, but it sounded like Amstrad had promising plans for the Spectrum. Overall it was taken as a positive happening, though the alternative would&amp;rsquo;ve been receivership for Sinclair. Sir Clive himself was to return to research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/21/this-month-in-crash-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 22:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/21/this-month-in-crash-85/</guid>
      <description>Compared to the previous few months, there seemed like a relative dearth of good games released for the Spectrum. Crash pondered whether this had anything to do with the recent release of the Spectrum 128K. Game compilations (often tied to a charity) were coming out at a ridiculous rate - would this result in the cost of games for the consumer (typically kids) going down? or will the revenue developers see take a big hit as people choose cheap compilations over &amp;ldquo;single&amp;rdquo; release games?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
