<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>April on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/april/</link>
    <description>Recent content in April on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:57:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/april/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/4/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/4/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>News Contrary to last month’s news, while ex-The One editor David Upchurch had been assigned to a new mag, it was to EMAP’s latest launch, PC Games, and not a reboot of Sinclair User&amp;hellip; which made a little more sense.
Ocean struck a deal with Virgin to release twelve of its games on Hit Squad, their budget label. The lineup included “Cannon Fodder”, “Dune”, “Dune 2”, “Jimmy White’s Whirlwind Snooker”, “Archer Maclean’s Pool”, “Realms”, “Legend of Kyrandia”, “Supremacy”, “KGB”, “Reach for the Skies”, “Shuttle” and “Lure of the Temptress”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/4/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/4/24/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News I&amp;rsquo;m guessing this was an April Fools joke, but the lead news story concerned PC game &amp;ldquo;X-Wing&amp;rdquo; appearing &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; the Amiga&amp;hellip; as in, it was a photo of an &amp;ldquo;X-Wing&amp;rdquo; box sitting on an Amiga&amp;hellip;
Mindscape revealed that their upcoming Gameboy platformer &amp;ldquo;Alfred Chicken&amp;rdquo; would be getting an Amiga release.
Ocean reckoned that the somewhat crowded car racer genre was in need of something with a bit more realism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;92</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/25/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/4/25/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</guid>
      <description>News It seemed this would be the final issue for the whole editorial crew as they were being replaced by the folk from &amp;ldquo;ex-sister magazine ACE&amp;rdquo;. Such a drastic move must&amp;rsquo;ve been a bitter pill to swallow, but it did mean the return of Gary Whitta.
TV companies had begun to take an interest in video games, with Channel 4&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Gamesmaster&amp;rdquo; clocking in at around 3 million viewers during its first season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #4 April/May 1989</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</guid>
      <description>This issue came hot on the heels of British Telecom&amp;rsquo;s decision to bail out of the games industry. They were looking to sell off the Rainbird, Firebird and Silverbird labels as one lot, while winding Telecomsoft down. The official reason given was that games were no longer in line with the goals of BT, and the asking price was rumoured to be around £5 million. The editorial questioned the motives, highlighting a series of recent misteps resulting in significant financial losses, which included the purchase of Beyond Software (closed down soon after due to poor performance), and the US based Firebird Licensees Inc which lasted less than a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 07:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News A couple of new arrivals at Zzap! this month, with Steve Jarratt swapping industrial chemistry for games journalism and Philipa Irving who, er, swapped Crash for its Newsfield sibling.
Ariolasoft’s Starlight label had three games on the way. &amp;ldquo;Dogfight 2187&amp;rdquo; promised 3D wireframe shoot ‘em up action with a vertically split screen giving two views of the action. The other two games were &amp;ldquo;Deathscape&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Greyfell”. Meanwhile Tony Crowther had teamed up with Keith Blake and Ross Goodley to develop ”Challenge of the Gobots” based on the popular kids cartoon, which would be published by Ariolasoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 01:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News In his editorial, Roger Kean pondered whether the games industry &amp;ldquo;coming of age&amp;rdquo; after 5-ish years with the conglomeration of software houses and the emergence of a small number of dominating companies was a good thing. On the one hand it did mean developers were able to focus more on creating games rather than managing the marketing and distribution, but on the other the desire to get as many games on the shelves as possible was putting a real strain on quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 23:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News May 28th would see Video Charity Day take place as part of the &amp;ldquo;massive&amp;rdquo; &amp;lsquo;88 Telethon charity drive. Video rental customers would be &amp;ldquo;encouraged&amp;rdquo; to donate while in video stores and there would be competitions and raffles.
C&amp;amp;VG found the fact that the player character in Martech&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Vixen&amp;rdquo; was female &amp;ldquo;doubly refreshing&amp;rdquo;. The double part may have been a reference to the game&amp;rsquo;s cover/advertisements which featured a photo of a Page 3 girl Corinne Russell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/15/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 06:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/15/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News Gordon Leslie Houghton was the newest person to join the Zzap!64 writing team.
Hard to know whether Zzap! fell for an April fools, or were behind it themselves, but they carried a news story about a Norwegian firm creating a C64 add-on that would turn the humble 64 into an Amiga. The &amp;ldquo;Amulator&amp;rdquo; was being made by Blue Tec and would cost around £280.
Features Martin Walker had just finished off &amp;ldquo;Hunter&amp;rsquo;s Moon&amp;rdquo; and had embarked on a new dev diary for his next (yet to be decided) game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/12/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 05:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/4/12/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News This month C&amp;amp;VG became the biggest selling games mag in the UK, shifting 106,571 copies monthly.
The Edge picked up the license for &amp;ldquo;Garfield&amp;rdquo;.
Superior Software were launching a big spring recruitment drive, and had written a handbook for budding games programmers titled &amp;ldquo;Success in Software&amp;rdquo;.
Beano-esque comic &amp;ldquo;Oink!&amp;rdquo; was to be turned into a game by CRL.
&amp;ldquo;Dan Dare&amp;rdquo; creator, Andy Wilson, was finishing up &amp;ldquo;Laurel and Hardy&amp;rdquo; which featured a &amp;ldquo;new programming technique called Cinevision&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News Roger Kean, who was the original editor of Crash, returned to resume his role after moving to Zzap64 a couple of years earlier (which had earned him the title of &amp;ldquo;traitor&amp;rdquo; from loyal Spectrum fans). Graeme Kidd was now to be editor of the ill fated LM magazine.
Spring had arrived and there were a slew of announcements by software houses of upcoming games. Some of the notable ones included:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 23:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News The UK release of &amp;ldquo;Questprobe 3&amp;rdquo; (aka &amp;ldquo;The Fantastic Four&amp;rdquo;) had suffered more delays. There had been hopes it&amp;rsquo;d be out for Christmas, but it looks like licensing issues had pushed it back.
Rhino announced &amp;ldquo;Ark Pandora&amp;rdquo; for the C64.
PSS had released two new wargames: &amp;ldquo;Falklands 82&amp;rdquo; for the Spectrum and &amp;ldquo;Theatre of Europe&amp;rdquo; for the Amstrad.
Global Software announced a game based on &amp;ldquo;the Worst Vegetable Movie of All Time&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The Attack of the Killer Tomatoes&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The Games Machine &#39;88</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 19:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/26/this-month-in-the-games-machine-88/</guid>
      <description>News Rare had been inundated with calls from developers wanting in on the Nintendo market and the Z80 arcade board that they (Rare) were working on. This all follows on from a pretty amazing interview with Rare in the previous issue of TGM - amazing because it was the first (and perhaps only?) proper interview conducted with the Stamper brothers. Everyone had been wondering what happened to Ultimate Play The Game (arguably the finest developer of the 8bit years), and now we all knew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Crash &#39;86</title>
      <link>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/21/this-month-in-crash-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 22:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2013/4/21/this-month-in-crash-85/</guid>
      <description>Compared to the previous few months, there seemed like a relative dearth of good games released for the Spectrum. Crash pondered whether this had anything to do with the recent release of the Spectrum 128K. Game compilations (often tied to a charity) were coming out at a ridiculous rate - would this result in the cost of games for the consumer (typically kids) going down? or will the revenue developers see take a big hit as people choose cheap compilations over &amp;ldquo;single&amp;rdquo; release games?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
