<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Level 9 on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/level-9/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Level 9 on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/level-9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #8 December &#39;88/January &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 07:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/6/19/confidential-magazine-8-december-88january-89/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://archive.org/embed/confidential8&#34;&#xA;width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&#xA;mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we bid goodbye to the 80s, the Editor pondered what lay ahead in the coming&#xA;decade. After the world had lived in fear of nuclear annihalation for so many&#xA;years, the arrival of the likes of Gorbachev meant we could now focus on the&#xA;&amp;ldquo;prospect of irreversible doom&amp;rdquo; thanks to global warming. Technology would, of&#xA;course, play a significant role in what was to come: &amp;ldquo;Our ability to&#xA;manipulate information and communicate the results to the whole World within&#xA;seconds, could lead us into chaos.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #6 August/September 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 06:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/1/2/confidential-magazine-6-augustseptember-1989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe&#xA;src=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/confidential6?ui=embed&#34; width=&#34;480&#34;&#xA;height=&#34;430&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&#xA;mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s mag included:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A rather depressing Editorial which opened with &amp;ldquo;Boom-time for the computer games world is over, at least for the next few years.&amp;rdquo; The Japanese consoles were wiping the floor with computers - the 8bits were barely hanging on, the ST not far behind them. There looked to be some life left in the Amiga, but it was the IBM PC that stood the best chance of lasting. Perhaps the grimmest thing about this was the high entry bar for console development - what would happen to all the small UK devs?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In other not so happy news, the once great Infocom had been assimilated into Mediagenic (prev Activision). The office was moved to the West Coast, but it seemed no designers or developers relocated with it. Steve Meretzky and Dave Lebling were among the most recent to quit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An interview Level 9&amp;rsquo;s Pete Austin about their upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lemonamiga.com/games/details.php?id=931&#34;&gt;Scapeghost&lt;/a&gt;. He was rather coy about their plans beyond this one, but now that we have the benefit of hindsight and know that it in fact would be their last, it did seem like they saw the writing on the wall.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A look at &amp;ldquo;Ranch Wars&amp;rdquo; which was a Play By Mail game except it wasn&amp;rsquo;t - it was an &amp;ldquo;on-going graphic adventure that comes through the post&amp;rdquo; and was a &amp;ldquo;strange amalgam of interactive fiction, graphical war-gaming and strategy all mixed together&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Encyclopedia Frobbozzica - an indepth reference of all things Zork.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An interview with Joe Dever, author of the Lone Wolf books.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A look at Role Playing Play By Mail game &amp;ldquo;Calvana&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Was the icon driven Infogrames &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lemonamiga.com/games/details.php?id=1766&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kult&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; the future of adventure games?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sandra Sharkey presented some general musings on writing adventures.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Confidential went on a bit of LARPing with &amp;ldquo;Mythlore&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A short story by Ian Urquhart.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidential Magazine #4 April/May 1989</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/9/16/confidential-magazine-4-aprilmay-1989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe&#xA;src=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/confidential4?ui=embed&#34; width=&#34;480&#34;&#xA;height=&#34;430&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&#xA;mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This issue came hot on the heels of British Telecom&amp;rsquo;s decision to bail out of&#xA;the games industry. They were looking to sell off the Rainbird, Firebird and&#xA;Silverbird labels as one lot, while winding Telecomsoft down. The official&#xA;reason given was that games were no longer in line with the goals of BT, and&#xA;the asking price was rumoured to be around £5 million. The editorial&#xA;questioned the motives, highlighting a series of recent misteps resulting in&#xA;significant financial losses, which included the purchase of Beyond Software&#xA;(closed down soon after due to poor performance), and the US based Firebird&#xA;Licensees Inc which lasted less than a year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
