<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>March on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/march/</link>
    <description>Recent content in March on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 06:43:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ziggurat.co.nz/tags/march/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;95</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 06:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2021/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-95/</guid>
      <description>News Despite some recent colossal flops at the box office (&amp;ldquo;Mario Brothers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Double Dragon&amp;rdquo;) it seemed the success of &amp;ldquo;Street Fighter&amp;rdquo; was enough for Hollywood to take another stab it with &amp;ldquo;Mortal Kombat&amp;rdquo;. The only &amp;ldquo;big names&amp;rdquo; attached to it were Christopher Lambert and Talisa Soto (a Bond girl in &amp;ldquo;Licence to Kill&amp;rdquo;). Unknown Paul Anderson was to direct. Elsewhere there were rumours of movies based on &amp;ldquo;Doom&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Myst&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;94</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 05:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2020/3/30/this-month-in-the-one-94/</guid>
      <description>theone199403
News This was to be David Upchurch&amp;rsquo;s last issue as Editor as off to head up EMAP&amp;rsquo;s relaunch of&amp;hellip; Sinclair User. Apparently the Speccy had been seeing a resurgence, though I find that a little hard to believe. At any rate, Simon Byron was to take over the helm.
Team 17 were embracing the CD32 starting with &amp;ldquo;Ultimate Body Blows&amp;rdquo;, a revamped version of their beat&amp;rsquo;em up featuring new AGA backdrops, digitised speech and a digital CD soundtrack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One &#39;93</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/3/18/this-month-in-the-one-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 07:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2019/3/18/this-month-in-the-one-93/</guid>
      <description>News Comic artist Dave Gibbons (of &amp;ldquo;Watchmen&amp;rdquo; fame) had been collaborating with Charles Cecil and Revolution Software on the cyberpunk point-and-click adventure &amp;ldquo;Beneath a Steel Sky&amp;rdquo;. It transpired that his involvement came about after he contacted The One to complain they&amp;rsquo;d forgotten to credit him for &amp;ldquo;Watchmen&amp;rdquo;. The mag decided to lend him an Amiga and a copy of &amp;ldquo;Deluxe Paint&amp;rdquo; for a followup article, which sparked his interest in computer art and lead to an introduction to Cecil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... The One for Amiga &#39;92</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/3/31/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 21:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2018/3/31/this-month-in-the-one-for-amiga-92/</guid>
      <description>This month in&amp;hellip; The One for Amiga &amp;lsquo;92 News A new TV show catering for gamers had recently debuted and The One wanted to hear from readers about what they thought of it. Did Gamesmaster provide what gaming fans were looking for?
Electronic Arts were to publish &amp;ldquo;Castles&amp;rdquo;, a &amp;ldquo;SimCity&amp;rdquo; meets RPG game from Interplay.
A new book from Sigma sought to help players struggling to get to grips with adventure games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... ZZap!64 &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 07:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/21/this-month-in-zzap64-87/</guid>
      <description>News Gary Penn wrote a long editorial on a matter that had been on a lot of people’s minds: had quality and innovation taken a dive as software houses relied more and more on coin-op, TV and film licenses? The market seemed to be full of these unimaginative and often shoddy tie ins which, aside from the attached IP, only had good presentation going for them. Developers were feeling the pinch as well: publishers would “guarantee 100,000” copies sold, giving them an excuse to lower royalties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/20/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 08:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2017/3/20/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Michael Jackson’s “Moonwalker” movie had only just come out and US Gold had already snaffled the game license.
Titus announced their futuristic deadly sport game &amp;ldquo;Titan”.
The Vocalizer 1000 was a music gadget where the user would hum/whistle/sing a tune at it and it would detect the varying pitches and allow playback of the tune using a selection of 28 instruments.
Gary Liddon was teaming up with renowned game artist Paul Docherty to develop &amp;ldquo;Tyger Tyger&amp;rdquo; for Mastertronic’s Ricochet label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in Zzap!64 &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 06:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-zzap64-86/</guid>
      <description>News Commodore announced they were closing their Corby factory and ceasing the manufacture of the 64 in Britain. Was this a sign of bigger troubles? The price of the C64 remained higher than that of competitors, and rather than address this, Commodore had introduced the C16 - but what did this actually solve?
English Software were finally about to release &amp;ldquo;Elektra Glide&amp;rdquo; on the C64 - some months after the original Atari version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 06:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The big buzz this month was the arrival of &amp;ldquo;Xenon&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST which heralded the first true coin-op quality game on home computers.
Electronic Arts were working on a graphic adventure for the Amiga called &amp;ldquo;Return to Atlantis&amp;rdquo;.
Infocom were trying something a bit different with their Infocomix line of interactive comics. Rather than a typical adventure game, each issue would allow the reader to choose their path through the storyline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... Zzap!64 &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 06:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/31/this-month-in-zzap64-88/</guid>
      <description>News A fresh faced 18yr old Paul Glancey joined the Zzap!64 team.
Features Julian Rignall and Steve Jarratt popped along to the 44th Amusement Trade Exhibition International to check out the latest arcade machines.
Sci-fi films and TV had taken a stab at many predictions of the future of computers over the previous 35 years, and Zzap!64 cast a critical eye over them.
Zzap!64 visited the offices of Digital Pictures to drool over their high power CG machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 05:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2015/3/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Indoor Sports&amp;rdquo; by Mindscape was to feature a set of &amp;ldquo;unusual&amp;rdquo; sports, such as air hockey.
Creative Sparks announced not one but four new budget titles: &amp;ldquo;Little Alien&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Smudge and the Moonees&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Shuffle&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Cyber I&amp;rdquo;. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like any of these were released.
Melbourne House&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Murder at Arkham Hall&amp;rdquo; was to be a detective style adventure with the player taking on the role of a reporter investigating a murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... TGM &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/22/this-month-in-tgm-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 23:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/22/this-month-in-tgm-89/</guid>
      <description>News Word leaked out that Epyx was working on a new console. David Morse (CEO of Epyx, and one of the original Amiga hardware designers) was involved on what was rumoured to be a new handheld. This, of course, would become the Atari Lynx.
Megadrives and NES consoles started appearing in arcades in the UK where players could purchase a set amount of play time with a range of games available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in Crash &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/20/this-month-in-crash-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 06:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/20/this-month-in-crash-87/</guid>
      <description>News With yet more consolidation of software houses, Graeme Kidd painted a rather bleak outlook for innovative and original games. Fewer, bigger companies spending more and more on licenses and marketing meant there was little room for fresh ideas. The only hope, in his eyes, was a system much like book publishing where &amp;ldquo;authors tout their wares around the large publishers.&amp;rdquo;
More tweaks were made to Crash&amp;rsquo;s review process. The quality of software had improved substantially since the early days and it was time for Crash to take a step back and judge games on a scale where 50% meant an average game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 06:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ziggurat.co.nz/news/2014/3/18/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News The biggest news by far this month was that US Gold had merged with Ultimate Play The Game, and that US Gold would now handle all international manufacturing, promotion, marketing and sales of Ultimate games. Ultimate said that they were going to concentrate on making games and planned to release six new titles during 1986. What wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear was just how involved the Stamper brothers were to be, but it would turn out that they already had their eyes on the new Japanese consoles and the formation of a certain company called Rare.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
