<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C&amp;VG on Ziggurat</title>
    <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/cvg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C&amp;VG on Ziggurat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Ziggurat Development Ltd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 07:36:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikekeith.github.io/tags/cvg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;90</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/2/8/this-month-in-cvg-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 07:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2018/2/8/this-month-in-cvg-90/</guid>
      <description>News Code Masters unveiled their fancy new CD compilations for the Spectrum and C64. The package included a computer interface to connect your regular CD player and the CD-ROM containing 30 Code Masters games. The Spectrum version was able to load games in under a minute, while the C64 utilised the stereo audio signal to encode a timing track enabling even quicker load times. C&amp;amp;VG marvelled at the possibilities: &amp;ldquo;Imagine a game with minutes of digitised speech or amazing digitised graphics!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/12/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 07:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/12/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Hot off the presses from Japan was news of the PC Engine Super Grafx which looked to build on the already impressive original. New custom chips meant it could chuck around 128 sprites (up from 64) and the cartridges saw a decent boost in size. Perhaps the most intriguing aspect was the Power Console add on which the console slotted into and featured a full on steering yoke, a gear stick/throttle, LCD clock/timer, LED radar display, numeric keypad and a bunch of buttons and knobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/11/16/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 07:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/11/16/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News A new computer was about to be unleashed on Europe which boasted specs that certainly beat the 8bits, but also - apparently - rivaled the Amiga and ST. While that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem terribly exciting, it did have one interesting feature: the ability to run most Speccy games. The SAM Coupe was due to launch in the UK on November 20th.
With Christmas around the corner, Hewson were to release a couple of compilations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/10/15/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 08:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/10/15/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Konix Here At Last&amp;rdquo; proclaimed the headline leading off this issue. The much hyped Konix Multisystem was going to be available to buy this month at stores across the UK for around 200 quid. Not all of the eagerly anticipated peripherals would be on sale to start with - the hydraulic chair was &amp;ldquo;on the horizon&amp;rdquo; and expected to cost another 200 quid. Of course, sadly, none of this was to be&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/9/5/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 07:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/9/5/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Two years after it launched in the US, Atari were bringing the 7800 ProSystem to the UK. On paper the specs weren&amp;rsquo;t up to much when compared to Nintendo and Sega&amp;rsquo;s offerings, but at £69.95 it looked decent value for money. Stateside the 7800 was the number 2 selling console ahead of the Master System.
Spectravideo&amp;rsquo;s popular range of Quickshot joysticks (the Quickshot II Turbo was my personal fave back in the day) was being joined by their new Wizmaster gamepad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 08:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Atari unveiled their impressive handheld, the Lynx. Julian Rignall got to check it out and was gobsmacked: &amp;ldquo;Erm&amp;hellip; hmmm&amp;hellip; What can I say about the most exciting thing to happen to the games industry since the invention of the home console?&amp;rdquo;
Sinclair (aka Amstrad) were to launch a new bundle. The &amp;ldquo;Action Pack&amp;rdquo; would consist of a Spectrum +2 (£149) or +3 (£199), a Magnum light gun and 6 games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/7/4/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 08:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/7/4/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News The industry was abuzz with talk of Nintendo’s Game Boy. The handheld had seen a very successful launch in Japan with over 500,000 units being sold (300,000 of which were on the first day), and now the question was when would it reach the UK. Nintendo were unable to give any dates, but confirmed they had plans…
The FIST telephone game was getting a sequel (I have no idea what this was).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 08:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/6/19/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw C&amp;amp;VG getting a revamp based on reader feedback. Coin ops and consoles would get more pages, the adventure section got a make over, there was more space dedicated to previews and overall there would be a lot more colour. The announcement of these changes referenced the fact that some features were dropped, but they didn’t actually specify which. Somewhat worryingly, there were no adventure game reviews - just some tips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/4/24/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/4/24/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>[Oh dear, I got confused and thought this was the April issue.. turns out my April issue appears to be missing - no doubt the fault of one of my High School friends back in the day]
News Rignall and Glancey took on Domark’s Mark Strachan and Andy Blazdell in three rounds of Tengen’s &amp;ldquo;Vindicators&amp;rdquo; arcade machine. The C&amp;amp;VG lads won two out of three and claimed the Tengen Trophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/3/20/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 08:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/3/20/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News Michael Jackson’s “Moonwalker” movie had only just come out and US Gold had already snaffled the game license.
Titus announced their futuristic deadly sport game &amp;ldquo;Titan”.
The Vocalizer 1000 was a music gadget where the user would hum/whistle/sing a tune at it and it would detect the varying pitches and allow playback of the tune using a selection of 28 instruments.
Gary Liddon was teaming up with renowned game artist Paul Docherty to develop &amp;ldquo;Tyger Tyger&amp;rdquo; for Mastertronic’s Ricochet label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/2/23/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 08:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/2/23/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Death Stalks the Night&amp;rdquo; was an upcoming arcade adventure from Ubi Soft where the player assumed the role as Count Dracula to take on “the usual Van Helsings”.
New software house EAS announced a space trading game called &amp;ldquo;STAG&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST.
Mr Chip’s &amp;ldquo;Wrangler&amp;rdquo;would see the player take control over Clint Eastwood (yes, apparently) and his ‘droid in what looked like a puzzle game.
Budget label Alternative were moving into the 16bits with Don Priestly’s &amp;ldquo;Mad Flunky”, a follow-up to his Spectrum game &amp;ldquo;Flunky”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;89</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/1/11/this-month-in-cvg-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 08:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2017/1/11/this-month-in-cvg-89/</guid>
      <description>News C&amp;amp;VG were giving away a Body Rap toy which would be strapped to your body and emit audio (bass, drum, snare, cymbal etc) when hit. They described it as a “neat little gizmo” but I can’t imagine it being anything other than dreadful.
The Amiga, ST and Amstrad versions of Titus’ car racing game &amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars II&amp;rdquo; were on the shelves, with the C64 due this month.
German software house Rainbow Arts were to release &amp;ldquo;Spherical”, a Gauntlet-style game, and &amp;ldquo;The Game&amp;rdquo; which promised to be a “space battle spectacular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/15/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 07:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/12/15/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News There were big changes at the mag, with Tony Takoushi &amp;ldquo;getting the boot&amp;rdquo; and replaced by Julian Rignall. This issue hit 114 pages.
Mandarin Software were developing &amp;ldquo;Grand Prix Circuit&amp;rdquo;, an F1 racing sim to be published by Accolade.
Elite&amp;rsquo;s lineup for Christmas included &amp;ldquo;Space Harrier 2&amp;rdquo; for the 16bits (seems that Grandslam actually had the rights for that, weird) , &amp;ldquo;Mike Read’s Pop Quiz&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Storm Warrior&amp;rdquo;. Their arcade truck racer &amp;ldquo;Supertrux&amp;rdquo; was narrowly going to miss the holiday season and was due early January.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/11/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 08:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/11/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News It was Superman vs Batman as to who would have the better game. Tynesoft delivering the former, while Ocean took on the latter. Early indications were that Batman had the edge.
Loricel&amp;rsquo;s next attempt to crack the UK would come in the form of Porsche racing game &amp;ldquo;944 Turbo Cup&amp;rdquo;. Driver Rene Metge (&amp;ldquo;who?&amp;rdquo; asked C&amp;amp;VG) provided the endorsement and the software house hoped to include a model car in the box, but apparently British retailers weren&amp;rsquo;t so keen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 07:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News Grand Slam were bringing the &amp;ldquo;Pacmania&amp;rdquo; coin-op to home computers (the Amiga, ST and Spectrum versions would be first, with C64 and Amstrad to follow next month). The software house was also working on a computer game based on board game &amp;ldquo;sensation&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Espionage&amp;rdquo;.
Software Horizons was new on the scene and would be publishing three 16bit games within the next month or so: &amp;ldquo;Veteran&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Luxor&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mafdet&amp;rdquo;.
Chris Crawford was updating his well received &amp;ldquo;Balance of Power&amp;rdquo; with some &amp;ldquo;new trouble zones of strategic importance&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/9/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 07:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/9/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News For the first time, major games were being released on the 16bits before the 8bits. C&amp;amp;VG reassured its readers that almost all the games would make their way to the C64/Spectrum/Amstrad, and that the magazine would continue to cover those machines.
The Bitmap Brothers were following up their well received 16bit shoot&amp;rsquo;em up &amp;ldquo;Xenon&amp;rdquo; with a new futuristic sports game, &amp;ldquo;Speedball&amp;rdquo;.
Mirrorsoft had created a new label, Imageworks, which would be their flagship for most of its new games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/8/18/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 09:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/8/18/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw ex-Zzap!64 editor Julian Rignall and ex-Crash editor Steve Jarret join the C&amp;amp;VG writing staff.
With the Seoul olympic games about to start, Ocean were to release &amp;ldquo;Daley Thompson&amp;rsquo;s Olympic Challenge&amp;rdquo;. Official olympic sponsor Adidas were also sponsoring the game.
The first screenshot of Realtime Games&amp;rsquo; impressive 16bit &amp;ldquo;Carrier Command&amp;rdquo; Spectrum port appeared. The game was also to appear on the Amstrad and C64.
French software house Lankhor were working on a car racing game called &amp;ldquo;Vroom&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/7/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/7/11/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The 1988 Euros were about to start and Grandslam were putting the finishing touches on &amp;ldquo;Peter Beardsley’s International Football&amp;rdquo;.
Titus was following up their &amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;Fire and Forget&amp;rdquo;, a vehicular combat game featuring cars decked out with an array of weapons.
Crocodile Dundee was heading back to the cinemas, but this time his antics would take place in New York.
German developer house Logotron was to release a heavily Defender inspired shooter, &amp;ldquo;Stay Ray&amp;rdquo;, for the Amiga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/6/21/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 08:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/6/21/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The issue came with a &amp;ldquo;Barbarian II&amp;rdquo; poster.
&amp;ldquo;Pandora&amp;rdquo; was a new sci-fi game from Firebird where character interaction was as important as blasting.
London&amp;rsquo;s The Museum of Mankind opened a new exhibit that made use of video discs and computers to create a game where visitors would learn what life in the Arctic was like.
The first game to hit the shelves from new publisher Electra was to be &amp;ldquo;Better Dead than Alien&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/5/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 08:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/5/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News Stephen Crow&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Starquake&amp;rdquo; was heading to the ST and Amstrad PC thanks to Mandarin Software.
Hewson were to re-release several classic titles by Gargoyle Games. &amp;ldquo;Dun Darach&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Marsport&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Tir Na Nog&amp;rdquo; would available for a mere £1.99.
C&amp;amp;VG apologised for incorrectly stating the price of &amp;ldquo;IO&amp;rdquo; for the C64 last month.
&amp;ldquo;Stir Crazy&amp;rdquo; from Infogrames starred a &amp;ldquo;crazy criminal character&amp;rdquo; attempting to escape prison.
&amp;ldquo;Batman: The Killing Joke&amp;rdquo; by Alan Moore and Brian Bolland was proving quite a hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 23:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/4/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News May 28th would see Video Charity Day take place as part of the &amp;ldquo;massive&amp;rdquo; &amp;lsquo;88 Telethon charity drive. Video rental customers would be &amp;ldquo;encouraged&amp;rdquo; to donate while in video stores and there would be competitions and raffles.
C&amp;amp;VG found the fact that the player character in Martech&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Vixen&amp;rdquo; was female &amp;ldquo;doubly refreshing&amp;rdquo;. The double part may have been a reference to the game&amp;rsquo;s cover/advertisements which featured a photo of a Page 3 girl Corinne Russell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 06:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/3/30/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News The big buzz this month was the arrival of &amp;ldquo;Xenon&amp;rdquo; for the Amiga and ST which heralded the first true coin-op quality game on home computers.
Electronic Arts were working on a graphic adventure for the Amiga called &amp;ldquo;Return to Atlantis&amp;rdquo;.
Infocom were trying something a bit different with their Infocomix line of interactive comics. Rather than a typical adventure game, each issue would allow the reader to choose their path through the storyline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/2/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 23:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/2/28/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw Eugene Lacey take over as editor. Lacey came from editing Commodore User, and had been a C&amp;amp;VG staff writer sometime earlier.
Go!&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bedlam&amp;rdquo; promised arcade action featuring up to 18 aliens at any one time.
Sega&amp;rsquo;s Master System recently launched in the UK and now a slew of titles were heading its way. These included: &amp;ldquo;Kung-Kid&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Fantasy Zone II&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;After Burner&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Global Defense&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Zaxxon 3D&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alien Syndrome&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rescue &amp;amp; Mission&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Zillion II: The Tri Formation&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Alex Kidd: The Lost Stars&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Boys Monster Land&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Cube Zone&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Maze Hunter 3D&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;88</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/1/10/this-month-in-cvg-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 05:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2016/1/10/this-month-in-cvg-88/</guid>
      <description>News This issue came with an audio cassette featuring music from 720º and Out Run.
Electric Dreams&amp;rsquo; Spectrum port of &amp;ldquo;Super Hang-On&amp;rdquo; narrowly missed the review window for the month, but a tasty screenshot of it was included instead. C&amp;amp;VG assured readers it was &amp;ldquo;simply brilliant&amp;rdquo;.
The Edge was bringing comic cat &amp;ldquo;Garfield&amp;rdquo; to home computers.
&amp;ldquo;Crazy Cars&amp;rdquo; was a rather promising looking 16bit racing game from Titus.
&amp;ldquo;Robocop&amp;rdquo; had taken US movie goers by storm and was due to hit UK screens early in the New Year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/12/29/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 05:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/12/29/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Rainbird&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Universal Military Simulator&amp;rdquo; for the ST promised wargaming fans the ability to re-enact a vast array of different battles, including ones between armies from different time periods.
&amp;ldquo;Stratton&amp;rdquo; from CRL would see the player attempt to shutdown the automated defence units of a space station which had suffered a terrorist attack and had turned on its inhabitants. (unable to find evidence of this being released)
Bike racing game &amp;ldquo;500 Grand Prix&amp;rdquo;, published by French house Loricels, was heading to the ST, IBM and C64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/11/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 07:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/11/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Microprose&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;F-15 Strike Eagle&amp;rdquo; was about to land on the ST. The ST would also get a port of Mirrorsoft&amp;rsquo;s flightsim featuring a somewhat older aircraft, &amp;ldquo;Spitfire 40&amp;rdquo;.
Viz were working on &amp;ldquo;Werewolves of London&amp;rdquo;.
For the first time since being bought out by Mastertronic, Melbourne House announced its upcoming titles: &amp;ldquo;Roadwars&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rockford&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pulse Warrior&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Street Hassle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Metropolis&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kelly X&amp;rdquo; (I was unable to find any sign that the latter two were released, at least not under those names).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/10/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 22:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/10/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Jim Synoski and Arnold Hendrick, designers of Microprose&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Project: Stealth Fighter&amp;rdquo;, were promoting the game ahead of its launch. While they admitted nothing official was known about the fighter, they felt that they had &amp;ldquo;a fair idea of what the capabilities of the plane must be&amp;rdquo;.
Incentive&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo; was shaping up well on the Speccy.
Electric Dreams had the rights to &amp;ldquo;Knightmare&amp;rdquo; - the game of the TV series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/9/13/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 06:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/9/13/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Digital Integration&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bobsleigh&amp;rdquo; was a departure from their usual flight sims and would centre around the winter event.
Incentive teased their impressive new Freescape engine with a couple of screenshots of the upcoming &amp;ldquo;Driller&amp;rdquo;.
English Software were working on a Rambo-esque game: &amp;ldquo;Captain Courageous&amp;rdquo;.
Atari dropped the price of the 520STFM to £299.99. They were also planning to re-launch the 130XE and position it as &amp;ldquo;the ultimate teaching computer&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/8/25/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 08:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/8/25/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Catch 23&amp;rdquo; was a new 3D vector arcade adventure from Martech.
Epyx were continuing their &amp;ldquo;Games&amp;rdquo; series, this time focussing on events such as BMXing, skateboarding, surfing and flying disks (frisbees) in &amp;ldquo;California Games&amp;rdquo;.
Microprose were to release a new flight sim, &amp;ldquo;Project: Stealth Fighter&amp;rdquo; based on the top secret American stealth plane, and a more arcade-y combat game, &amp;ldquo;Airborne Ranger&amp;rdquo;.
Activision &amp;amp; System 3 got the game rights for Arnie&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Predator&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/7/19/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 06:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/7/19/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Dungeons, Amethysts, Alchemists &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Everythin&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; from Atlantis Software promised &amp;ldquo;the occasional rude word and sexual innuendo, novice nuns, entangled lovers and busty barmaids&amp;rdquo;. The cover of the game came with a &amp;ldquo;Not suitable for persons under the age of 16&amp;rdquo; label.
Paul Hardcastle had a big hit with his Vietnam war song &amp;ldquo;19&amp;rdquo; and Cascade were turning it into a game. Rather interestingly, the player would be faced with a choice at the start: fight the war or the draft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 07:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/6/30/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News US Gold had signed a deal to sponsor race driver David Hall&amp;rsquo;s car for the Formula Forward season.
Meanwhile, US Gold released &amp;ldquo;Deeper Dungeons&amp;rdquo; for those &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo; fans wanting more.
The British Open AD&amp;amp;D Championships were held at the Reading University Students Union building. Up to 600 people were expected.
Laser tag guns were the toy of the moment. The two main contenders were &amp;ldquo;Laser Combat&amp;rdquo; from Action GT, and &amp;ldquo;Laser Tag&amp;rdquo; from Mattel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/5/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 04:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/5/24/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Simon Price, who had previously worked on &amp;ldquo;Redhawk&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Kwah!&amp;rdquo;, was developing &amp;ldquo;Wiz&amp;rdquo; for Melbourne House.
Danish software house Kele Line had two new C64 releases this month, &amp;ldquo;Thunder Force&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Unitrax&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;The 4th Dimension&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Vikings&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Pirates of the Ocean&amp;rdquo; were to follow. Seems that only &amp;ldquo;Thunder Force&amp;rdquo; (published by Hewson) and &amp;ldquo;Vikings&amp;rdquo; made it out.
&amp;ldquo;The Mystery of Arkham Manor&amp;rdquo; would see the player take on the role of a journo investigating a - as the title suggests - mysterious murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/4/12/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 05:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/4/12/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News This month C&amp;amp;VG became the biggest selling games mag in the UK, shifting 106,571 copies monthly.
The Edge picked up the license for &amp;ldquo;Garfield&amp;rdquo;.
Superior Software were launching a big spring recruitment drive, and had written a handbook for budding games programmers titled &amp;ldquo;Success in Software&amp;rdquo;.
Beano-esque comic &amp;ldquo;Oink!&amp;rdquo; was to be turned into a game by CRL.
&amp;ldquo;Dan Dare&amp;rdquo; creator, Andy Wilson, was finishing up &amp;ldquo;Laurel and Hardy&amp;rdquo; which featured a &amp;ldquo;new programming technique called Cinevision&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/3/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 05:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/3/23/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;Indoor Sports&amp;rdquo; by Mindscape was to feature a set of &amp;ldquo;unusual&amp;rdquo; sports, such as air hockey.
Creative Sparks announced not one but four new budget titles: &amp;ldquo;Little Alien&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Smudge and the Moonees&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Shuffle&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Cyber I&amp;rdquo;. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like any of these were released.
Melbourne House&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Murder at Arkham Hall&amp;rdquo; was to be a detective style adventure with the player taking on the role of a reporter investigating a murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/2/14/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 21:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/2/14/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News The Robot Society of America was offering newly signed up members the chance to win an &amp;ldquo;experimental sound-activated robot&amp;rdquo; kit. Membership was $50 per year.
Bug Byte was to release old Virgin games under its budget label. &amp;ldquo;Strangeloop&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Falcon Patrol II&amp;rdquo; were among the first batch.
Also getting in on the budget action was newcomer Alternative Software with releases such as &amp;ldquo;Howzat&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Henry&amp;rsquo;s Hoard&amp;rdquo;. Not exactly the most thrilling line up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;87</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-cvg-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 20:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2015/1/31/this-month-in-cvg-87/</guid>
      <description>News Ocean was to bring &amp;ldquo;Donkey Kong&amp;rdquo; to the C64, Spectrum and Amstrad.
&amp;ldquo;Blood n&amp;rsquo; Guts&amp;rdquo; was heading to the C64 and was described by publisher American Action as &amp;ldquo;an ancient barbarian decathlon with all the violence and brutality you&amp;rsquo;ve ever dreamed about in a computer game&amp;rdquo;. Oo-kay.
Atari&amp;rsquo;s 7800 was about to hit the shelves retailing for around £70, with games costing £10-15.
Bo Jangeborg was busy finishing &amp;ldquo;Fairlight II&amp;rdquo;, which was to be double the size and feature a greater variety of graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 02:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/12/28/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Probe Software was porting two arcade games, &amp;ldquo;Quartet&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Enduro Racer&amp;rdquo; to home computers for Activision.
&amp;ldquo;Tracker&amp;rdquo; from Rainbird promised tactical battles against an &amp;ldquo;artificially intelligent enemy&amp;rdquo; which would involve strategy and fast 3D arcade sections.
Beyond continued to promote their much hyped &amp;ldquo;Star Trek&amp;rdquo; game, which would never see a release. They also revealed &amp;ldquo;Infodroid&amp;rdquo; - a new game from Denton Designs.
After Ocean&amp;rsquo;s exceptionally disappointing &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo; a few months earlier, Activision owned the US rights to the cartoon and David Crane had been working on an entirely different &amp;ldquo;Transformers&amp;rdquo; game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 23:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/11/30/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News This month saw C&amp;amp;VG turn 5 years old and to celebrate they had a bunch of special features, including a Spectrum listing by Steve Turner&amp;rsquo;s dad.
Microsphere revealed their next game would be &amp;ldquo;Contact Sam Cruise&amp;rdquo;, which was inspired by classic private eye movies. There was also a hint that there might be something for fans of &amp;ldquo;Skool Daze&amp;rdquo; at Christmas.
Arioalasoft got the licenses for two Hanna-Barbera cartoons: &amp;ldquo;The Centurions&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Challenge of the Gobots&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 03:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/10/12/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Ariolasoft spun out two new software houses, 39 Steps to focus on adventure games and Reaktor arcade/action games. First up from 39 Steps would be &amp;ldquo;They Stole a Million&amp;rdquo; while Reaktor&amp;rsquo;s would be &amp;ldquo;Deactivators&amp;rdquo;.
Martial arts games were proving popular and Martech threw their hat in the ring with &amp;ldquo;Uchi-Mata&amp;rdquo;, a &amp;ldquo;more subtle&amp;rdquo; simulation based on Judo.
Beyond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Star Trek&amp;rdquo; was to land in time for Christmas and would feature more than 1000 stars and 256 subplots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 01:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/9/21/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Peter Jones and Trevor Lever (the blokes behind &amp;ldquo;Terrormolinos&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hampstead&amp;rdquo;) were back with a new two part adventure &amp;ldquo;Dodgy Geezers&amp;rdquo;.
US Gold had a strong upcoming lineup with &amp;ldquo;Gauntlet&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Masters of the Universe&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Infiltrator&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Super Cycle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Championship Wrestling&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Movie Monster&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;World Games&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Xevious&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Express Raider&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Break Thru&amp;rdquo;. Phew.
Lucasfilm and Activision picked up the game rights for &amp;ldquo;Labyrinth&amp;rdquo;. The movie had been received well in the US and was due to hit the UK around Christmas</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 03:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/8/17/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s nearly here&amp;rdquo;, declared C&amp;amp;VG about Mike Singleton&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Dark Sceptre&amp;rdquo;. The ambitious strategy/adventure (which was intended to have an optional Play By Mail service to allow players to compete with each other and Mike himself) had been in progress for a while and looked fantastic, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be until February 1988 that C&amp;amp;VG finally got to play it. From the review: &amp;ldquo;Was it worth the wait? We&amp;rsquo;ll pass on that&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (it received 8/10)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/7/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 04:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/7/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Leading this month&amp;rsquo;s news was US Gold&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;World Cup Carnival&amp;rdquo;, the official World Cup &amp;lsquo;86 game. A team of programmers had been working on it for 6 months and US Gold boldly claimed that it would &amp;ldquo;reach new standards in football simulation&amp;rdquo;. Sadly it would turn out to be one of the most infamously terrible games of the time, and was just a repackaging of an older title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 03:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/6/22/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Activision announced &amp;ldquo;Murder on the Missippi[sic]&amp;rdquo;, which was being written by Adam Bellin. Rather oddly C&amp;amp;VG described Bellin as &amp;ldquo;part of the team who produced the controversial &amp;lsquo;Ghostbusters&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;. I have no idea what the controversy was.
&amp;ldquo;Dr Blitzen and the Islands of Arcanum&amp;rdquo; would be the followup to the popular &amp;ldquo;Dynamite Dan&amp;rdquo;.
Alligata released &amp;ldquo;Who Dares Wins II&amp;rdquo;.
Colin McLinton won Firebird&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Elite&amp;rdquo; competition. There were 11 finalists, all of which had achieved Elite status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/5/25/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 01:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/5/25/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News Tony Crowther moved back Alligata, the company he started out with. He had briefly run his own software house called Wizard Developments.
After finding success with Delta4&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bored of the Rings&amp;rdquo; CRL had signed up the new St Brides spoof &amp;ldquo;The Very Big Cave Adventure&amp;rdquo;.
Little of the much hyped &amp;ldquo;Nexus&amp;rdquo; had been heard over the previous few months, but now it had resurfaced with news that Beyond would no longer be the publisher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 23:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/4/27/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News The UK release of &amp;ldquo;Questprobe 3&amp;rdquo; (aka &amp;ldquo;The Fantastic Four&amp;rdquo;) had suffered more delays. There had been hopes it&amp;rsquo;d be out for Christmas, but it looks like licensing issues had pushed it back.
Rhino announced &amp;ldquo;Ark Pandora&amp;rdquo; for the C64.
PSS had released two new wargames: &amp;ldquo;Falklands 82&amp;rdquo; for the Spectrum and &amp;ldquo;Theatre of Europe&amp;rdquo; for the Amstrad.
Global Software announced a game based on &amp;ldquo;the Worst Vegetable Movie of All Time&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The Attack of the Killer Tomatoes&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/3/18/this-month-in-cvg-86/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 06:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/3/18/this-month-in-cvg-86/</guid>
      <description>News The biggest news by far this month was that US Gold had merged with Ultimate Play The Game, and that US Gold would now handle all international manufacturing, promotion, marketing and sales of Ultimate games. Ultimate said that they were going to concentrate on making games and planned to release six new titles during 1986. What wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear was just how involved the Stamper brothers were to be, but it would turn out that they already had their eyes on the new Japanese consoles and the formation of a certain company called Rare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;86</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/1/5/mun4x70unjj1dh0jl2mlo3doj77olx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2014/1/5/mun4x70unjj1dh0jl2mlo3doj77olx/</guid>
      <description>News Dave Perry and Nick Jones had nearly wrapped up the latest Wally game for MikroGen - &amp;ldquo;Three Weeks in Paradise&amp;rdquo;.
Domark released a screenshot of their rather controversial &amp;ldquo;Friday the 13th&amp;rdquo;. The game certainly got the attention of the press but - unsurprisingly - for all the wrong reasons, as it turned out to be rubbish. (&amp;ldquo;Oh dear, oh dear&amp;rdquo; lamented Crash in their review).
A BBC conversion of Imagine&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Arcadia&amp;rdquo; called &amp;ldquo;Wet Zone&amp;rdquo; was to be distributed on the Micronet 800 dialup service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/12/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 21:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/12/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Ariolasoft released a couple of screenshots from a new game which promised to be a &amp;ldquo;totally interactive graphic adventure &amp;lsquo;movie&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; The game, &amp;ldquo;Wild West&amp;rdquo;, received luke warm reviews, but it was notable in that it was one of those rarities at the time: a game developed behind the iron curtain.
Activision were to take on EA&amp;rsquo;s excellent &amp;ldquo;Racing Destruction Set&amp;rdquo; with their own racing game with a built in editor called &amp;ldquo;Fast Tracks&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 04:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/11/24/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Elite announced &amp;ldquo;Scooby-Doo in the Castle Mystery&amp;rdquo;, teasing gamers with a couple of amazing looking screens. It promised to provide cartoon like quality graphics but the game then promptly disappeared, only to resurface some time later as a very good, but very different game developed for Elite by Gargoyle Games.
Christian Urqhart (programmer behind games like &amp;ldquo;Daley Thompson&amp;rsquo;s Decathlon&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Hunchback&amp;rdquo;) had left Ocean and formed his own company, Alphabatim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 23:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/10/20/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News After months of teasing, the new look for C&amp;amp;VG was here. It was quite a radical change and still looks pretty decent today.
The excellent &amp;ldquo;Bored of the Rings&amp;rdquo; was going to be re-launched by Silversoft and would feature new locations and graphics.
Beyond struck a deal with Mindscape that would see its games distributed in the the US. First up were &amp;ldquo;Lords of Midnight&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Shadowfire&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Quake Minus One&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 04:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/9/15/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News The Golden Sundial of Pi prize from &amp;ldquo;Pimania&amp;rdquo; was finally found! The winners - Sue Cooper and Lizi Newman - solved the puzzle by being at Hindover Hill in Sussex on July 22nd. The competition had begun on the release of &amp;ldquo;Pimania&amp;rdquo; in 1982.
British Telecom were about to open up public access to M.U.D. (multi-user dungeon), which had previously just been available to students and staff at Essex University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/13/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 08:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/8/13/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News US Gold had signed the licenses to a couple of Disney games, &amp;ldquo;Winnie the Pooh in the Hundred Acre Wood&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Donald Duck&amp;rsquo;s Playground&amp;rdquo;. Both were aimed at children, and both were written by Al Lowe (including the music).
Even though Ocean had been publishing Konami&amp;rsquo;s games in the US, they were strangely absent from UK shelves. This was about to change with &amp;ldquo;Hypersports&amp;rdquo;, followed by &amp;ldquo;Konami Tennis&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Yie Ar Kung-Fu&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Hyper Rally&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Golf&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Mikie&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Comic Bakery&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/7/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 06:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/7/8/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Plans were afoot to build Britain&amp;rsquo;s first Laser tag centre. It would be built on Wellington Pier in Great Yarmouth and promised to &amp;ldquo;take leisure and entertainment &amp;lsquo;into the 21st century.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;
Games Workshop was about to release &amp;ldquo;Chaos&amp;rdquo; by a certain Julian Gollop who would go onto produce such genre defining games as Rebelstar and XCom. He has a remake of &amp;ldquo;Chaos&amp;rdquo; underway and you can follow his progress on his blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/6/16/this-month-in-cvg-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 04:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/6/16/this-month-in-cvg-85/</guid>
      <description>News Atari announced they were about to launch a new range of computers. First there were the new XEs which were basically upgraded/re-styled 800 XLs. But more importantly were the STs which would provide an impressive jump from the existing machines. Robert Schifreen who had written the &amp;ldquo;Bug hunter&amp;rdquo; and Micronet columns for C&amp;amp;VG was arrested for hacking. Notable Reviews &amp;ldquo;Starion&amp;rdquo; Melbourne House - Spectrum Game of the Month 10/10 &amp;ldquo;Programmer David Webb, a 19-year old student, spent nine months working on Starion - and if there&amp;rsquo;s any justice in the world he will be rewarded with a number one hit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Month in... C&amp;VG &#39;85</title>
      <link>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/5/12/this-month-in-cvg-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikekeith.github.io/news/2013/5/12/this-month-in-cvg-/</guid>
      <description>News Not games related as such, but May saw the launch of C&amp;amp;VG&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bring Back the Doctor&amp;rdquo; campaign after the BBC announced Doctor Who was to end. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the BBC had specified when this was to happen, as it would last another 4 years.
The &amp;ldquo;Designer of the Month&amp;rdquo; was Stephen Redman, a 21 year old uni student who released the somewhat controversial (how innocent we all were) game &amp;ldquo;A Day in the Life&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
